<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>vinaya on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/vinaya/</link>
    <description>Recent content in vinaya on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/vinaya/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Memorizing The Bhikkhunī Pātimokkha</title>
      <link>/posts/memorizing-the-bhikkhuni-patimokkha/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/memorizing-the-bhikkhuni-patimokkha/</guid>
      <description>Palm leaf photo link wellcomecollection:[mfn]CC 4.0 iiif.wellcomecollection.org/image/L0031774/full/760%2C/0/default.jpg[/mfn]&#xA;Today I finished memorizing the Bhikkhunī Pātimokkha in Pāḷi (the 311 Theravāda nun&amp;rsquo;s rules). While I did not recite the whole lot in a single session, I did memorize in chunks until the total was completely memorized at one time or another. That means, I would recite a chunk of rules in front of a teacher by memory and then work on a separate adjacent succeeding chunk for memory.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theravāda Buddhist Monk Head Shaving: Traditions, Stories, and Techniques</title>
      <link>/posts/monks-shaving-techniques-traditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/monks-shaving-techniques-traditions/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to shaving heads, Theravāda Buddhist Monks might be the authority on this issue. It is second nature for monks to shave but perhaps unknown to the rest of the world. In this article, we will discuss the motivation, Buddhist culture and methods for shaving the head and how it is done.&#xA;Simplicity Inspires But Also Saves Money: For those of you in the layperson world (man or woman) who aspire to become monks but cannot plunge into a monastery just yet, you might want to try cutting your hair very short before shaving it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Monks Allowed To Perform Marriage Ceremonies?</title>
      <link>/posts/are-monks-allowed-to-perform-marriages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/are-monks-allowed-to-perform-marriages/</guid>
      <description>Although Buddhist lay people might be interested in having a monk perform their marriage ceremony, it is not allowed and doing so is classed as a heavy rule (Saṅghādisesa). Such heavy rules have penalties and require the monk to lose his full status for a minimum of 6 nights[mfn]mānatta[/mfn] and additional probation time if concealing the offense occurs.&#xA;Image was created by AI DALL-E by openai. All participants do not exist in real life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International Institute of Theravada</title>
      <link>/posts/international-institute-of-theravada/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/international-institute-of-theravada/</guid>
      <description>Multi purpose hall at IIT&#xA;After 3 years in Myanmar, I have moved to The International Institute of Theravāda. What is this place and why did I come here and what is mission?&#xA;What is IIT? The International Institute of Theravāda (IIT) is a comprehensive training institute aimed at facilitating spiritual and academic development of Buddhist monks, based on Theravada teachings. It is inclusive and accommodative, irrespective of sects (Nikaya) and other differences within the Theravada Buddhist clergy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Is The Bhikkhu Patimokkha or Buddhist Monk Rules?</title>
      <link>/posts/what-is-the-bhikkhu-patimokkha-or-buddhist-monk-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/what-is-the-bhikkhu-patimokkha-or-buddhist-monk-rules/</guid>
      <description>Pa Auk Monastery in 2014, Photo by Klaus&#xA;The Pātimokkha is a set of 227 rules for the bhikkhus belonging to the Theravāda sect which is based on the Pāḷi language texts. The 227 rules are grouped into seven classes with the first two, Pārājikā and Saṅghādisesā considered as &amp;ldquo;heavy&amp;rdquo;. The first heavy group is also considered irrecoverable while the second requires official transactions to restore the full bhikkhu status to the offender.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Buddhist Monks Allowed To Use Money?</title>
      <link>/posts/are-buddhist-monks-allowed-to-use-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/are-buddhist-monks-allowed-to-use-money/</guid>
      <description>A Money tree in Laos cc-by-attrib-sa https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Buddhist_money_tree_with_toilet_paper.jpg&#xA;Are Buddhist monks allowed to use money? The short answer is that monks are definitely not allowed to even touch money for all traditions; Theravāda, Mahayāna, and Tibetan. However, it is very common for monks to not only accept money from lay people without shame, but they even encourage lay people to offer the money. Nevertheless, it is still a rule and there are heavy consequences if this becomes a lifetime habit and a wrong mode of livelihood.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stay Away From the Fools and Associate with the Wise</title>
      <link>/posts/stay-away-from-the-fools-and-associate-with-the-wise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/stay-away-from-the-fools-and-associate-with-the-wise/</guid>
      <description>Sattigumba and Pupphaka&#xA;Asevanā ca bālānaṃ, paṇḍitānañca sevanā;&#xA;Pūjā ca pūjaneyyānaṃ etaṃ maṅgalamuttamaṃ.&#xA;Avoid the Fools and&#xA;Associate with the wise.&#xA;Give respect to the respectable.&#xA;This is the highest blessing.&#xA;Maṅgala Sutta&#xA;This small quote is from the first verse spoken by the Buddha when he was asked, &amp;ldquo;What is the highest blessing?&amp;rdquo; There are thirty-eight blessings listed and you can find them here. However, the first verse is the most important and we will only discuss the fools and the wise.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making Natural Brooms</title>
      <link>/posts/making-natural-brooms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/making-natural-brooms/</guid>
      <description>Sayadaw holding one of his finished brooms&#xA;Natural fiber brooms are quite common in Theravadan countries such as Myanmar, Thailand, Sri Lanka, Cambodia, and Laos. Since the plants that are used to make brooms grow in our monastery, one of our very senior monks takes pleasure in making brooms when he needs to stretch his legs after a long meditation. It is strange, but since our main job is to meditate, working can be a leisure activity!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patimokkha Chant Feb 15, 2022</title>
      <link>/posts/patimokkha-chant-feb-15-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/patimokkha-chant-feb-15-2022/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, I recited the 227 rules of the Pātimokkha for 110 bhikkhus at Pa-Auk Meditation Center in Pyin Oo Lwin. When a monk recites the Pātimokkha, traditionally he does so by memory and not by reading. My recitation was not the best quality, but it was not so bad considering I only started when I was 47, and I have only done this 5 times now. However, the recitations get better and better each time I do it and I hope improvement continues until perfection.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should Bhikkhunis Be Sent To Probation Monasteries?</title>
      <link>/posts/should-bhikkhunis-be-sent-to-probation-monasteries/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/should-bhikkhunis-be-sent-to-probation-monasteries/</guid>
      <description>Copyright notice.. picture by Kim Traynor cc-by-sa&#xA;Note: This post is not for everyone. Those who claim to be bhikkhunis and supporters of the movement, and monks and nuns in general will find this interesting.&#xA;Did you know that bhikkhunis (nuns) are not allowed to sleep alone or travel alone and if they do, they are sentenced to 2 weeks of rehabilitation and lose their full status as bhikkhunis during this period?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monk Towels and Soap</title>
      <link>/posts/soap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/soap/</guid>
      <description>Very few people from the West know about what the monks use for their bath towels and their bathing soap. Monks use items that are much different than those found in the West, although commonly known in Myanmar and other Buddhist countries. Furthermore, the monks use these items because of the monk rules associated with them in addition to the abundance and low cost.&#xA;Monks at Pa-Auk usually use small hand towels instead of normal &amp;ldquo;wrap-around&amp;rdquo; sized towels.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Does Rainy Season Start?</title>
      <link>/posts/when-does-rainy-season-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/when-does-rainy-season-start/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I got a nice message from a monk friend telling me he was taking vassa (3 month Rainy Season Retreat) on July 23rd (the Full Moon Day) and wishing me a happy vassa before he goes offline for three months. However, we at Pa-Auk are taking the vassa today on July 24 (the day after the Full Moon Day). The calendars often say it starts on the Full Moon Day, but we don&amp;rsquo;t do that at Pa-Auk.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Buddha&#39;s Intermittent Fasting</title>
      <link>/posts/the-buddhas-intermittent-fasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/the-buddhas-intermittent-fasting/</guid>
      <description>Did the Buddha do intermittent fasting? The answer is: Yes.&#xA;When I first became a monk, people were shocked about how I gave up eating after Solar Noon and I have not eaten dinner in over 20 years. Sometimes I switch to one meal per day, but I often find a light breakfast, mostly liquid foods or rice soup, with a full lunch works best for me. These days, many people are using intermittent fasting as a form of weight loss and when I describe my Buddhist monk diet, they give a nod and say &amp;ldquo;Intermittent Fasting&amp;hellip; It&amp;rsquo;s Healthy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chicago Lao Monastery</title>
      <link>/posts/chicago-lao-monastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/chicago-lao-monastery/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I had a chance to go to a Lao Monastery in Elgin, Chicago, IL, USA for 12 days. I usually avoid American Theravada Temples like the plague because most of these places have monks who use money and much of the monk life is centered around collecting money. This is a typical standard not only in America but in most countries. This monastery however, is different.&#xA;In 2015, the committee decided to stop being a useless, unwholesome temple that teaches wrong dhammavinaya (teaching and training &amp;mdash; on wrong ways to give donation and wrong ways to make merit, and obviously wrong kamma and results).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kauai Update: Lihue</title>
      <link>/posts/kauai-update-lihue/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/kauai-update-lihue/</guid>
      <description>All-focus&#xA;Things have recently changed&#xA;Things have recently changed in my life. I have now moved to Lihue. Things were going well at the place where I was at before in Kilauea. The owner was happy with what I was doing for the community and I was happy and fulfilled with what I was doing for the community as well. Unfortunately, the owner&amp;rsquo;s son came for a visit. In short, he said, &amp;ldquo;I want to visit a monk.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vinaya Comparison of Monastery Allowances</title>
      <link>/posts/vinaya-comparison-of-monastery-allowances/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/vinaya-comparison-of-monastery-allowances/</guid>
      <description>Below is a chart comparing special allowances by tradition which is useful for making a decision on where to ordain. If you need an explanation, read further..&#xA;There are some allowances and differences among traditions. I have included four traditions to the best of my knowledge about certain “allowances” that are allowed in some places and not allowed in other places. Who is right? Well, I believe that the two monasteries on the right (especially Wat Khao Sanamachai) are correct while other monks will believe that the monasteries on the left are correct.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Are Monk Bowls Black?</title>
      <link>/posts/why-are-monk-bowls-black/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/why-are-monk-bowls-black/</guid>
      <description>Monk bowls are black because they are fired with sesame oil 5 times to protect it from rusting. There are two types of bowls allowed; Iron and Clay. Iron bowls need to be fired 5 times and clay bowls only need firing twice. Obviously, the clay bowls do not need to be black in color but are rare to find because they are fragile and very very heavy. Iron bowls are black from the baked-on sesame oil.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buddhist Monks&#39; Robes Information</title>
      <link>/posts/buddhist-monks-robes-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/buddhist-monks-robes-information/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1367&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;708&amp;rdquo;] Sewing pattern from BMC 1 (creative-commons, Thanissaro Bhikkhu)[/caption]&#xA;Robe Information Few people realize that the Theravāda monk’s robes are actually a piece of rectangular cloth with no sleeves.[mfn]While some monks use shirts with sleeves underneath their robes, it is not actually allowed [/mfn] If you see a Theravāda monk wearing his robes in different styles, then rest assured it is due to the art of “tying the robes” or “rolling the robes” or what I call “robe origami.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kauai Update Part 2</title>
      <link>/posts/kauai-update-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/kauai-update-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Aloha!&#xA;It has been a little over a month since I have been on the island of Kauai. Things have been going well although my situation is still the same. I am still in a tent at Anini, but I have a new tent in Anini with a better view of the pristine Kauai shore! Things are dryer than the record rains we had last month.. and I guess if it were wetter than before a new record would be set.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should We Be Nice To Muslims?</title>
      <link>/posts/should-we-be-nice-to-muslims/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/should-we-be-nice-to-muslims/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1211&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;400&amp;rdquo;] Muslim Imam giving dana[/caption]&#xA;The short answer is, &amp;ldquo;Yes.&amp;rdquo; Of course we should be nice to Muslims, Christians, Atheist, animals, snakes and all beings. Sabbe Satta means all beings. In this long winded article, I speak about how the Muslims will win a majority in Myanmar and how Buddhism is already falling down in quality and quantity. Any &amp;ldquo;evil&amp;rdquo; actions like parochial schools, or large families were actually practiced in Myanmar by Buddhists only 20 or 30 years ago.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vegetarianism and Theravada Buddhism</title>
      <link>/posts/vegetarianism-theravada-buddhism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/vegetarianism-theravada-buddhism/</guid>
      <description>Vegetarianism and Theravada Buddhism I have been asked to write a little something on vegetarianism and Theravāda Buddhism. I am qualified to be quite objective, and to see both sides of the issue because I was a vegetarian for a total of ten years as a lay person and I had vegetarian eyes. That meant that when I looked at meat, cooked or not, I saw a dead animal in front of me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inspire Means To Leave Facebook</title>
      <link>/posts/inspire-means-leave-facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/inspire-means-leave-facebook/</guid>
      <description>Inspire Means To Leave Facebook Much of what I write about is related to stories that happen to me that would charge me up and make me feel inspired. I would then write down what happened and share it with others. Often my stories are related to vinaya – the monks’ rules and living without money. These days it is special for a monk to live without money and I can inspire people simply by following the rules.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Traveling Without a Helper</title>
      <link>/posts/traveling-without-helper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/traveling-without-helper/</guid>
      <description>When Ven. Devananda and I traveled to Kauai in 2015, we did not have a Kappiya (helper) to buy us food or even pay for our luggage. One can live without helpers, but it does take some pre-planning.&#xA;We had a ticket from Yangon to Honolulu that was dirt cheap at only $854 for a round trip fare. However, it came with 12 hour and 6 hour layovers in China.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Finally Did It!</title>
      <link>/posts/i-finally-did-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/i-finally-did-it/</guid>
      <description>I Finally Did It! This Rainy Season (Vassa) I was able to learn the Pātimokkha (227 Rules) by heart. It is the first round and it takes me a long time to do it, and there are mistakes. Never the less, it is considered “learned” and “memorized” at this stage. I will hopefully recite the Pātimokkha for the full moon November 3rd if all goes well. I need to get my 2+ hours of recitation down to at least 1:15 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donation to Sangha or Individuals?</title>
      <link>/posts/donation-sangha-individuals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/donation-sangha-individuals/</guid>
      <description>When should you give to Saṅgha?&#xA;When should you give to individual monks?&#xA;This is a question that is not addressed very often and it can cause lots of trouble for monks knowingly and unknowingly. Quite often, many monks blindly prompt donors to recite a line of pāḷi before they offer anything to them. “Bhikkhu Saṅghassa demi.” There are some variations, but that is the generic formula. It means, “I give to the community of monks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Are Most Monasteries Not Allowable?</title>
      <link>/posts/why-monasteries-not-allowable/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/why-monasteries-not-allowable/</guid>
      <description>Why are most monasteries not allowable for vinaya monks? Today, I was Skyping my parents which is something we do once or twice a month now. I feel it is good for them to &amp;ldquo;see&amp;rdquo; me as a monk, rather than having them talk to me and visualizing their son from 1999. That was when I left home and things changed for me. We had a nice discussion. We spoke about possibilities for a visit, but I told them that finding a place was difficult, because the monks all use money and whatever they buy with that money becomes unallowable.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shining The Inner Core</title>
      <link>/posts/shining-the-inner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/shining-the-inner/</guid>
      <description>To receive this by email, sign up at https://subhuti.withmetta.net/subscribe/&#xA;Last year, this picture (without the writing) went viral. The viral post seems to makes its rounds from time to time and every so often, someone tells me they saw my picture. It started when I was in Bagan for an 8 day trip with my friend Ashin Pannyagavesaka. We did a slow and thorough excursion and walked a good chunk of Bagan when rides were not provided.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inspiration, move me brightly</title>
      <link>/posts/inspiration-move-brightly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/inspiration-move-brightly/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_966&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;2048&amp;rdquo;] Alms[/caption]&#xA;Inspiration is like a bright star that shines among the dim. In Monastic life, there are few monasteries or monks that really inspire people. Following the vinaya (or rules) inspires people. It is tried and tested.&#xA;This was an old picture when I was in a vinaya monastery that follows all of the rules including the &amp;ldquo;basic ten rules&amp;rdquo; that a 7 year old beginner monk is supposed to follow.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5, 8 and 10 Precepts</title>
      <link>/posts/5-8-10-precepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/5-8-10-precepts/</guid>
      <description>Here is a comparison of 5, 8 and 10 precepts. The Buddhist who follows five precepts is known as a regular lay Buddhist. The person who follows 8 precepts is known as a serious Buddhist yogi. The person who follows the 10 precepts is known as a novice monk. A bhikkhu follows 227 rules.&#xA;It is important to know these classes to know which rules are more important to follow. It also can explain, what class of rules a monk is following.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buddhism and Abortion</title>
      <link>/posts/buddhism-and-abortion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/buddhism-and-abortion/</guid>
      <description>What do Theravada Buddhists believe in terms of abortion? Much of what has been written are liberal beliefs and overturning what is written down in the texts. They claim “Modern Buddhism” as a section heading, but there is no such thing as “Modern Buddhism” since there is no such thing as “Modern Kamma.” The rules of kamma do not change over time, and abortion has been around since the time of the Buddha.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visit to Varanasi Monastery, Mingaladon</title>
      <link>/posts/visit-varanasi-monastery-mingaladon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/visit-varanasi-monastery-mingaladon/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_786&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;764&amp;rdquo;] Sima of Varanasi Monastery[/caption]&#xA;A Brief Visit to Varanasi Monastery, Mingaladon&#xA;I had a few more days before I was allowed to arrive at ITBM University (I am there now). Very close by is one of my favorite monasteries in the Yangon District. Actually, there are very few choices for monks who follow the monk’s rules (Vinaya) if you want to live with like minded vinaya monks.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
