<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>basic on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/basic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in basic on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/basic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Basic Pali Terms for Dhamma</title>
      <link>/posts/basic-pali-terms-for-dhamma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/basic-pali-terms-for-dhamma/</guid>
      <description>Burmese Pāḷi&#xA;I have made a list of the most basic Pāḷi terms which will help you in your Theravāda Buddhist Readings and listening to Dhamma Talks. I could have added more, but there are already 165+ terms. I have decided to sort the words in alphabetical order so I would not have to decide which were the most important. Grouping the words would have also given me the same dilemma.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Most Basic Pali Chants to Learn</title>
      <link>/posts/the-most-basic-pali-chants-to-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/the-most-basic-pali-chants-to-learn/</guid>
      <description>Myanmar Pali Script (credit at bottom link.. cc-sa-attrib)&#xA;There are many different Pāḷi chants to learn, yet I wanted to list the absolute basic chants that one should learn. If you are interested in Pāḷi chanting, these are the first to learn. The most basic and essential chants for beginning lay people should know are listed in order of importance:&#xA;Namo Tassa, Triple Gem with the 5 precepts, Bare bones Triple Gem chant of the 24 qualities of the Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
