<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>concept on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/concept/</link>
    <description>Recent content in concept on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/concept/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ajahn Brahmavamso&#39;s Dark Jhāna</title>
      <link>/posts/ajahn-brahmavamsos-dark-jhana/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/ajahn-brahmavamsos-dark-jhana/</guid>
      <description>Does Ajahn Brahmavamso Jhāna Have a Nimitta? Ajahn Brahmavamso (&amp;ldquo;Ajahn Brahm&amp;rdquo;) teaches about a samādhi nimitta. However, during jhāna, he says that there is no perception of light. He says that &amp;ldquo;The nimitta is the gateway to jhāna, but not the object of jhāna itself. Pīti or sukha are the objects of jhāna&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;If you follow Ajahn Brahm, this article will help you follow his teachings better. If you follow another method, this article will help you distinguish the difference.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Concept in Breath Meditation</title>
      <link>/posts/concept-meditation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/concept-meditation/</guid>
      <description>The Concept in Breath Meditation The concept of the breath as it is used in meditation is not well understood. We will discuss this matter in this small article. There are many methods concerned with the breath, but The Ancient Theravāda Commentaries say that one should focus at one area above the upper lip and at the exit of the nostrils. However, if one just limited himself to that one single method, things can still get complicated.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
