<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>patimokkha on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/patimokkha/</link>
    <description>Recent content in patimokkha on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/patimokkha/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Memorizing The Bhikkhunī Pātimokkha</title>
      <link>/posts/memorizing-the-bhikkhuni-patimokkha/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/memorizing-the-bhikkhuni-patimokkha/</guid>
      <description>Palm leaf photo link wellcomecollection:[mfn]CC 4.0 iiif.wellcomecollection.org/image/L0031774/full/760%2C/0/default.jpg[/mfn]&#xA;Today I finished memorizing the Bhikkhunī Pātimokkha in Pāḷi (the 311 Theravāda nun&amp;rsquo;s rules). While I did not recite the whole lot in a single session, I did memorize in chunks until the total was completely memorized at one time or another. That means, I would recite a chunk of rules in front of a teacher by memory and then work on a separate adjacent succeeding chunk for memory.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Is The Bhikkhu Patimokkha or Buddhist Monk Rules?</title>
      <link>/posts/what-is-the-bhikkhu-patimokkha-or-buddhist-monk-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/what-is-the-bhikkhu-patimokkha-or-buddhist-monk-rules/</guid>
      <description>Pa Auk Monastery in 2014, Photo by Klaus&#xA;The Pātimokkha is a set of 227 rules for the bhikkhus belonging to the Theravāda sect which is based on the Pāḷi language texts. The 227 rules are grouped into seven classes with the first two, Pārājikā and Saṅghādisesā considered as &amp;ldquo;heavy&amp;rdquo;. The first heavy group is also considered irrecoverable while the second requires official transactions to restore the full bhikkhu status to the offender.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Buddhist Monks Allowed To Use Money?</title>
      <link>/posts/are-buddhist-monks-allowed-to-use-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/are-buddhist-monks-allowed-to-use-money/</guid>
      <description>A Money tree in Laos cc-by-attrib-sa https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Buddhist_money_tree_with_toilet_paper.jpg&#xA;Are Buddhist monks allowed to use money? The short answer is that monks are definitely not allowed to even touch money for all traditions; Theravāda, Mahayāna, and Tibetan. However, it is very common for monks to not only accept money from lay people without shame, but they even encourage lay people to offer the money. Nevertheless, it is still a rule and there are heavy consequences if this becomes a lifetime habit and a wrong mode of livelihood.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patimokkha Chant Feb 15, 2022</title>
      <link>/posts/patimokkha-chant-feb-15-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/patimokkha-chant-feb-15-2022/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, I recited the 227 rules of the Pātimokkha for 110 bhikkhus at Pa-Auk Meditation Center in Pyin Oo Lwin. When a monk recites the Pātimokkha, traditionally he does so by memory and not by reading. My recitation was not the best quality, but it was not so bad considering I only started when I was 47, and I have only done this 5 times now. However, the recitations get better and better each time I do it and I hope improvement continues until perfection.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How To Memorize Pāḷi by Rote Method</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-memorize-pa%E1%B8%B7i-by-rote-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/how-to-memorize-pa%E1%B8%B7i-by-rote-method/</guid>
      <description>Title Page&#xA;In America, the Rote Method of learning is belittled as &amp;ldquo;learning like a parrot&amp;rdquo; and rarely or never taught in the Western school systems. However, it is a useful brute force method for memorizing Pali texts and the only way to memorize longer word for word Pāḷi texts such as the Pātimokkha. This system is used extensively in Myanmar schools and Myanmar study monasteries. If you hear lots of noise in the classrooms, rote learning is what they are doing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Finally Did It!</title>
      <link>/posts/i-finally-did-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/i-finally-did-it/</guid>
      <description>I Finally Did It! This Rainy Season (Vassa) I was able to learn the Pātimokkha (227 Rules) by heart. It is the first round and it takes me a long time to do it, and there are mistakes. Never the less, it is considered “learned” and “memorized” at this stage. I will hopefully recite the Pātimokkha for the full moon November 3rd if all goes well. I need to get my 2+ hours of recitation down to at least 1:15 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lucky-Draw and Devas</title>
      <link>/posts/lucky-draw-devas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/lucky-draw-devas/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_902&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;948&amp;rdquo;] Calculation of odds.[/caption]&#xA;Do you believe in devas?&#xA;Devas are the Buddhist equivalent to angels. Ok .. Here is the story. I was on alms round two weeks ago and a regular supporter invited us to ask for anything for our studies at school. I needed some pens, so I asked for some pens. He told me to wait and showed up with a huge pen gift-box.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
