<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rainy-season on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/rainy-season/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rainy-season on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/rainy-season/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Umbrella Shop 2004-2014</title>
      <link>/posts/umbrella-shop-2004-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/umbrella-shop-2004-2015/</guid>
      <description>Monks walking up the monastery road near the library 2014. (Double umbrella)&#xA;Excerpt from Going For Broke: Monasterynote5: Walkman Karaoke, 2004&#xA;Rainy Season is luckily my favorite and I love all five months of it. It is the perfect temperature also, not too hot, not too cold. It&amp;rsquo;s quiet and the noises around me get white washed out from the rain striking the metal corrugated roofing. We had over 350 Bhikkhus and a total of more than 600 residents this past Rainy Season (2004).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Does Rainy Season Start?</title>
      <link>/posts/when-does-rainy-season-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/when-does-rainy-season-start/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I got a nice message from a monk friend telling me he was taking vassa (3 month Rainy Season Retreat) on July 23rd (the Full Moon Day) and wishing me a happy vassa before he goes offline for three months. However, we at Pa-Auk are taking the vassa today on July 24 (the day after the Full Moon Day). The calendars often say it starts on the Full Moon Day, but we don&amp;rsquo;t do that at Pa-Auk.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Is Vassa (Rainy Season) Late Sometimes?</title>
      <link>/posts/why-is-vassa-rainy-season-late-sometimes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/why-is-vassa-rainy-season-late-sometimes/</guid>
      <description>Please note: this was written in 2020 but also applies to 2023. Vassa starts on August 1, 2023.&#xA;There seems to be confusion about when vassa is this year. This year is a special year and Vassa starts the day after the full moon day in August. The full moon day is August 3rd and Vassa starts on August 4th.&#xA;However, there are some traditions that believe that Vassa has already started with the full moon day of July 4th and Vassa on July 5th.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
