<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>monk on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/monk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in monk on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/monk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Monastery Murder Massacre</title>
      <link>/posts/monastery-murder-massacre/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/monastery-murder-massacre/</guid>
      <description>Artistic digital recreation of Migalaṇḍika (an ascetic who looked like a monk)&#xA;The Monastery Murder Massacre that happened in Vesālī during the time of The Buddha is not well known among lay people. It was because of this massacre that The Buddha made a rule about killing humans. For the first 20 years, there were no rules and this was the third rule that was ever created. Before this, the monks intuitively knew what was proper and there was no need for rules.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Monks Get Married?</title>
      <link>/posts/can-monks-marry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/can-monks-marry/</guid>
      <description>cc0 picture&#xA;Recently, there have been some instances in the news of monks who have been accused of rape or consensual sex. One monk appears to have supported a child with his money. While we won&amp;rsquo;t know the true outcome until an admission of guilt is made, we should investigate what is a rule and what is not a rule. Although it is appalling that the Catholic church allows its priests to continue in the order even after such admissions of guilt for sexual acts, the Buddhist rules across all Buddhist schools have a different approach.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As Long As You Stand On The Road</title>
      <link>/posts/stand-on-the-road/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/stand-on-the-road/</guid>
      <description>That is me going for alms on Aalona Street Kilauea.&#xA;I have a Christmas story for you. I have tried to keep it short but it didn&amp;rsquo;t work out.&#xA;When I was in Kaua&amp;rsquo;i on from 2017-2019, an 18 month run, I made it a point to go for alms by the house to house loving-kindness method on Tuesdays and Wednesdays as a way to get food. Early on, I was invited to Waiapua Road while standing in front of Hanalei Big Save which was my Monday stop.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ian (exVen. Visarada) Visits Kauai</title>
      <link>/posts/ian-pka-visarada-visits-kauai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/ian-pka-visarada-visits-kauai/</guid>
      <description>This past July, I had an old friend named Ian Sloan (previously Venerable Visarada ) visit me in Kauai. He disrobed after being a monk for 25 years. He disrobed because of a conflict of philosophy about what happens at death. It was a combination of accounts from past life regressions in hypnotherapy, what he has read by Edgar Cayce, and the event of his father&amp;rsquo;s death. He seems to appreciate the Near Death Experiences which can still be explained partially with Buddhism, but he felt it was time to disrobe.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fighting Anger With Loving-Kindness and No Money</title>
      <link>/posts/fighting-anger-with-loving-kindness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/fighting-anger-with-loving-kindness/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I ran into a very angry man who came out of his house yelling at me and coming closer and closer. Eventually, I won the fight with my two big weapons, loving-kindness and my commitment of being free from money for all these years. I have been going for alms in this neighborhood for a little over a year now, and while I did have two girls yell at me, they did not leave their property boundary.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Koral Inspires Me</title>
      <link>/posts/koral-inspires-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/koral-inspires-me/</guid>
      <description>Koral&amp;rsquo;s Family&#xA;Just about every Wednesday, I still find the time to continue with my Kilauea alms round[mfn]map is here[/mfn] (which used to include Tuesdays too). I take a one hour bus ride from Lihue, and then set out on my alms round, wishing loving-kindness to the houses one by one as I walk along the road.&#xA;In the beginning people thought I was some weird homeless person who might be crazy, but after some time, some fearless people spoke to me and then word started spreading.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18th Anniversary and Update</title>
      <link>/posts/18th-anniversary-and-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/18th-anniversary-and-update/</guid>
      <description>This is where I live&#xA;Wow! Today is February 7th and another year has passed. I have now completed 18 years total as a monk and I am working on my 19th year. Of course, my monk age is 12 rainy seasons because I changed Nikayas after my 6th year. I have been living my monk life in Kauai, Hawaii for about 10 months now and things have been moving along.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kauai Monk Update 3</title>
      <link>/posts/kauai-update-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/kauai-update-3/</guid>
      <description>Kauai Update #3&#xA;I have moved from the Botanical Gardens recently. I was able to stay there for 5 months and the majority of the time there was wonderful. However things were changing and it was time for me to look for another place and now I am staying in a new long term location in Kilauea.&#xA;It all happened after a wonderful person picked me up on the side of the road holding my signs the day my parents, brother and in-law dropped me off (I’ll get back to that family-visit part later).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
