<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>facebook on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/facebook/</link>
    <description>Recent content in facebook on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/facebook/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What is an Overturned Bowl?</title>
      <link>/posts/what-is-an-overturned-bowl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/what-is-an-overturned-bowl/</guid>
      <description>Pa-Auk Bowl Blackening Foundry (not a political picture)&#xA;We have seen many Facebook selfies of politically active monks with their bowls turned upside down. What does this mean and is that proper?&#xA;The answer is: What you see on Facebook is not proper for monks or nuns. What you see on the news with monks and nuns as protesters is not proper. Overturning a bowl is an official Buddhist act, but what you have seen on Facebook and on the news are not official acts of overturning a bowl.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inspire Means To Leave Facebook</title>
      <link>/posts/inspire-means-leave-facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/inspire-means-leave-facebook/</guid>
      <description>Inspire Means To Leave Facebook Much of what I write about is related to stories that happen to me that would charge me up and make me feel inspired. I would then write down what happened and share it with others. Often my stories are related to vinaya – the monks’ rules and living without money. These days it is special for a monk to live without money and I can inspire people simply by following the rules.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
