<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>teaching on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/categories/teaching/</link>
    <description>Recent content in teaching on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/categories/teaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Planting Wisdom: Reflections on the Cūḷakammavibhaṅga Sutta and a Meditation Journey</title>
      <link>/posts/planting-wisdom-reflections-on-the-cu%E1%B8%B7akammavibha%E1%B9%85ga-sutta-and-a-meditation-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/planting-wisdom-reflections-on-the-cu%E1%B8%B7akammavibha%E1%B9%85ga-sutta-and-a-meditation-journey/</guid>
      <description>In this talk, I explore the Cūḷakammavibhaṅga Sutta and share the story of reconnecting with my first meditation teacher after nearly two decades. The focus is on the seeds of kamma that we plant continuously through our actions. What kind of seeds are we planting right now?&#xA;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Iq7LED3zIJo&#xA;The Seeds From Long Ago The Seeds From Long Ago I remember when I first learned how to meditate on my breath some time in 1990, during my university years.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three Stories Of Loving-kindness</title>
      <link>/posts/three-stories-of-loving-kindness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/three-stories-of-loving-kindness/</guid>
      <description>There are three stories of loving-kindness told in the video posted below. The first story is from Kaua&amp;rsquo;i, Hawai&amp;rsquo;i, when a person did not want me on &amp;ldquo;his&amp;rdquo; street. Through the power of loving-kindness, things changed. Another story was also from the island in 2015. There were children on bicycles who were yelling at us to go away on multiple days. Through the power of loving-kindness, things changed. The last story is from 2011 during a trip to India.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Does Namo Tassa Bhagavato Arahato Sammāsambuddhassa Mean?</title>
      <link>/posts/what-does-namo-tassa-bhagavato-arahato-sammasambuddhassa-mean/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/what-does-namo-tassa-bhagavato-arahato-sammasambuddhassa-mean/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: Today we will have a short and brief introduction into the meaning of &amp;ldquo;Namo Tassa Bhagavato Arahato Sammāsambuddhassa&amp;rdquo;. We could easily say it is the most frequently chanted stanza of all Buddhist Pāḷi because this is said before any other type of chant. It is also chanted before every proper Theravāda dhamma talk. We will discuss the word by word meaning and the basic grammar. In short, the phrase means &amp;ldquo;Reverence to the Buddha.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How The Buddha&#39;s Teachings Saved Japan</title>
      <link>/posts/how-the-buddhas-teachings-saved-japan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/how-the-buddhas-teachings-saved-japan/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: There was a moment in world history where the Buddha&amp;rsquo;s teachings greatly affected world diplomacy during the Peace Treaty of 1951. We can learn from this type of history and apply the solution in our daily lives. In short, we can stop hatred with loving-kindness.&#xA;President J.R. Jayewardene of Sri Lanka exits from a helicopter and walks to his airplane for departure after a state visit.&#xA;If you look at the history of the San Francisco Treaty of 1951, you will see that it officially negotiated the end of the war crimes with Japan from WWII.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Most Common Dhammapāda Chants</title>
      <link>/posts/the-most-common-dhammapada-chants/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/the-most-common-dhammapada-chants/</guid>
      <description>CC BY-SA 2.5, https://commons.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?curid=190448&#xA;The most popular Buddhist book is the Dhammapada which contains 423 poetic verses in the Pāḷi language. What are the most popular verses? While there are some classic chants and everyone has favorites, nothing compares to what the monks chant and what is found in most chanting books. Here are the chants that are integrated into many different traditions and usually chanted after the pātimokkha.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Order of Monks: How Seniority Shapes the Buddhist Monastic Life</title>
      <link>/posts/the-order-of-monks-how-seniority-shapes-the-buddhist-monastic-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/the-order-of-monks-how-seniority-shapes-the-buddhist-monastic-life/</guid>
      <description>monks seated for the patimokkha recitation in Pa-Auk Mawlamyine&#xA;Introduction One of the things that you may notice when you visit a Buddhist monastery is that the monks sit, eat, walk, and pay respect to each other in a certain order. This order is based on the principle of seniority, which is determined by the date of ordination, not by age, education, or social status. Whoever is ordained earlier is considered senior, and whoever is ordained later is considered junior.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buddhism and Lists</title>
      <link>/posts/buddhism-and-lists/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/buddhism-and-lists/</guid>
      <description>Buddha by Numbers&#xA;Introduction The Buddhist teachings are often organized by various lists. Various matrices of interlinked lists to organize the teachings are one of the distinctive features of Buddhism. In my studies, I find myself learning many different types of lists for memory. By doing so, I can see the benefit and how they can be expanded and interlinked. While it may seem like dry minutia and uninteresting at first glance, the lists run very deep when you start to understand how the whole system works.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is Theravada Buddhism?</title>
      <link>/posts/what-is-theravada-buddhism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/what-is-theravada-buddhism/</guid>
      <description>Monk at The Bodhi Tree located at International Institute of Theravāda&#xA;Theravada (Theravāda) is one of the major branches of Buddhism and is often referred to as the &amp;ldquo;School of the Elders.&amp;rdquo; It is the oldest surviving Buddhist school and it is the predominant religion of Sri Lanka, Myanmar, Thailand, Laos, and Cambodia. Because of its age and orthodoxy, it can also be loosely translated as &amp;ldquo;Old School Buddhism&amp;rdquo; in some ways too.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Piṇḍapāta:  Why Do Monks Go For Alms in a Village?</title>
      <link>/posts/why-go-for-alms-in-a-village-while-they-are-still-recovering-economic-crisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/why-go-for-alms-in-a-village-while-they-are-still-recovering-economic-crisis/</guid>
      <description>Alms Tray and Cambodia Monk&amp;rsquo;s Full Bowl&#xA;Introduction: This article explains the essence of piṇḍapāta (alms) and why we go for alms, even in poor villages. On the weekends, I have some time to go for alms in the nearby village. However, you might ask yourself, &amp;ldquo;Why would a monk collect food from a very poor village during an economic crisis when the monastery is mostly supported by wealthy people?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What does AI think of Loving-Kindness?  Here is a poem.</title>
      <link>/posts/ai-poem-on-loving-kindness/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/ai-poem-on-loving-kindness/</guid>
      <description>ai generated art for this post&#xA;I asked openai chatGPT to write a buddhist poem on loving-kindness in the style of Dr. Seuss. This is what I got.&#xA;With open hearts and open hands,&#xA;We spread loving-kindness across the lands.&#xA;Like ripples on a pond, it starts with one,&#xA;But soon it touches everyone.&#xA;With each kind word and thoughtful deed,&#xA;We plant the seeds of love, in hearts to breed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Is Halloween Bad According To Theravada Buddhism?</title>
      <link>/posts/why-is-halloween-bad-according-to-theravada-buddhism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/why-is-halloween-bad-according-to-theravada-buddhism/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: While I&amp;rsquo;m sure most religions do not particularly like the tradition of Halloween, I thought it would be good to explain why Halloween is not good according to Theravāda Buddhism.&#xA;Celebrating Halloween in modern times, regardless of the reasons why it was started in the first place, consists of dressing up in costumes. In celebration, you either dress up or you praise other people&amp;rsquo;s costumes. It is mostly bad karma for the one dressing up and if you praise that, it is not good either.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How To Be Human and Higher</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-be-human-and-higher/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/how-to-be-human-and-higher/</guid>
      <description>Sunrise behind clouds, free public domain CC0 image.&#xA;Many people want to go to Heaven or at least be born in human worlds but most people do not know what is needed to go there, let alone how to achieve enlightenment. Previously, in a previous article, I explained what happens after death according to the Theravāda teachings. If you have not read it, you really should. It explains the five causes for the five effects to arise (rebirth).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buddhism:  What Happens After Death?</title>
      <link>/posts/buddhism-what-happens-after-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/buddhism-what-happens-after-death/</guid>
      <description>https://unsplash.com/photos/j3R9C-Xqe1w&#xA;Warning: This is a long but clear and interesting religious post on what happens after death according to Classical Theravāda Buddhism.&#xA;Key Points: The Fully Enlightened do not take a rebirth after death. Immediate rebirth takes place after the death moment for all other beings. Kamma is what determines your next birth Lifetime and Momentary suffering Be careful what you wish for There is no such thing as a guaranteed intermediate stage (Bardo Plane).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Only The Best For Buddha</title>
      <link>/posts/only-the-best-for-buddha/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/only-the-best-for-buddha/</guid>
      <description>6 Color Buddhist Flag&#xA;Yesterday, on Vesak, I was invited to go with Sayadaw Kumarabhivamsa, the Tipitaka Sayadaw and one more monk to visit the three very large Buddhas in our monastery and then finally to give water to the Bodhi Tree. When we give water to the Bodhi Tree, it is not uncommon to give pure bottled drinking water to it. Yes, you read that correctly.&#xA;Bottled drinking water is used to water a tree.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stay Away From the Fools and Associate with the Wise</title>
      <link>/posts/stay-away-from-the-fools-and-associate-with-the-wise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/stay-away-from-the-fools-and-associate-with-the-wise/</guid>
      <description>Sattigumba and Pupphaka&#xA;Asevanā ca bālānaṃ, paṇḍitānañca sevanā;&#xA;Pūjā ca pūjaneyyānaṃ etaṃ maṅgalamuttamaṃ.&#xA;Avoid the Fools and&#xA;Associate with the wise.&#xA;Give respect to the respectable.&#xA;This is the highest blessing.&#xA;Maṅgala Sutta&#xA;This small quote is from the first verse spoken by the Buddha when he was asked, &amp;ldquo;What is the highest blessing?&amp;rdquo; There are thirty-eight blessings listed and you can find them here. However, the first verse is the most important and we will only discuss the fools and the wise.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Happy Boxing Day</title>
      <link>/posts/happy-boxing-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/happy-boxing-day/</guid>
      <description>Robin Hutton cc-nc-sa https://www.flickr.com/photos/robinhutton/35838229270&#xA;What to do when someone &amp;ldquo;gives&amp;rdquo; anger? Today, December 26th is Boxing Day. It is on this day when people give gifts to the poor, perhaps the gifts you received on Christmas but did not want to keep. It is also a day to give money or boxes to employees. Happy Boxing Day!&#xA;The Buddha has spoken about not accepting gifts in his famous sutta in regard to those who give &amp;ldquo;anger&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Only In The West, Only In Asia</title>
      <link>/posts/only-in-the-west-only-in-asia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/only-in-the-west-only-in-asia/</guid>
      <description>Only In The West, Only In Asia&#xA;Different Cultures, Different Views Many Westerners don’t understand or appreciate the old Buddhist texts or teachings. They are very different from Asian culture and history. They find it hard to relate to them.&#xA;Let me give you an example. This is a picture and story of a bidet (a device that sprays water to clean your private parts after using the toilet).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Did The Buddha Know Einstein&#39;s Theory?</title>
      <link>/posts/did-the-buddha-know-einsteins-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/did-the-buddha-know-einsteins-theory/</guid>
      <description>Einstein formula on blackboard see this link for attribution&#xA;The Mass–energy equivalence is one of the most famous physics equations known to the general population. Did the Buddha know this beforehand? We all know this formula as the explanation for how nuclear energy works, but we really don&amp;rsquo; t know much more than that.&#xA;For my one of my birthdays, I asked a monk who was once a nuclear engineer from Chernobyl to explain to me how it works.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Most Basic Pali Chants to Learn</title>
      <link>/posts/the-most-basic-pali-chants-to-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/the-most-basic-pali-chants-to-learn/</guid>
      <description>Myanmar Pali Script (credit at bottom link.. cc-sa-attrib)&#xA;There are many different Pāḷi chants to learn, yet I wanted to list the absolute basic chants that one should learn. If you are interested in Pāḷi chanting, these are the first to learn. The most basic and essential chants for beginning lay people should know are listed in order of importance:&#xA;Namo Tassa, Triple Gem with the 5 precepts, Bare bones Triple Gem chant of the 24 qualities of the Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Monks Get Married?</title>
      <link>/posts/can-monks-marry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/can-monks-marry/</guid>
      <description>cc0 picture&#xA;Recently, there have been some instances in the news of monks who have been accused of rape or consensual sex. One monk appears to have supported a child with his money. While we won&amp;rsquo;t know the true outcome until an admission of guilt is made, we should investigate what is a rule and what is not a rule. Although it is appalling that the Catholic church allows its priests to continue in the order even after such admissions of guilt for sexual acts, the Buddhist rules across all Buddhist schools have a different approach.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Do Monasteries Have Skeletons?</title>
      <link>/posts/why-do-monasteries-have-skeletons/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/why-do-monasteries-have-skeletons/</guid>
      <description>If you go to a Theravada Buddhist forest monastery in Asia, you are likely to find a full skeleton or parts of a skeleton somewhere where it can be viewed easily. Some monasteries also have cemeteries inside the boundary like Pa-Auk Forest Monastery in Mawlamyine. Some other monasteries have a place were dead bodies are burned (with open wood fires), right on the premises, like Pa-Auk Mawlamyine and also Wat Pa Nanachat in Thailand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Buddhist Monk&#39;s Prayers For The Old And Sick</title>
      <link>/posts/buddhist-prayers-for-old-and-sick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/buddhist-prayers-for-old-and-sick/</guid>
      <description>India 2011&#xA;Can Buddhist Monks Pray For The Old And Sick?&#xA;Recently, a life long friend of the family has been diagnosed with lung cancer, a tough break because she is not a smoker. My mother asked me if I could say a prayer for her. I can, and have, but there was more to say about what I could do for her.&#xA;When I chant the Loving-kindness sutta for someone in person as a “blessing”, I usually explain what it means beforehand and then I chant it for them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Real Buddha Statues</title>
      <link>/posts/the-real-buddha-statues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/the-real-buddha-statues/</guid>
      <description>What qualities make up the real Buddha Statues? There are certain qualities of a Buddha that makes one instantly recognizable from afar. There are many features that make the Buddha a Buddha besides the iconic drooping earlobes. From time to time, I see statues of the Buddha that are just not right. When you know the correct signs of The Buddha, you immediately know that something is wrong. While you cannot fool a Sri Lankan, you can fool others from all parts of the world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ajahn Brahmavamso&#39;s Dark Jhāna</title>
      <link>/posts/ajahn-brahmavamsos-dark-jhana/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/ajahn-brahmavamsos-dark-jhana/</guid>
      <description>Does Ajahn Brahmavamso Jhāna Have a Nimitta? Ajahn Brahmavamso (&amp;ldquo;Ajahn Brahm&amp;rdquo;) teaches about a samādhi nimitta. However, during jhāna, he says that there is no perception of light. He says that &amp;ldquo;The nimitta is the gateway to jhāna, but not the object of jhāna itself. Pīti or sukha are the objects of jhāna&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;If you follow Ajahn Brahm, this article will help you follow his teachings better. If you follow another method, this article will help you distinguish the difference.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Walking Meditation Inside The Home</title>
      <link>/posts/walking-meditation-inside-the-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/walking-meditation-inside-the-home/</guid>
      <description>There are many people who are inside their homes, so I thought it would be good to make a small 10 minute video on how to do basic walking meditation inside the home. Here it is.&#xA;https://youtu.be/e1MCuTxcf7A</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Free PTS Sutta eBooks</title>
      <link>/posts/free-pts-sutta-ebooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/free-pts-sutta-ebooks/</guid>
      <description>The Pali Text Society has made its Vinaya, Sutta and Abhidhamma books available for non-commercial use since 2013. The Sutta books have been extracted from the Buddhadust Website which is still considered as &amp;ldquo;work in progress.&amp;rdquo; However, the work was good enough to reformat as eBooks in its current state.&#xA;Stephen Torrence and myself did most of the work to reformat the web pages into eBook versions. There were thousands of webpages which required many scripts to remove the web content.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chicago Lao Monastery</title>
      <link>/posts/chicago-lao-monastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/chicago-lao-monastery/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I had a chance to go to a Lao Monastery in Elgin, Chicago, IL, USA for 12 days. I usually avoid American Theravada Temples like the plague because most of these places have monks who use money and much of the monk life is centered around collecting money. This is a typical standard not only in America but in most countries. This monastery however, is different.&#xA;In 2015, the committee decided to stop being a useless, unwholesome temple that teaches wrong dhammavinaya (teaching and training &amp;mdash; on wrong ways to give donation and wrong ways to make merit, and obviously wrong kamma and results).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Most Important Buddhist Lesson Learned and Taught</title>
      <link>/posts/most-important-buddhist-lesson-learned/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/most-important-buddhist-lesson-learned/</guid>
      <description>A little while ago, I was asked what was the most important lesson learned and what was the most important thing that I taught. The answer spans two different videos and they are listed below:&#xA;The first video gives a very technical answer, yet in very simple English that everyone can understand. However those who are into the deepest Dhamma and Abhidhamma will still appreciate what is said and how it is said.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kauai Monk Update 3</title>
      <link>/posts/kauai-update-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/kauai-update-3/</guid>
      <description>Kauai Update #3&#xA;I have moved from the Botanical Gardens recently. I was able to stay there for 5 months and the majority of the time there was wonderful. However things were changing and it was time for me to look for another place and now I am staying in a new long term location in Kilauea.&#xA;It all happened after a wonderful person picked me up on the side of the road holding my signs the day my parents, brother and in-law dropped me off (I’ll get back to that family-visit part later).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Abhidhamma Lessons: A Top-Down Approach Using Computer Science</title>
      <link>/posts/abhidhamma-lessons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/abhidhamma-lessons/</guid>
      <description>Free Book: Abhidhamma Lessons PDF Download Abhidhamma Lessons PDF Here is a book I wrote long ago that relates the Abhidhamma to Computer Science. As a programmer from the nineties, I &amp;ldquo;clicked&amp;rdquo; with the abhidhamma after reading just a small amount. When I learned that the mind does only one thing at a time, it instantly clicked with a graduate class I had taken on digital circuits. It gave me the faith in the Abhidhamma early on which is very rare among Western Monks and Western Theravada Buddhist lay people.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why do monks have one shoulder exposed sometimes and both shoulders covered other times?</title>
      <link>/posts/why-do-monks-have-one-shoulder-exposed-sometimes-and-both-shoulders-covered-other-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/why-do-monks-have-one-shoulder-exposed-sometimes-and-both-shoulders-covered-other-times/</guid>
      <description>Why do monks have one shoulder exposed sometimes and both shoulders covered other times?&#xA;There is a very small rule about having the robes fully covered when we are in a populated areas (sekhiyā 3). Although it is a very small rule, it can say a great deal about the monk and his respect for the monastic code, especially in the afternoons or evenings.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Populated areas&amp;rdquo; refers to when we are outside of the monastery and outside of the forest.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guided Four Elements and Loving-Kindness September 9th, 2018</title>
      <link>/posts/guided-four-elements-and-loving-kindness-september-9th-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/guided-four-elements-and-loving-kindness-september-9th-2018/</guid>
      <description>Here is a dhamma talk with a very brief instruction for Four Elements. It is not complete, but gives a small taste of four elements. Loving-kindness is also included as usual. The recording is cleaner using some post processing with the same recorder.&#xA;[archiveorg id=BhanteSubhuti2018Sept9 width=520 height=140]</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dhamma Talk Princeville August 19 2018</title>
      <link>/posts/dhamma-talk-princeville-august-19-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/dhamma-talk-princeville-august-19-2018/</guid>
      <description>With only 5 minutes left before we were supposed to start, the security guard told us that someone else had the room booked and we would need to move to a smaller amd inferior room. It was a mistake on their part, and while I did ask to see the schedule book, I opted out because we were running out of time and needed to setup the room again. It was disturbing and noisy, but we had to make the best of it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vegetarianism and Theravada Buddhism</title>
      <link>/posts/vegetarianism-theravada-buddhism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/vegetarianism-theravada-buddhism/</guid>
      <description>Vegetarianism and Theravada Buddhism I have been asked to write a little something on vegetarianism and Theravāda Buddhism. I am qualified to be quite objective, and to see both sides of the issue because I was a vegetarian for a total of ten years as a lay person and I had vegetarian eyes. That meant that when I looked at meat, cooked or not, I saw a dead animal in front of me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inspire Means To Leave Facebook</title>
      <link>/posts/inspire-means-leave-facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/inspire-means-leave-facebook/</guid>
      <description>Inspire Means To Leave Facebook Much of what I write about is related to stories that happen to me that would charge me up and make me feel inspired. I would then write down what happened and share it with others. Often my stories are related to vinaya – the monks’ rules and living without money. These days it is special for a monk to live without money and I can inspire people simply by following the rules.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are You A Buddhist</title>
      <link>/posts/are-you-a-buddhist/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/are-you-a-buddhist/</guid>
      <description>Are You A Buddhist?&#xA;Introduction&#xA;Being a Buddhist is quite open because if you believe in certain aspects it is better than not believing in anything. We take what we can get. However, here are the more traditional aspects of being Buddhist. One should believe in The Triple Gem – ie**: The Buddha, The Dhamma and The Sangha).** This can be expanded to include The 4 Noble Truths. This can be expanded to include the Eightfold Noble Path as well.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Dark Side of Ajahn Mun&#39;s Biography</title>
      <link>/posts/dark-side-ajahn-mun/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/dark-side-ajahn-mun/</guid>
      <description>Ajahn Mun dark&#xA;Did Ajahn Mun say the Buddha congratulated him on the night he attained arahant? His biography books says it for sure.&#xA;Venerable Ācariya Mun Būridatta Thera is one of the most revered forest masters of the 20th century. He is the root guru of both the Dhammayut and Ajahn Chah monasteries. He popularized the monastic practice of living under an umbrella in the forest and his relentless energy is fascinating and inspiring.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Do Monks Say Grace Before Eating?</title>
      <link>/posts/monks-say-grace-eating/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/monks-say-grace-eating/</guid>
      <description>How Do Monks Say Grace Before Eating? Do Theravāda monks say anything before they eat? Do they give thanks? Who do they say thanks to? Or is it something else?&#xA;Buddhist monks generally do a reflection and chant something before eating. In fact it is said that the monks incurs debt if they doe not reflect before eating. Actually, there are 4 reflections concerning the Four Requisites:&#xA;1. Robes</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does The Buddha live in Nibbana</title>
      <link>/posts/buddha-live-nibbana/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/buddha-live-nibbana/</guid>
      <description>The Buddha in the clouds&#xA;Does the Buddha Live in Nibbāna? Many people believe that the Buddha is alive and living in some sort of transcendental realm called Nibbāna where he can hear your prayers and eat and drink the food and water that you offer to Him. We Buddhist monks smile when we hear that people have such beliefs because nobody lives in Nibbāna, not even a Buddha.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buddhism and Abortion</title>
      <link>/posts/buddhism-and-abortion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/buddhism-and-abortion/</guid>
      <description>What do Theravada Buddhists believe in terms of abortion? Much of what has been written are liberal beliefs and overturning what is written down in the texts. They claim “Modern Buddhism” as a section heading, but there is no such thing as “Modern Buddhism” since there is no such thing as “Modern Kamma.” The rules of kamma do not change over time, and abortion has been around since the time of the Buddha.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
