<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>covid on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/covid/</link>
    <description>Recent content in covid on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/covid/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Living as a Monk in Myanmar During Covid and Government Change</title>
      <link>/posts/living-as-a-monk-in-myanmar-during-covid-and-government-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/living-as-a-monk-in-myanmar-during-covid-and-government-change/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Foreigner monk gets a COVID vaccine jab during the times of the new Myanmar government&#xA;In this article, I want to share with you some of my experiences of living as a monk in Myanmar during the covid pandemic and the government change that happened recently. I also want to explain why I left Myanmar at the end of 2022 and what I am doing now.&#xA;I am an American Buddhist monk who has been living in Myanmar for many years.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pa-Auk Lockdown #3:  Living With COVID</title>
      <link>/posts/pa-auk-lockdown-3-living-with-covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/pa-auk-lockdown-3-living-with-covid/</guid>
      <description>Now the world is getting used to COVID-19 and many countries are announcing a new policy called &amp;ldquo;Living with COVID&amp;rdquo;. Now we are too. I will explain&amp;hellip;.&#xA;On March 17, 2022, Pa-Auk Pyin Oo Lwin literally started to live with COVID. On that day, there were 5 monks that were sick and tested positive. When lunch came, we were on high alert. Massive testing happened within the next few days and we went from 12 positive cases to 25 and then to 35 and now we are at 50 cases for the male size and 15 for the female side only one week later.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pa-Auk Vaccination 2021</title>
      <link>/posts/pa-auk-vaccination-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/pa-auk-vaccination-2021/</guid>
      <description>Injection on Western resident monk&#xA;Pa-Auk finally vaccinated 2000 of its residents across its branch monasteries with a privately sponsored SinoPharm vaccine. Pa-Auk Pyin Oo Lwin branch had its vaccines delivered on September 18th, 2021 with about half of the total population signed up. Vaccination was voluntary and provided by donors.&#xA;While it did take a long time for us to get the vaccine, the government did invite us for the vaccine back in April or May 2021.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Super Quarantine Inside Pa-Auk</title>
      <link>/posts/super-quarantine-inside-pa-auk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/super-quarantine-inside-pa-auk/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I had a serious medical problem that had the potential to be extremely serious. Please don&amp;rsquo;t ask. In any case, I arranged permission to go outside and then arranged for someone to help me get to a clinic in Mandalay which had the proper technology to properly assess my problem. This article is not about going out. Instead this article is about coming back and staying in quarantine.&#xA;Because we do not have monastery-wide vaccines yet, Pa-Auk is quite strict about letting people go outside because when you come back, you will need to be on a 3 week quarantine before testing for your release.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
