<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>bodhi-tree on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/bodhi-tree/</link>
    <description>Recent content in bodhi-tree on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/bodhi-tree/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Only The Best For Buddha</title>
      <link>/posts/only-the-best-for-buddha/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/only-the-best-for-buddha/</guid>
      <description>6 Color Buddhist Flag&#xA;Yesterday, on Vesak, I was invited to go with Sayadaw Kumarabhivamsa, the Tipitaka Sayadaw and one more monk to visit the three very large Buddhas in our monastery and then finally to give water to the Bodhi Tree. When we give water to the Bodhi Tree, it is not uncommon to give pure bottled drinking water to it. Yes, you read that correctly.&#xA;Bottled drinking water is used to water a tree.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our Bodhi Tree</title>
      <link>/posts/our-bodhi-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/our-bodhi-tree/</guid>
      <description>There is a Bodhi Tree on our property and we sometimes do a vandana (chanting) in front of this tree rather than at the gazebo. We did one tonight until a passing rain cloud sprinkled on us.&#xA;From Wikipedia: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bodhi_Tree The Bodhi Tree, also known as Bo (from Sinhalese: Bo) and &amp;ldquo;peepal tree&amp;rdquo; in Nepal and Bhutan, was a large and very old sacred fig tree (Ficus religiosa[1])[2] located in Bodh Gaya, India, under which Siddhartha Gautama, the spiritual teacher later known as Gautama Buddha, is said to have attained enlightenment, or Bodhi.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
