<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>lockdown on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/lockdown/</link>
    <description>Recent content in lockdown on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/lockdown/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pa-Auk Lockdown #3:  Living With COVID</title>
      <link>/posts/pa-auk-lockdown-3-living-with-covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/pa-auk-lockdown-3-living-with-covid/</guid>
      <description>Now the world is getting used to COVID-19 and many countries are announcing a new policy called &amp;ldquo;Living with COVID&amp;rdquo;. Now we are too. I will explain&amp;hellip;.&#xA;On March 17, 2022, Pa-Auk Pyin Oo Lwin literally started to live with COVID. On that day, there were 5 monks that were sick and tested positive. When lunch came, we were on high alert. Massive testing happened within the next few days and we went from 12 positive cases to 25 and then to 35 and now we are at 50 cases for the male size and 15 for the female side only one week later.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Lockdown Suggestions From A Monk</title>
      <link>/posts/7-lockdown-suggestions-from-a-monk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/7-lockdown-suggestions-from-a-monk/</guid>
      <description>These days, the lockdowns are in full swing. The question is, &amp;ldquo;What do you do with your time?&amp;rdquo; Perhaps you are out of work, or retired like my parents. What do you do? As a monk, lockdowns or &amp;ldquo;stay at home&amp;rdquo; orders are not much of a big deal unless a medical problem arises.&#xA;Since April, we have been on a more serious lockdown to the point where it has affected the food variety to mostly long shelf-life food items.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Covid-19 Lockdown @ Pa-Auk</title>
      <link>/posts/covid-19-lockdown-pa-auk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/covid-19-lockdown-pa-auk/</guid>
      <description>Going for Alms at Pa-Auk&#xA;The world has has begun to know about Covid-19 and unfortunately, some countries know it better than others. As a monk, I try to stay away from basic web internet except one day per week, but I still hear what goes on and as of today, April 6th, 2020, Myanmar has 21 cases and one death. The number grows slowly in the beginning as you all might know and it is uncertain what will become of the virus in weeks to come.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
