<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>kalapa on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/kalapa/</link>
    <description>Recent content in kalapa on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/kalapa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Suttanta Versus Abhidhamma Rivers</title>
      <link>/posts/suttanta-versus-abhidhamma-rivers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/suttanta-versus-abhidhamma-rivers/</guid>
      <description>Irrawaddi River, Bagan, 2015&#xA;There seems to be quite a bit of confusion about what the Abhidhamma is all about. If I were to describe a river based on Suttanta values and then describe it again in terms of Abhidhamma and commentary values, Abhidhamma will be very clear in its validity and purpose. I don&amp;rsquo;t recall the Buddha explaining rivers in Suttas in the way I will explain them. However, I will try to explain them &amp;ldquo;as if&amp;rdquo; they were spoken in the Suttas and also &amp;ldquo;as if&amp;rdquo; they were mentioned in the Abhidhamma and Commentaries.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Did The Buddha Know Einstein&#39;s Theory?</title>
      <link>/posts/did-the-buddha-know-einsteins-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/did-the-buddha-know-einsteins-theory/</guid>
      <description>Einstein formula on blackboard see this link for attribution&#xA;The Mass–energy equivalence is one of the most famous physics equations known to the general population. Did the Buddha know this beforehand? We all know this formula as the explanation for how nuclear energy works, but we really don&amp;rsquo; t know much more than that.&#xA;For my one of my birthdays, I asked a monk who was once a nuclear engineer from Chernobyl to explain to me how it works.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
