<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>maymyo on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/maymyo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in maymyo on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/maymyo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Thanks and Giving</title>
      <link>/posts/thanks-and-giving/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/thanks-and-giving/</guid>
      <description>Of course I&amp;rsquo;m happy!&#xA;On November 24, I helped make a nice breakfast and lunch for Pa-Auk Forest Monastery, Pyin Oo Lwin. I organized 28 monks including myself to be the donors for the whole day meals + fresh squeezed apple juice, for a full value of 1,250,000 Myanmar Kyat. It fed approximately 530 yogis across four sections in Pa-Auk Forest Monastery. But how is that possible for monks to donate money?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monastery-wide Sickness Happens</title>
      <link>/posts/monastery-wide-sickness-happens/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/monastery-wide-sickness-happens/</guid>
      <description>While I have said quite a lot to inspire people about life as a monk around the world. I should give you both sides of the story to be fair.&#xA;When you think about living in Asia full-time or just for a visit, the first thought that comes to mind is, &amp;ldquo;Will I get sick?&amp;rdquo;. It can happen, and when you rely on volunteers and health standards that work &amp;ldquo;most of the time&amp;rdquo; but not all of the time, then problems can arise.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maymyo Pa-Auk Meals</title>
      <link>/posts/maymyo-pa-auk-meals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/maymyo-pa-auk-meals/</guid>
      <description>At Theravada monasteries there is no eating allowed after Noontime. Some monasteries only give one meal per day, while other monasteries give 2 meals per day. Both meal plans are allowed by the Buddha. However, some monasteries have no meals brought to the monks and they need to go out in the village and collect it. This last case is very rare and usually done by the forest monks living in secluded places or ehem.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview: Monk Meditates for 24 Hours</title>
      <link>/posts/interview-monk-meditates-for-24-hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/interview-monk-meditates-for-24-hours/</guid>
      <description>Downloaded from https://www.needpix.com&#xA;Interview 1 of 2 Note: Some edits have been made afterwards to make things clear or to protect the anonymity of people.&#xA;I am sitting here now with one anonymous monk. He has sat for more than 24 hours in 4th jhāna and I wanted to interview him anonymously to inspire others. So we are here with Bhante (Note: All monks can be called “Bhante”).&#xA;I want to ask a few questions.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
