<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>bagan on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/bagan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in bagan on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/bagan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On The Way Back Home</title>
      <link>/posts/on-the-way-back-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/on-the-way-back-home/</guid>
      <description>Swedagon Pagoda, Myanmar&#xA;On November 4th, I left The States for Sri Lanka, Thailand and of course Myanmar which I now consider a home for myself. Shortly after the Buddhist Rainy Season had begun in Kaua’i, the support for inviting a second monk fell through and I was tired of being alone which meant I needed to leave.&#xA;Around the same time, in late July or early August, my Lao/American supporter named Thongvanh, sent me brochure with a monk who was leading a “Spiritual Sri Lanka Trip” which included the Sri Maha Bodhi Tree in Anuradhapura.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shining The Inner Core</title>
      <link>/posts/shining-the-inner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/shining-the-inner/</guid>
      <description>To receive this by email, sign up at https://subhuti.withmetta.net/subscribe/&#xA;Last year, this picture (without the writing) went viral. The viral post seems to makes its rounds from time to time and every so often, someone tells me they saw my picture. It started when I was in Bagan for an 8 day trip with my friend Ashin Pannyagavesaka. We did a slow and thorough excursion and walked a good chunk of Bagan when rides were not provided.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
