<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>pa-auk-pyin-oo-lwin on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/pa-auk-pyin-oo-lwin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in pa-auk-pyin-oo-lwin on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/pa-auk-pyin-oo-lwin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Covid-19 Lockdown @ Pa-Auk</title>
      <link>/posts/covid-19-lockdown-pa-auk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/covid-19-lockdown-pa-auk/</guid>
      <description>Going for Alms at Pa-Auk&#xA;The world has has begun to know about Covid-19 and unfortunately, some countries know it better than others. As a monk, I try to stay away from basic web internet except one day per week, but I still hear what goes on and as of today, April 6th, 2020, Myanmar has 21 cases and one death. The number grows slowly in the beginning as you all might know and it is uncertain what will become of the virus in weeks to come.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anniversary 19:  I’m Still Standing</title>
      <link>/posts/anniversary-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/anniversary-19/</guid>
      <description>The standing marble Buddha at Pyin Oo Lwin Pa-Auk&#xA;On Feb 7th, 2001 I took my original ordination with The Most Venerable Pa-Auk Saydawgyi. It was the happiest days of my life and the most important one besides successfully being born as a human and surviving any serious death or injuries. Although there was a small hiccup, it has been 19 years total. I had just finished arranging my residential visa that was said could not be changed from a tourist visa without leaving the country.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On The Way Back Home</title>
      <link>/posts/on-the-way-back-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/on-the-way-back-home/</guid>
      <description>Swedagon Pagoda, Myanmar&#xA;On November 4th, I left The States for Sri Lanka, Thailand and of course Myanmar which I now consider a home for myself. Shortly after the Buddhist Rainy Season had begun in Kaua’i, the support for inviting a second monk fell through and I was tired of being alone which meant I needed to leave.&#xA;Around the same time, in late July or early August, my Lao/American supporter named Thongvanh, sent me brochure with a monk who was leading a “Spiritual Sri Lanka Trip” which included the Sri Maha Bodhi Tree in Anuradhapura.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
