<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>theravada on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/theravada/</link>
    <description>Recent content in theravada on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/theravada/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What is Theravada Buddhism?</title>
      <link>/posts/what-is-theravada-buddhism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/what-is-theravada-buddhism/</guid>
      <description>Monk at The Bodhi Tree located at International Institute of Theravāda&#xA;Theravada (Theravāda) is one of the major branches of Buddhism and is often referred to as the &amp;ldquo;School of the Elders.&amp;rdquo; It is the oldest surviving Buddhist school and it is the predominant religion of Sri Lanka, Myanmar, Thailand, Laos, and Cambodia. Because of its age and orthodoxy, it can also be loosely translated as &amp;ldquo;Old School Buddhism&amp;rdquo; in some ways too.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should Bhikkhunis Be Sent To Probation Monasteries?</title>
      <link>/posts/should-bhikkhunis-be-sent-to-probation-monasteries/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/should-bhikkhunis-be-sent-to-probation-monasteries/</guid>
      <description>Copyright notice.. picture by Kim Traynor cc-by-sa&#xA;Note: This post is not for everyone. Those who claim to be bhikkhunis and supporters of the movement, and monks and nuns in general will find this interesting.&#xA;Did you know that bhikkhunis (nuns) are not allowed to sleep alone or travel alone and if they do, they are sentenced to 2 weeks of rehabilitation and lose their full status as bhikkhunis during this period?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Theravada Bhikkhuni Ordinations Valid?</title>
      <link>/posts/are-theravada-bhikkhuni-ordinations-valid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/are-theravada-bhikkhuni-ordinations-valid/</guid>
      <description>cc0 picture https://pxhere.com/en/photo/489726&#xA;There is not much written in English explaining why bhikkhuni ordinations are rejected by the Theravāda Community of Monks. The English writings are a poor representation of the vast majority of Buddhist Scholarship and that is why there is &amp;ldquo;controversy&amp;rdquo; regarding the revival of the extinct Theravāda Bhikkhuni order. There is really no controversy to speak about once you know the full story.&#xA;Many Westerners believe that women are not able to become nuns without such a revival, but that is not true.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Robes of Theravadan, Mahayanan, Tibetan Monks</title>
      <link>/posts/the-robes-of-theravadan-mahayanan-tibetan-monks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/the-robes-of-theravadan-mahayanan-tibetan-monks/</guid>
      <description>It occured to me that people don&amp;rsquo;t know one type of Buddhist monk from the other and a post was needed to explain this.&#xA;First a little bit of history. Theravada is the closest thing as one can get to the original form of Buddhism and is based on the Pali texts. The countries that have Theravada as their national religion are; Myanmar, Thailand, Laos, Sri Lanka, and Cambodia. It dates back to the Buddha from 5th century BCE Later, came Mahayana - Chinese Buddhism of the 1st century BCE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How To Pronounce Theravada</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-pronounce-theravada/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/how-to-pronounce-theravada/</guid>
      <description>How to Pronounce Theravāda Have you ever wondered if you were pronouncing Theravāda correctly? Read this article to find out how to properly pronounce Theravāda.&#xA;Most of the resources out on the web mispronounce the word Theravāda, and Google has failed me when I did a search too. However, it was a good excuse to write this small article. The &amp;ldquo;Th&amp;rdquo; sound in Theravāda is not the English &amp;ldquo;Th&amp;rdquo; like &amp;ldquo;Them&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Think.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buddhist Monks&#39; Robes Information</title>
      <link>/posts/buddhist-monks-robes-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/buddhist-monks-robes-information/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1367&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;708&amp;rdquo;] Sewing pattern from BMC 1 (creative-commons, Thanissaro Bhikkhu)[/caption]&#xA;Robe Information Few people realize that the Theravāda monk’s robes are actually a piece of rectangular cloth with no sleeves.[mfn]While some monks use shirts with sleeves underneath their robes, it is not actually allowed [/mfn] If you see a Theravāda monk wearing his robes in different styles, then rest assured it is due to the art of “tying the robes” or “rolling the robes” or what I call “robe origami.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Collecting Alms (Piṇḍapāta) Legal?</title>
      <link>/posts/is-collecting-alms-pindapata-legal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/is-collecting-alms-pindapata-legal/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1264&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;708&amp;rdquo;] That is me going for alms on Aalona Street Kilauea.[/caption]&#xA;Collecting alms, also known as piṇḍapāta by Theravāda Buddhists, is a legal activity in the USA. There are some restrictions though. I spoke with a lawyer who seemed to know civil liberties quite well, but there are no guarantees with what I say. However, this information should make sense and seem legal to you. It is legal to ring the doorbell of any house and preach to them or talk to them about politics under the freedom of speech rights.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kauai Update Part 2</title>
      <link>/posts/kauai-update-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/kauai-update-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Aloha!&#xA;It has been a little over a month since I have been on the island of Kauai. Things have been going well although my situation is still the same. I am still in a tent at Anini, but I have a new tent in Anini with a better view of the pristine Kauai shore! Things are dryer than the record rains we had last month.. and I guess if it were wetter than before a new record would be set.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vegetarianism and Theravada Buddhism</title>
      <link>/posts/vegetarianism-theravada-buddhism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/vegetarianism-theravada-buddhism/</guid>
      <description>Vegetarianism and Theravada Buddhism I have been asked to write a little something on vegetarianism and Theravāda Buddhism. I am qualified to be quite objective, and to see both sides of the issue because I was a vegetarian for a total of ten years as a lay person and I had vegetarian eyes. That meant that when I looked at meat, cooked or not, I saw a dead animal in front of me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Do Monks Say Grace Before Eating?</title>
      <link>/posts/monks-say-grace-eating/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/monks-say-grace-eating/</guid>
      <description>How Do Monks Say Grace Before Eating? Do Theravāda monks say anything before they eat? Do they give thanks? Who do they say thanks to? Or is it something else?&#xA;Buddhist monks generally do a reflection and chant something before eating. In fact it is said that the monks incurs debt if they doe not reflect before eating. Actually, there are 4 reflections concerning the Four Requisites:&#xA;1. Robes</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does The Buddha live in Nibbana</title>
      <link>/posts/buddha-live-nibbana/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/buddha-live-nibbana/</guid>
      <description>The Buddha in the clouds&#xA;Does the Buddha Live in Nibbāna? Many people believe that the Buddha is alive and living in some sort of transcendental realm called Nibbāna where he can hear your prayers and eat and drink the food and water that you offer to Him. We Buddhist monks smile when we hear that people have such beliefs because nobody lives in Nibbāna, not even a Buddha.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kauai Propagation Presentation</title>
      <link>/posts/kauai-propagation-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/kauai-propagation-presentation/</guid>
      <description>A 2 part Powerpoint presentation about what two monks did in Kauai, Hawaii during June to December 2015. The theme was propagation, but the propagation was done just from being monks who do not touch money, and collect their food the traditional Buddhist monk way. The vision, how it got started, stories and experiences were shared. About 50 people were in the audience. Running time is about 1 hour total for both.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
