<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>alms on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/alms/</link>
    <description>Recent content in alms on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/alms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Three Stories Of Loving-kindness</title>
      <link>/posts/three-stories-of-loving-kindness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/three-stories-of-loving-kindness/</guid>
      <description>There are three stories of loving-kindness told in the video posted below. The first story is from Kaua&amp;rsquo;i, Hawai&amp;rsquo;i, when a person did not want me on &amp;ldquo;his&amp;rdquo; street. Through the power of loving-kindness, things changed. Another story was also from the island in 2015. There were children on bicycles who were yelling at us to go away on multiple days. Through the power of loving-kindness, things changed. The last story is from 2011 during a trip to India.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why A Monk&#39;s Empty Bowl Made Me So Happy!</title>
      <link>/posts/why-a-monks-empty-bowl-made-me-so-happy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/why-a-monks-empty-bowl-made-me-so-happy/</guid>
      <description>Ven. Nepal Nāthaputta and I have been going for alms together for some time now. He usually comes with me the whole way on Saturdays and on Sundays, he forks right after the 2nd or 3rd house. However, recently, a new monk decided to join our route. Last week, Ven. Nepal Nāthaputta went off on his own on Saturday while the two of us went on my usual route (good for two monks).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intelligent Donations: Turning The Tables</title>
      <link>/posts/intelligent-donations-turning-the-tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/intelligent-donations-turning-the-tables/</guid>
      <description>Ven Ananda with the two donors&#xA;Recently, we received six new tables arranged by a monk&amp;rsquo;s two donors. The tables were nice but I didn&amp;rsquo;t think we needed them, so I asked the monk why. He said there was not enough room on the tables for his donors&amp;rsquo; donations, so they decided to donate more tables so they can donate more. When his donors make donations, they are not small.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Piṇḍapāta:  Why Do Monks Go For Alms in a Village?</title>
      <link>/posts/why-go-for-alms-in-a-village-while-they-are-still-recovering-economic-crisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/why-go-for-alms-in-a-village-while-they-are-still-recovering-economic-crisis/</guid>
      <description>Alms Tray and Cambodia Monk&amp;rsquo;s Full Bowl&#xA;Introduction: This article explains the essence of piṇḍapāta (alms) and why we go for alms, even in poor villages. On the weekends, I have some time to go for alms in the nearby village. However, you might ask yourself, &amp;ldquo;Why would a monk collect food from a very poor village during an economic crisis when the monastery is mostly supported by wealthy people?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Great Day, 2019</title>
      <link>/posts/a-great-day-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/a-great-day-2019/</guid>
      <description>I remember when I was living in Kaua&amp;rsquo;i in a tent propped up in the corner of my friend Uncle Gene Taylor&amp;rsquo;s property. I had just come home from my daily alms round and I popped into his room to say hello. He is old and has difficulty walking, yet he is usually quite cheerful. As part of the visit routine, he asked me how my day was and I smiled and happily said, &amp;ldquo;Today was a great day.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leaving Kaua&#39;i On A Jet Plane</title>
      <link>/posts/leaving-kauai-on-a-jet-plane/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/leaving-kauai-on-a-jet-plane/</guid>
      <description>All-focus&#xA;As the rest of the song goes.. &amp;ldquo;And I don&amp;rsquo;t know when I&amp;rsquo;ll be back again.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;It has been almost 1.5 years living on Kaua&amp;rsquo;i. I have had an incredible experience here by doing an experiment to see if a monk can establish a monastery any place he travels to through the lost art of wandering for alms. A practice done in the name of the Buddha but rarely practised anymore.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Most Important Buddhist Lesson Learned and Taught</title>
      <link>/posts/most-important-buddhist-lesson-learned/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/most-important-buddhist-lesson-learned/</guid>
      <description>A little while ago, I was asked what was the most important lesson learned and what was the most important thing that I taught. The answer spans two different videos and they are listed below:&#xA;The first video gives a very technical answer, yet in very simple English that everyone can understand. However those who are into the deepest Dhamma and Abhidhamma will still appreciate what is said and how it is said.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pa-Auk Monastery Alms Line in Myanmar</title>
      <link>/posts/pa-auk-monastery-alms-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/pa-auk-monastery-alms-line/</guid>
      <description>I recently found this video in my Google Drive. I had a layperson (probably UKZ) follow me around in the line to show what it was like for a monk to go through the alms food line at Pa-Auk Main Center, Mawlamyine, Myanmar. It is not easy to manage so many donors with big hearts to give. Most of the time, I am giving hand signals to get less food. You might want to play this at double speed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fighting Anger With Loving-Kindness and No Money</title>
      <link>/posts/fighting-anger-with-loving-kindness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/fighting-anger-with-loving-kindness/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I ran into a very angry man who came out of his house yelling at me and coming closer and closer. Eventually, I won the fight with my two big weapons, loving-kindness and my commitment of being free from money for all these years. I have been going for alms in this neighborhood for a little over a year now, and while I did have two girls yell at me, they did not leave their property boundary.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Koral Inspires Me</title>
      <link>/posts/koral-inspires-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/koral-inspires-me/</guid>
      <description>Koral&amp;rsquo;s Family&#xA;Just about every Wednesday, I still find the time to continue with my Kilauea alms round[mfn]map is here[/mfn] (which used to include Tuesdays too). I take a one hour bus ride from Lihue, and then set out on my alms round, wishing loving-kindness to the houses one by one as I walk along the road.&#xA;In the beginning people thought I was some weird homeless person who might be crazy, but after some time, some fearless people spoke to me and then word started spreading.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kauai Update: Lihue</title>
      <link>/posts/kauai-update-lihue/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/kauai-update-lihue/</guid>
      <description>All-focus&#xA;Things have recently changed&#xA;Things have recently changed in my life. I have now moved to Lihue. Things were going well at the place where I was at before in Kilauea. The owner was happy with what I was doing for the community and I was happy and fulfilled with what I was doing for the community as well. Unfortunately, the owner&amp;rsquo;s son came for a visit. In short, he said, &amp;ldquo;I want to visit a monk.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should Monks Use Mixing Bowls as Monk Bowls?</title>
      <link>/posts/should-monks-use-mixing-bowls-as-monk-bowls/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/should-monks-use-mixing-bowls-as-monk-bowls/</guid>
      <description>On a warm Hawaiian Christmas day in 2018, I was off to collect my alms in the village. I was in a rush and worried that I would not be able to find a ride to the village where I go for alms because so few cars would be on the roads. Luckily, I got a ride and as I stepped out of the the car, I did my usual baggage check.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Miracle On 3 or 4 Streets</title>
      <link>/posts/miracle-on-3-or-4-streets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/miracle-on-3-or-4-streets/</guid>
      <description>Here are a five remarkable stories of miracles to tell, but not all of them. There have been many miracles that have come my way when I needed them the most. For the Christians out there, they might say, “Doesn’t that make you believe in God?” My answer is, “It makes me believe there are heavenly beings (Devas &amp;amp; Devis)) who are looking out for me.”. There are other stories not included such as &amp;ldquo;My Watch Story&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kauai Monk Update 3</title>
      <link>/posts/kauai-update-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/kauai-update-3/</guid>
      <description>Kauai Update #3&#xA;I have moved from the Botanical Gardens recently. I was able to stay there for 5 months and the majority of the time there was wonderful. However things were changing and it was time for me to look for another place and now I am staying in a new long term location in Kilauea.&#xA;It all happened after a wonderful person picked me up on the side of the road holding my signs the day my parents, brother and in-law dropped me off (I’ll get back to that family-visit part later).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Results From Collecting Alms In Kauai</title>
      <link>/posts/results-from-collecting-alms-in-kauai/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/results-from-collecting-alms-in-kauai/</guid>
      <description>As a Buddhist Monk collecting alms in Kauai, USA for the past 4 months, the results are in. On Tuesday and Wednesdays as shown on the map above, I collect my food, wishing loving-kindness to one side of the street at a time. So how many houses have given food at least once? About 18 people from different houses have given me food at least once. About 4 or 5 cars have given to me, but they are not included in the 18 number.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Collecting Alms (Piṇḍapāta) Legal?</title>
      <link>/posts/is-collecting-alms-pindapata-legal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/is-collecting-alms-pindapata-legal/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1264&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;708&amp;rdquo;] That is me going for alms on Aalona Street Kilauea.[/caption]&#xA;Collecting alms, also known as piṇḍapāta by Theravāda Buddhists, is a legal activity in the USA. There are some restrictions though. I spoke with a lawyer who seemed to know civil liberties quite well, but there are no guarantees with what I say. However, this information should make sense and seem legal to you. It is legal to ring the doorbell of any house and preach to them or talk to them about politics under the freedom of speech rights.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vegetarianism and Theravada Buddhism</title>
      <link>/posts/vegetarianism-theravada-buddhism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/vegetarianism-theravada-buddhism/</guid>
      <description>Vegetarianism and Theravada Buddhism I have been asked to write a little something on vegetarianism and Theravāda Buddhism. I am qualified to be quite objective, and to see both sides of the issue because I was a vegetarian for a total of ten years as a lay person and I had vegetarian eyes. That meant that when I looked at meat, cooked or not, I saw a dead animal in front of me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Do Monks Say Grace Before Eating?</title>
      <link>/posts/monks-say-grace-eating/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/monks-say-grace-eating/</guid>
      <description>How Do Monks Say Grace Before Eating? Do Theravāda monks say anything before they eat? Do they give thanks? Who do they say thanks to? Or is it something else?&#xA;Buddhist monks generally do a reflection and chant something before eating. In fact it is said that the monks incurs debt if they doe not reflect before eating. Actually, there are 4 reflections concerning the Four Requisites:&#xA;1. Robes</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Are Most Monasteries Not Allowable?</title>
      <link>/posts/why-monasteries-not-allowable/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/why-monasteries-not-allowable/</guid>
      <description>Why are most monasteries not allowable for vinaya monks? Today, I was Skyping my parents which is something we do once or twice a month now. I feel it is good for them to &amp;ldquo;see&amp;rdquo; me as a monk, rather than having them talk to me and visualizing their son from 1999. That was when I left home and things changed for me. We had a nice discussion. We spoke about possibilities for a visit, but I told them that finding a place was difficult, because the monks all use money and whatever they buy with that money becomes unallowable.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shining The Inner Core</title>
      <link>/posts/shining-the-inner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/shining-the-inner/</guid>
      <description>To receive this by email, sign up at https://subhuti.withmetta.net/subscribe/&#xA;Last year, this picture (without the writing) went viral. The viral post seems to makes its rounds from time to time and every so often, someone tells me they saw my picture. It started when I was in Bagan for an 8 day trip with my friend Ashin Pannyagavesaka. We did a slow and thorough excursion and walked a good chunk of Bagan when rides were not provided.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dhamma Talk in Thailand Loving-kindness Wins</title>
      <link>/posts/dhamma-talk-thailand-loving-kindness-wins/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/dhamma-talk-thailand-loving-kindness-wins/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=00t5_a8L9Xg&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be This is a Dhamma Talk I gave at Wat Khao Sanamachai about Kauai, alms and how loving-kindness wins battles.. It is translated into Thai by a Lao monk who lives there. The full story can be seen at https://subhuti.withmetta.net/2015/11/26/676/</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kauai Propagation Presentation</title>
      <link>/posts/kauai-propagation-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/kauai-propagation-presentation/</guid>
      <description>A 2 part Powerpoint presentation about what two monks did in Kauai, Hawaii during June to December 2015. The theme was propagation, but the propagation was done just from being monks who do not touch money, and collect their food the traditional Buddhist monk way. The vision, how it got started, stories and experiences were shared. About 50 people were in the audience. Running time is about 1 hour total for both.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When It Rains It Pours</title>
      <link>/posts/when-it-rains-it-pours/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/when-it-rains-it-pours/</guid>
      <description>I had a really good day going for alms today. When it “rains it pours.” Although it rained today, I am talking about alms donations. I told myself, that if this village does not give (like usual), then I will skip it and find another one or stay with the shack village alone. After 3 weeks of only one donor in that village, I finally got some edible food&amp;hellip;. However, I accomplished that by going down some other side-roads I had started to skip.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Benefits of Faith Alms</title>
      <link>/posts/faith-alms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/faith-alms/</guid>
      <description>The benefits of “Faith piṇḍapata”. This is a term that I learned either in Abhayagiri, Ca, or Wat Pah Nanachat or both. Probably brought to the West from Ajahn Pasanno who is/was the abbot of both. This means that when you go on alms, you make a determination to only eat the alms food you collect. When you do something like this (and I am not sooo perfect when I follow these things), you can learn a lot about yourself and the real Buddhist teachings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Loving Kindness Wins The Race</title>
      <link>/posts/676/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/676/</guid>
      <description>Loving Kindness Wins The Race (Adventures in Going for Alms in Hawaii)&#xA;Last week we encountered a disturbing event while we were going for Alms in village in Kauai. There was a lady on a bicycle who approached us and asked us what we were doing. Her tone of voice was not so happy, but we enjoy telling people what we are doing because it does not happen so often and that is one of our goals when we stand in front of each house.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Very Sweet Indeed</title>
      <link>/posts/619/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/619/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, we got some pre-Halloween candy during our alms round at one of the houses. I thought that was very &amp;ldquo;sweet&amp;rdquo; of our donor.&#xA;Halloween is a holiday on October 31, in America where kids dress up as, well, anything they want. They go around the neighborhood at night and ring the doorbells and say &amp;ldquo;Trick or treat!&amp;rdquo;. Then the person at the house would place some candy inside the ambitiously sized candy collection bags.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
