<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>halloween on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/halloween/</link>
    <description>Recent content in halloween on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/halloween/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why Is Halloween Bad According To Theravada Buddhism?</title>
      <link>/posts/why-is-halloween-bad-according-to-theravada-buddhism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/why-is-halloween-bad-according-to-theravada-buddhism/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: While I&amp;rsquo;m sure most religions do not particularly like the tradition of Halloween, I thought it would be good to explain why Halloween is not good according to Theravāda Buddhism.&#xA;Celebrating Halloween in modern times, regardless of the reasons why it was started in the first place, consists of dressing up in costumes. In celebration, you either dress up or you praise other people&amp;rsquo;s costumes. It is mostly bad karma for the one dressing up and if you praise that, it is not good either.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Possessed!  A Halloween Special</title>
      <link>/posts/possessed-halloween-special/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/possessed-halloween-special/</guid>
      <description>There were a few times when I have seen some yogis and or monks go crazy. One time I saw a possession case when I went to a Kandy forest monastery called, Ulpathkandha. It means Sprint Hill Monastery.&#xA;I think it was 2010 when I went there. I wanted to use the Internet for the first time in a few years. I wanted to see what this Facebook thing was.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Very Sweet Indeed</title>
      <link>/posts/619/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/619/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, we got some pre-Halloween candy during our alms round at one of the houses. I thought that was very &amp;ldquo;sweet&amp;rdquo; of our donor.&#xA;Halloween is a holiday on October 31, in America where kids dress up as, well, anything they want. They go around the neighborhood at night and ring the doorbells and say &amp;ldquo;Trick or treat!&amp;rdquo;. Then the person at the house would place some candy inside the ambitiously sized candy collection bags.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
