<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>itbmu on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/categories/itbmu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in itbmu on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/categories/itbmu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Power Of Timing In Donations</title>
      <link>/posts/the-power-of-timing-in-donations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/the-power-of-timing-in-donations/</guid>
      <description>This Dhamma talk discusses the key elements of the Kāladāna Sutta in addition to three personal stories that show how donations can miraculously come back to you. Some of the stories can be found at my website at this particular webpage below with pictures of the original items:&#xA;https://americanmonk.org/miracle-on-3-or-4-streets/&#xA;The video is below:&#xA;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Qy_h71a17Qo&#xA;Miracle On 3 or 4 Streets If you have ever wondered how monks survive on miracles when things go wrong, read on!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Miracle On 3 or 4 Streets</title>
      <link>/posts/miracle-on-3-or-4-streets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/miracle-on-3-or-4-streets/</guid>
      <description>Here are a five remarkable stories of miracles to tell, but not all of them. There have been many miracles that have come my way when I needed them the most. For the Christians out there, they might say, “Doesn’t that make you believe in God?” My answer is, “It makes me believe there are heavenly beings (Devas &amp;amp; Devis)) who are looking out for me.”. There are other stories not included such as &amp;ldquo;My Watch Story&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Are Most Monasteries Not Allowable?</title>
      <link>/posts/why-monasteries-not-allowable/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/why-monasteries-not-allowable/</guid>
      <description>Why are most monasteries not allowable for vinaya monks? Today, I was Skyping my parents which is something we do once or twice a month now. I feel it is good for them to &amp;ldquo;see&amp;rdquo; me as a monk, rather than having them talk to me and visualizing their son from 1999. That was when I left home and things changed for me. We had a nice discussion. We spoke about possibilities for a visit, but I told them that finding a place was difficult, because the monks all use money and whatever they buy with that money becomes unallowable.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Singing With My Bowl</title>
      <link>/posts/singwithbowl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/singwithbowl/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Singing With My Bowl&amp;rdquo; Today, after I Skyped my parents to say hello, I was doing my usual weekend schedule after: Go walking for alms, and then meditate at Swedo Paya (Tooth Relic Pagoda down the street from me). It is my favorite part of the week. It is where I can stop being a college student and be more like the monk I prefer to be. Near the end of my meditation in the Pagoda, a large Vietnam group came and did a chanting procession circumnavigating the inside of the pagoda.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inspiration, move me brightly</title>
      <link>/posts/inspiration-move-brightly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/inspiration-move-brightly/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_966&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;2048&amp;rdquo;] Alms[/caption]&#xA;Inspiration is like a bright star that shines among the dim. In Monastic life, there are few monasteries or monks that really inspire people. Following the vinaya (or rules) inspires people. It is tried and tested.&#xA;This was an old picture when I was in a vinaya monastery that follows all of the rules including the &amp;ldquo;basic ten rules&amp;rdquo; that a 7 year old beginner monk is supposed to follow.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lucky-Draw and Devas</title>
      <link>/posts/lucky-draw-devas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/lucky-draw-devas/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_902&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;948&amp;rdquo;] Calculation of odds.[/caption]&#xA;Do you believe in devas?&#xA;Devas are the Buddhist equivalent to angels. Ok .. Here is the story. I was on alms round two weeks ago and a regular supporter invited us to ask for anything for our studies at school. I needed some pens, so I asked for some pens. He told me to wait and showed up with a huge pen gift-box.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kauai Propagation Presentation</title>
      <link>/posts/kauai-propagation-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/kauai-propagation-presentation/</guid>
      <description>A 2 part Powerpoint presentation about what two monks did in Kauai, Hawaii during June to December 2015. The theme was propagation, but the propagation was done just from being monks who do not touch money, and collect their food the traditional Buddhist monk way. The vision, how it got started, stories and experiences were shared. About 50 people were in the audience. Running time is about 1 hour total for both.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Different Love Trumps Hate</title>
      <link>/posts/different-love-trumps-hate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/different-love-trumps-hate/</guid>
      <description>This video clip below came my way and I would hate to say that not only is this guy is correct right near the end of his talk, but he is expressing the same thoughts as the Buddha and myself&amp;hellip;well, at least the last part. This link will skip over to 3 minutes 38 seconds. Remainder running time is about 2 minutes. NOTE: There is more I say below after this video: https://www.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Coolest Incense Holder</title>
      <link>/posts/coolest-incense-holder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/coolest-incense-holder/</guid>
      <description>Here is a sample video and written instructions for making a self-contained incense holder made from a plastic bottle. It is the coolest incense holder I have ever used. The idea is not mine. An American lay person had one at his dorm room and I thought it was the coolest thing since sliced bread. I made mine in minutes.&#xA;The Problem: No matter how you slice it, incense holders often let the ashes fall outside of the &amp;ldquo;catching-base.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When It Rains It Pours</title>
      <link>/posts/when-it-rains-it-pours/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/when-it-rains-it-pours/</guid>
      <description>I had a really good day going for alms today. When it “rains it pours.” Although it rained today, I am talking about alms donations. I told myself, that if this village does not give (like usual), then I will skip it and find another one or stay with the shack village alone. After 3 weeks of only one donor in that village, I finally got some edible food&amp;hellip;. However, I accomplished that by going down some other side-roads I had started to skip.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Benefits of Faith Alms</title>
      <link>/posts/faith-alms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/faith-alms/</guid>
      <description>The benefits of “Faith piṇḍapata”. This is a term that I learned either in Abhayagiri, Ca, or Wat Pah Nanachat or both. Probably brought to the West from Ajahn Pasanno who is/was the abbot of both. This means that when you go on alms, you make a determination to only eat the alms food you collect. When you do something like this (and I am not sooo perfect when I follow these things), you can learn a lot about yourself and the real Buddhist teachings.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
