<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>monastery on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/monastery/</link>
    <description>Recent content in monastery on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/monastery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Video:  Knowing And Seeing Pa-Auk Forest Monastery</title>
      <link>/posts/video-knowing-seeing-pa-auk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/video-knowing-seeing-pa-auk/</guid>
      <description>From Knowing and Seeing Pa-Auk Forest Monastery video&#xA;In 2005 I made a video called, &amp;ldquo;Knowing and Seeing Pa-Auk Forest Monastery.&amp;rdquo; This is about the Pa-Auk Main Branch in Mawlamyine. Sayadawgyi was young back then and used to climb the stairs to his mountain kuti twice per day. I will miss that.&#xA;The title was meant to play with the name of Sayadawgyi&amp;rsquo;s famous book called, &amp;ldquo;Knowing and Seeing.&amp;rdquo; The book is referring to knowing and seeing the detailed Dhammas which were once thought impossible to know and literally &amp;ldquo;see&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Covid-19 Lockdown @ Pa-Auk</title>
      <link>/posts/covid-19-lockdown-pa-auk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/covid-19-lockdown-pa-auk/</guid>
      <description>Going for Alms at Pa-Auk&#xA;The world has has begun to know about Covid-19 and unfortunately, some countries know it better than others. As a monk, I try to stay away from basic web internet except one day per week, but I still hear what goes on and as of today, April 6th, 2020, Myanmar has 21 cases and one death. The number grows slowly in the beginning as you all might know and it is uncertain what will become of the virus in weeks to come.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leaving Kaua&#39;i On A Jet Plane</title>
      <link>/posts/leaving-kauai-on-a-jet-plane/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/leaving-kauai-on-a-jet-plane/</guid>
      <description>All-focus&#xA;As the rest of the song goes.. &amp;ldquo;And I don&amp;rsquo;t know when I&amp;rsquo;ll be back again.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;It has been almost 1.5 years living on Kaua&amp;rsquo;i. I have had an incredible experience here by doing an experiment to see if a monk can establish a monastery any place he travels to through the lost art of wandering for alms. A practice done in the name of the Buddha but rarely practised anymore.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Racism in Asia, Myanmar, and Monasteries</title>
      <link>/posts/racism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/racism/</guid>
      <description>Racism in Asia, Myanmar and Monasteries I remember when I came to Sri Lanka, in 2007 and I met a monk who said he was from Slovenia. “Slovenia? What kind of country is that?” I told him that I had memorized the world map in school, but I didn’t remember any “Slovenia.” There happened to be a large world map in the other room and he called me over to see it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inspiration, move me brightly</title>
      <link>/posts/inspiration-move-brightly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/inspiration-move-brightly/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_966&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;2048&amp;rdquo;] Alms[/caption]&#xA;Inspiration is like a bright star that shines among the dim. In Monastic life, there are few monasteries or monks that really inspire people. Following the vinaya (or rules) inspires people. It is tried and tested.&#xA;This was an old picture when I was in a vinaya monastery that follows all of the rules including the &amp;ldquo;basic ten rules&amp;rdquo; that a 7 year old beginner monk is supposed to follow.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visit to Varanasi Monastery, Mingaladon</title>
      <link>/posts/visit-varanasi-monastery-mingaladon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/visit-varanasi-monastery-mingaladon/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_786&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;764&amp;rdquo;] Sima of Varanasi Monastery[/caption]&#xA;A Brief Visit to Varanasi Monastery, Mingaladon&#xA;I had a few more days before I was allowed to arrive at ITBM University (I am there now). Very close by is one of my favorite monasteries in the Yangon District. Actually, there are very few choices for monks who follow the monk’s rules (Vinaya) if you want to live with like minded vinaya monks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pa-Auk Monastery in Mudon</title>
      <link>/posts/pa-auk-monastery-mudon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/pa-auk-monastery-mudon/</guid>
      <description>Kyownpine Pa-Auk Branch Monastery in Mudon, Myanmar. I have moved to Yorgo Sayadaw &amp;rsquo;s new monastery called Kyownpine. The Yorgo Sayadaw read my first ordination transaction 15 years ago and invited me to come. He speaks no English, but we have fun together. Such a lovely place, lots of Metta here. Good views, cool at night (75 degrees), nice kuti. This place is suitable for foreigners to live at complete with proper vinaya (monks&amp;rsquo; rules).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
