<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>going-for-broke on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/going-for-broke/</link>
    <description>Recent content in going-for-broke on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/going-for-broke/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why did you become a monk?</title>
      <link>/posts/why-did-you-become-a-monk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/why-did-you-become-a-monk/</guid>
      <description>Probably the #1 question we get is, &amp;ldquo;Why did you become a monk?&amp;rdquo; That question has many factors and answers. However, a better question is, &amp;ldquo;How did I actually get the nerve to become a monk?&amp;rdquo; I had a lot to give up. I was a computer programmer and really enjoyed my job. It did not feel like work actually and I was also making more than 15 times what someone on minimum wage was making at that time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Blackjack Anniversary</title>
      <link>/posts/my-blackjack-anniversary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/my-blackjack-anniversary/</guid>
      <description>Eating Hall Feb 7 2022&#xA;Today is my 21rst anniversary for when I first got ordained as a monk on February 7th, 2001. As you know there was a hiccup and I ordained twice (back to back) leaving me with an official age of 15 years. However, the total years is 21 and this is my blackjack year when I first got my name.&#xA;There were many reasons why I wanted to ordain as a Buddhist Monk.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Free Book: Going For Broke</title>
      <link>/posts/book-going-for-broke/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/book-going-for-broke/</guid>
      <description>Downloads:&#xA;Going For Broke: Travelogs On Becoming a Buddhist Monk is a compilation of travel stories. It is an anonymously written book about a lay person who quit his job in order to travel the world and then become a Buddhist Monk. Most people either love it and read it in a few days or never finish it.&#xA;Here is the back cover:&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Going for Broke&amp;rdquo; consists of travel stories written by a young American man who gave up his lucrative job to travel the world and decide if he would fulfill his lifelong dream of becoming a Buddhist monk.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
