<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>kauai on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/kauai/</link>
    <description>Recent content in kauai on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/kauai/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Great Day, 2019</title>
      <link>/posts/a-great-day-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/a-great-day-2019/</guid>
      <description>I remember when I was living in Kaua&amp;rsquo;i in a tent propped up in the corner of my friend Uncle Gene Taylor&amp;rsquo;s property. I had just come home from my daily alms round and I popped into his room to say hello. He is old and has difficulty walking, yet he is usually quite cheerful. As part of the visit routine, he asked me how my day was and I smiled and happily said, &amp;ldquo;Today was a great day.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leaving Kaua&#39;i On A Jet Plane</title>
      <link>/posts/leaving-kauai-on-a-jet-plane/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/leaving-kauai-on-a-jet-plane/</guid>
      <description>All-focus&#xA;As the rest of the song goes.. &amp;ldquo;And I don&amp;rsquo;t know when I&amp;rsquo;ll be back again.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;It has been almost 1.5 years living on Kaua&amp;rsquo;i. I have had an incredible experience here by doing an experiment to see if a monk can establish a monastery any place he travels to through the lost art of wandering for alms. A practice done in the name of the Buddha but rarely practised anymore.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ian (exVen. Visarada) Visits Kauai</title>
      <link>/posts/ian-pka-visarada-visits-kauai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/ian-pka-visarada-visits-kauai/</guid>
      <description>This past July, I had an old friend named Ian Sloan (previously Venerable Visarada ) visit me in Kauai. He disrobed after being a monk for 25 years. He disrobed because of a conflict of philosophy about what happens at death. It was a combination of accounts from past life regressions in hypnotherapy, what he has read by Edgar Cayce, and the event of his father&amp;rsquo;s death. He seems to appreciate the Near Death Experiences which can still be explained partially with Buddhism, but he felt it was time to disrobe.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Koral Inspires Me</title>
      <link>/posts/koral-inspires-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/koral-inspires-me/</guid>
      <description>Koral&amp;rsquo;s Family&#xA;Just about every Wednesday, I still find the time to continue with my Kilauea alms round[mfn]map is here[/mfn] (which used to include Tuesdays too). I take a one hour bus ride from Lihue, and then set out on my alms round, wishing loving-kindness to the houses one by one as I walk along the road.&#xA;In the beginning people thought I was some weird homeless person who might be crazy, but after some time, some fearless people spoke to me and then word started spreading.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kauai Update: Lihue</title>
      <link>/posts/kauai-update-lihue/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/kauai-update-lihue/</guid>
      <description>All-focus&#xA;Things have recently changed&#xA;Things have recently changed in my life. I have now moved to Lihue. Things were going well at the place where I was at before in Kilauea. The owner was happy with what I was doing for the community and I was happy and fulfilled with what I was doing for the community as well. Unfortunately, the owner&amp;rsquo;s son came for a visit. In short, he said, &amp;ldquo;I want to visit a monk.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18th Anniversary and Update</title>
      <link>/posts/18th-anniversary-and-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/18th-anniversary-and-update/</guid>
      <description>This is where I live&#xA;Wow! Today is February 7th and another year has passed. I have now completed 18 years total as a monk and I am working on my 19th year. Of course, my monk age is 12 rainy seasons because I changed Nikayas after my 6th year. I have been living my monk life in Kauai, Hawaii for about 10 months now and things have been moving along.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Old Kauai Favorite: KKCR Interview</title>
      <link>/posts/kkcr-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/kkcr-interview/</guid>
      <description>Here is the link to the 2015 KKCR radio show. We were interviewed on Kauai Community Radio for about one hour instead of the scheduled 20 minutes. We all had fun doing it. It will give you a good taste of what we did on the island in 2015 and what I am doing now. I often enjoy revisiting this recording, and I hope you do too.&#xA;[archiveorg id=oasis111518-2]</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kauai Monk Update 3</title>
      <link>/posts/kauai-update-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/kauai-update-3/</guid>
      <description>Kauai Update #3&#xA;I have moved from the Botanical Gardens recently. I was able to stay there for 5 months and the majority of the time there was wonderful. However things were changing and it was time for me to look for another place and now I am staying in a new long term location in Kilauea.&#xA;It all happened after a wonderful person picked me up on the side of the road holding my signs the day my parents, brother and in-law dropped me off (I’ll get back to that family-visit part later).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Results From Collecting Alms In Kauai</title>
      <link>/posts/results-from-collecting-alms-in-kauai/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/results-from-collecting-alms-in-kauai/</guid>
      <description>As a Buddhist Monk collecting alms in Kauai, USA for the past 4 months, the results are in. On Tuesday and Wednesdays as shown on the map above, I collect my food, wishing loving-kindness to one side of the street at a time. So how many houses have given food at least once? About 18 people from different houses have given me food at least once. About 4 or 5 cars have given to me, but they are not included in the 18 number.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Collecting Alms (Piṇḍapāta) Legal?</title>
      <link>/posts/is-collecting-alms-pindapata-legal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/is-collecting-alms-pindapata-legal/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1264&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;708&amp;rdquo;] That is me going for alms on Aalona Street Kilauea.[/caption]&#xA;Collecting alms, also known as piṇḍapāta by Theravāda Buddhists, is a legal activity in the USA. There are some restrictions though. I spoke with a lawyer who seemed to know civil liberties quite well, but there are no guarantees with what I say. However, this information should make sense and seem legal to you. It is legal to ring the doorbell of any house and preach to them or talk to them about politics under the freedom of speech rights.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kauai Update Part 2</title>
      <link>/posts/kauai-update-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/kauai-update-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Aloha!&#xA;It has been a little over a month since I have been on the island of Kauai. Things have been going well although my situation is still the same. I am still in a tent at Anini, but I have a new tent in Anini with a better view of the pristine Kauai shore! Things are dryer than the record rains we had last month.. and I guess if it were wetter than before a new record would be set.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kauai Update</title>
      <link>/posts/kauai-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/kauai-update/</guid>
      <description>Kauai Update April 22 Aloha! I have been in Kauai since April 9th. It has been a rough start but things are getting better everyday. If you have paid attention to the news, you may have noticed an unheard of 30&amp;quot; of rain in 24 hours. Actually, there were several days of incredible amounts of rain, but only the third day broke the records. See https:www.washingtonpost.com&#xA;I was in a tent in Anini Park during that time and I am still in Anini Park.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Traveling Without a Helper</title>
      <link>/posts/traveling-without-helper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/traveling-without-helper/</guid>
      <description>When Ven. Devananda and I traveled to Kauai in 2015, we did not have a Kappiya (helper) to buy us food or even pay for our luggage. One can live without helpers, but it does take some pre-planning.&#xA;We had a ticket from Yangon to Honolulu that was dirt cheap at only $854 for a round trip fare. However, it came with 12 hour and 6 hour layovers in China.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dhamma Talk in Thailand Loving-kindness Wins</title>
      <link>/posts/dhamma-talk-thailand-loving-kindness-wins/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/dhamma-talk-thailand-loving-kindness-wins/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=00t5_a8L9Xg&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be This is a Dhamma Talk I gave at Wat Khao Sanamachai about Kauai, alms and how loving-kindness wins battles.. It is translated into Thai by a Lao monk who lives there. The full story can be seen at https://subhuti.withmetta.net/2015/11/26/676/</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kauai Propagation Presentation</title>
      <link>/posts/kauai-propagation-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/kauai-propagation-presentation/</guid>
      <description>A 2 part Powerpoint presentation about what two monks did in Kauai, Hawaii during June to December 2015. The theme was propagation, but the propagation was done just from being monks who do not touch money, and collect their food the traditional Buddhist monk way. The vision, how it got started, stories and experiences were shared. About 50 people were in the audience. Running time is about 1 hour total for both.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Homeless and Living Out of a Box.</title>
      <link>/posts/homeless-living-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/homeless-living-box/</guid>
      <description>I remember when I went to America in 2008 with one of my monastic friends named Ven. Visarada. He was an experienced monk and had good ascetic practices. When we went to America, he did not have any luggage and brought everything he owned with him. Instead of using luggage, he used a simple cardboard box. It is simple, easy to get, easy to dispose of and also more suitable for a monk than fancy luggage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kauai Slideshow</title>
      <link>/posts/704/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/704/</guid>
      <description>I recently made a Hawaii video slideshow. Here is the link. https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2DjEHWNTHQ0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Blue Room Session and Update</title>
      <link>/posts/688/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/688/</guid>
      <description>I went to the sacred Blue Room cave today with a friend named Narayandass. Its waters are known for their healing powers. I made a recording of some chanting before we meditated there. It was a special time and extremely high on my &amp;ldquo;Before I Go&amp;rdquo; list. A recording can be found at https://archive.org/details/Blueroomkauai. The raw recording has nothing added but was trimmed at the beginning and end of the file.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Loving Kindness Wins The Race</title>
      <link>/posts/676/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/676/</guid>
      <description>Loving Kindness Wins The Race (Adventures in Going for Alms in Hawaii)&#xA;Last week we encountered a disturbing event while we were going for Alms in village in Kauai. There was a lady on a bicycle who approached us and asked us what we were doing. Her tone of voice was not so happy, but we enjoy telling people what we are doing because it does not happen so often and that is one of our goals when we stand in front of each house.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our Bodhi Tree</title>
      <link>/posts/our-bodhi-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/our-bodhi-tree/</guid>
      <description>There is a Bodhi Tree on our property and we sometimes do a vandana (chanting) in front of this tree rather than at the gazebo. We did one tonight until a passing rain cloud sprinkled on us.&#xA;From Wikipedia: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bodhi_Tree The Bodhi Tree, also known as Bo (from Sinhalese: Bo) and &amp;ldquo;peepal tree&amp;rdquo; in Nepal and Bhutan, was a large and very old sacred fig tree (Ficus religiosa[1])[2] located in Bodh Gaya, India, under which Siddhartha Gautama, the spiritual teacher later known as Gautama Buddha, is said to have attained enlightenment, or Bodhi.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
