<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sayadaw-u-revata on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/sayadaw-u-revata/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sayadaw-u-revata on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/sayadaw-u-revata/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Order of Monks: How Seniority Shapes the Buddhist Monastic Life</title>
      <link>/posts/the-order-of-monks-how-seniority-shapes-the-buddhist-monastic-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/the-order-of-monks-how-seniority-shapes-the-buddhist-monastic-life/</guid>
      <description>monks seated for the patimokkha recitation in Pa-Auk Mawlamyine&#xA;Introduction One of the things that you may notice when you visit a Buddhist monastery is that the monks sit, eat, walk, and pay respect to each other in a certain order. This order is based on the principle of seniority, which is determined by the date of ordination, not by age, education, or social status. Whoever is ordained earlier is considered senior, and whoever is ordained later is considered junior.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Only The Best For Buddha</title>
      <link>/posts/only-the-best-for-buddha/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/only-the-best-for-buddha/</guid>
      <description>6 Color Buddhist Flag&#xA;Yesterday, on Vesak, I was invited to go with Sayadaw Kumarabhivamsa, the Tipitaka Sayadaw and one more monk to visit the three very large Buddhas in our monastery and then finally to give water to the Bodhi Tree. When we give water to the Bodhi Tree, it is not uncommon to give pure bottled drinking water to it. Yes, you read that correctly.&#xA;Bottled drinking water is used to water a tree.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
