<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>bhikkhuni on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/bhikkhuni/</link>
    <description>Recent content in bhikkhuni on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/bhikkhuni/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Memorizing The Bhikkhunī Pātimokkha</title>
      <link>/posts/memorizing-the-bhikkhuni-patimokkha/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/memorizing-the-bhikkhuni-patimokkha/</guid>
      <description>Palm leaf photo link wellcomecollection:[mfn]CC 4.0 iiif.wellcomecollection.org/image/L0031774/full/760%2C/0/default.jpg[/mfn]&#xA;Today I finished memorizing the Bhikkhunī Pātimokkha in Pāḷi (the 311 Theravāda nun&amp;rsquo;s rules). While I did not recite the whole lot in a single session, I did memorize in chunks until the total was completely memorized at one time or another. That means, I would recite a chunk of rules in front of a teacher by memory and then work on a separate adjacent succeeding chunk for memory.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should Bhikkhunis Be Sent To Probation Monasteries?</title>
      <link>/posts/should-bhikkhunis-be-sent-to-probation-monasteries/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/should-bhikkhunis-be-sent-to-probation-monasteries/</guid>
      <description>Copyright notice.. picture by Kim Traynor cc-by-sa&#xA;Note: This post is not for everyone. Those who claim to be bhikkhunis and supporters of the movement, and monks and nuns in general will find this interesting.&#xA;Did you know that bhikkhunis (nuns) are not allowed to sleep alone or travel alone and if they do, they are sentenced to 2 weeks of rehabilitation and lose their full status as bhikkhunis during this period?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Theravada Bhikkhuni Ordinations Valid?</title>
      <link>/posts/are-theravada-bhikkhuni-ordinations-valid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/are-theravada-bhikkhuni-ordinations-valid/</guid>
      <description>cc0 picture https://pxhere.com/en/photo/489726&#xA;There is not much written in English explaining why bhikkhuni ordinations are rejected by the Theravāda Community of Monks. The English writings are a poor representation of the vast majority of Buddhist Scholarship and that is why there is &amp;ldquo;controversy&amp;rdquo; regarding the revival of the extinct Theravāda Bhikkhuni order. There is really no controversy to speak about once you know the full story.&#xA;Many Westerners believe that women are not able to become nuns without such a revival, but that is not true.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
