<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>bhikkhu on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/bhikkhu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in bhikkhu on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/bhikkhu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Percentage of Monks Who Do Not Use Money</title>
      <link>/posts/percentage-of-monks-who-do-not-use-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/percentage-of-monks-who-do-not-use-money/</guid>
      <description>Monk walking towards the world of the 5%&#xA;If you are a Westerner and new to Buddhism, you might be surprised to learn that most monks use and handle money. I have calculated that around 95% use money while 5% do not use money. The general consensus of those I have consulted say that about 2 or 3 percent do not use money but I used a 5% number to be safe.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International Institute of Theravada</title>
      <link>/posts/international-institute-of-theravada/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/international-institute-of-theravada/</guid>
      <description>Multi purpose hall at IIT&#xA;After 3 years in Myanmar, I have moved to The International Institute of Theravāda. What is this place and why did I come here and what is mission?&#xA;What is IIT? The International Institute of Theravāda (IIT) is a comprehensive training institute aimed at facilitating spiritual and academic development of Buddhist monks, based on Theravada teachings. It is inclusive and accommodative, irrespective of sects (Nikaya) and other differences within the Theravada Buddhist clergy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kauai Monk Update 3</title>
      <link>/posts/kauai-update-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/kauai-update-3/</guid>
      <description>Kauai Update #3&#xA;I have moved from the Botanical Gardens recently. I was able to stay there for 5 months and the majority of the time there was wonderful. However things were changing and it was time for me to look for another place and now I am staying in a new long term location in Kilauea.&#xA;It all happened after a wonderful person picked me up on the side of the road holding my signs the day my parents, brother and in-law dropped me off (I’ll get back to that family-visit part later).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>September 11 and Jeremy Glick</title>
      <link>/posts/september-11-and-jeremy-glick/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/september-11-and-jeremy-glick/</guid>
      <description>September 11th and Jeremy Glick&#xA;I have a personal story I want to tell you about Jeremy Glick and September 11, 2001. The short story is that my name is Jeremy Glick and I was a computer programmer. However, I had left my regular world in 1999 and people who have lost track of me remembered me when 9/11 happened. About seven months after I ordained as a Buddhist Monk in 2001, the famous 9/11 or September 11th event happened.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kauai Update Part 2</title>
      <link>/posts/kauai-update-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/kauai-update-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Aloha!&#xA;It has been a little over a month since I have been on the island of Kauai. Things have been going well although my situation is still the same. I am still in a tent at Anini, but I have a new tent in Anini with a better view of the pristine Kauai shore! Things are dryer than the record rains we had last month.. and I guess if it were wetter than before a new record would be set.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donation to Sangha or Individuals?</title>
      <link>/posts/donation-sangha-individuals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/donation-sangha-individuals/</guid>
      <description>When should you give to Saṅgha?&#xA;When should you give to individual monks?&#xA;This is a question that is not addressed very often and it can cause lots of trouble for monks knowingly and unknowingly. Quite often, many monks blindly prompt donors to recite a line of pāḷi before they offer anything to them. “Bhikkhu Saṅghassa demi.” There are some variations, but that is the generic formula. It means, “I give to the community of monks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making A Foot-Rug From Old Robes</title>
      <link>/posts/making-foot-rug-old-robes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/making-foot-rug-old-robes/</guid>
      <description>Here is an instructional video on how to make a foot-rug from old and discarded monk&amp;rsquo;s robes. If you are a monk, perhaps you will be very interested in this. I made the video as I was making my very first rug. Ven. Khemavamsa is the one who helped in the end. It was his idea and I have never seen this before. The story from the texts is below:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kauai Propagation Presentation</title>
      <link>/posts/kauai-propagation-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/kauai-propagation-presentation/</guid>
      <description>A 2 part Powerpoint presentation about what two monks did in Kauai, Hawaii during June to December 2015. The theme was propagation, but the propagation was done just from being monks who do not touch money, and collect their food the traditional Buddhist monk way. The vision, how it got started, stories and experiences were shared. About 50 people were in the audience. Running time is about 1 hour total for both.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
