<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>kauai-monk on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/kauai-monk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in kauai-monk on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/kauai-monk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fighting Anger With Loving-Kindness and No Money</title>
      <link>/posts/fighting-anger-with-loving-kindness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/fighting-anger-with-loving-kindness/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I ran into a very angry man who came out of his house yelling at me and coming closer and closer. Eventually, I won the fight with my two big weapons, loving-kindness and my commitment of being free from money for all these years. I have been going for alms in this neighborhood for a little over a year now, and while I did have two girls yell at me, they did not leave their property boundary.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kauai Update: Lihue</title>
      <link>/posts/kauai-update-lihue/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/kauai-update-lihue/</guid>
      <description>All-focus&#xA;Things have recently changed&#xA;Things have recently changed in my life. I have now moved to Lihue. Things were going well at the place where I was at before in Kilauea. The owner was happy with what I was doing for the community and I was happy and fulfilled with what I was doing for the community as well. Unfortunately, the owner&amp;rsquo;s son came for a visit. In short, he said, &amp;ldquo;I want to visit a monk.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Old Kauai Favorite: KKCR Interview</title>
      <link>/posts/kkcr-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/kkcr-interview/</guid>
      <description>Here is the link to the 2015 KKCR radio show. We were interviewed on Kauai Community Radio for about one hour instead of the scheduled 20 minutes. We all had fun doing it. It will give you a good taste of what we did on the island in 2015 and what I am doing now. I often enjoy revisiting this recording, and I hope you do too.&#xA;[archiveorg id=oasis111518-2]</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kauai Monk Update 3</title>
      <link>/posts/kauai-update-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/kauai-update-3/</guid>
      <description>Kauai Update #3&#xA;I have moved from the Botanical Gardens recently. I was able to stay there for 5 months and the majority of the time there was wonderful. However things were changing and it was time for me to look for another place and now I am staying in a new long term location in Kilauea.&#xA;It all happened after a wonderful person picked me up on the side of the road holding my signs the day my parents, brother and in-law dropped me off (I’ll get back to that family-visit part later).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bhikkhu Subhuti’s Blog has moved!</title>
      <link>/posts/bhikkhu-subhutis-blog-moved/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/bhikkhu-subhutis-blog-moved/</guid>
      <description>Bhikkhu Subhuti’s Blog has moved! [caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1406&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;593&amp;rdquo;] cc-sa-3.0[/caption]&#xA;The blog at https://Subhuti.withmettanet has moved to https://AmericanMonk.org The new title of the blog is American Monk: Bhante Subhūti Why change The Domain Address? The reason why I changed the name of the domain was to streamline my verbal website announcements to let them known how to find the monk in Kauai. Usually a conversation will start up with some new person in Kauai and then I say, “Hey, you can check out my blog at subhuti.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
