<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hawaii on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/hawaii/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hawaii on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/hawaii/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Power Of Timing In Donations</title>
      <link>/posts/the-power-of-timing-in-donations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/the-power-of-timing-in-donations/</guid>
      <description>This Dhamma talk discusses the key elements of the Kāladāna Sutta in addition to three personal stories that show how donations can miraculously come back to you. Some of the stories can be found at my website at this particular webpage below with pictures of the original items:&#xA;https://americanmonk.org/miracle-on-3-or-4-streets/&#xA;The video is below:&#xA;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Qy_h71a17Qo&#xA;Miracle On 3 or 4 Streets If you have ever wondered how monks survive on miracles when things go wrong, read on!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Traveling Without a Helper</title>
      <link>/posts/traveling-without-helper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/traveling-without-helper/</guid>
      <description>When Ven. Devananda and I traveled to Kauai in 2015, we did not have a Kappiya (helper) to buy us food or even pay for our luggage. One can live without helpers, but it does take some pre-planning.&#xA;We had a ticket from Yangon to Honolulu that was dirt cheap at only $854 for a round trip fare. However, it came with 12 hour and 6 hour layovers in China.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kauai Propagation Presentation</title>
      <link>/posts/kauai-propagation-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/kauai-propagation-presentation/</guid>
      <description>A 2 part Powerpoint presentation about what two monks did in Kauai, Hawaii during June to December 2015. The theme was propagation, but the propagation was done just from being monks who do not touch money, and collect their food the traditional Buddhist monk way. The vision, how it got started, stories and experiences were shared. About 50 people were in the audience. Running time is about 1 hour total for both.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kauai Slideshow</title>
      <link>/posts/704/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/704/</guid>
      <description>I recently made a Hawaii video slideshow. Here is the link. https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2DjEHWNTHQ0</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
