<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>forest-monastery on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/forest-monastery/</link>
    <description>Recent content in forest-monastery on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/forest-monastery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pa-Auk Monastery in Mudon</title>
      <link>/posts/pa-auk-monastery-mudon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/pa-auk-monastery-mudon/</guid>
      <description>Kyownpine Pa-Auk Branch Monastery in Mudon, Myanmar. I have moved to Yorgo Sayadaw &amp;rsquo;s new monastery called Kyownpine. The Yorgo Sayadaw read my first ordination transaction 15 years ago and invited me to come. He speaks no English, but we have fun together. Such a lovely place, lots of Metta here. Good views, cool at night (75 degrees), nice kuti. This place is suitable for foreigners to live at complete with proper vinaya (monks&amp;rsquo; rules).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pa-Auk Forest Monastery HD</title>
      <link>/posts/paaukhd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/paaukhd/</guid>
      <description>I made this video from 55 minutes of nearly silent footage. I cut it us and added a script to it. The titles in English are from the original and are misspelled in some areas. The monastery is more or less the same except a new health clinic which i had posted pictures of earlier. I finally got a higher resolution copy uploaded (in full) to YouTube, thanks to a wonderful Bhante who helped me upload it from the DVD Version.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
