<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>chanting on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/chanting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in chanting on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/chanting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Most Basic Pali Chants to Learn</title>
      <link>/posts/the-most-basic-pali-chants-to-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/the-most-basic-pali-chants-to-learn/</guid>
      <description>Myanmar Pali Script (credit at bottom link.. cc-sa-attrib)&#xA;There are many different Pāḷi chants to learn, yet I wanted to list the absolute basic chants that one should learn. If you are interested in Pāḷi chanting, these are the first to learn. The most basic and essential chants for beginning lay people should know are listed in order of importance:&#xA;Namo Tassa, Triple Gem with the 5 precepts, Bare bones Triple Gem chant of the 24 qualities of the Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Most Important Buddhist Lesson Learned and Taught</title>
      <link>/posts/most-important-buddhist-lesson-learned/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/most-important-buddhist-lesson-learned/</guid>
      <description>A little while ago, I was asked what was the most important lesson learned and what was the most important thing that I taught. The answer spans two different videos and they are listed below:&#xA;The first video gives a very technical answer, yet in very simple English that everyone can understand. However those who are into the deepest Dhamma and Abhidhamma will still appreciate what is said and how it is said.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Do Monks Say Grace Before Eating?</title>
      <link>/posts/monks-say-grace-eating/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/monks-say-grace-eating/</guid>
      <description>How Do Monks Say Grace Before Eating? Do Theravāda monks say anything before they eat? Do they give thanks? Who do they say thanks to? Or is it something else?&#xA;Buddhist monks generally do a reflection and chant something before eating. In fact it is said that the monks incurs debt if they doe not reflect before eating. Actually, there are 4 reflections concerning the Four Requisites:&#xA;1. Robes</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spoken Metta Mix by One Voice</title>
      <link>/posts/spoken-metta-mix-one-voice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/spoken-metta-mix-one-voice/</guid>
      <description>This is a spoken English version of the Discourse on Loving-Kindness (Metta Sutta), mixed with the Pāi chanting of One Voice (EkaSara). I like it and I think you will too. Enjoy! If you get a chance, It is best listened with headphones. There is quite a bit of stereophonic separation included. Feedback welcome. The audio is uploaded here.&#xA;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aMpSVv2ZdvI</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Blue Room Session and Update</title>
      <link>/posts/688/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/688/</guid>
      <description>I went to the sacred Blue Room cave today with a friend named Narayandass. Its waters are known for their healing powers. I made a recording of some chanting before we meditated there. It was a special time and extremely high on my &amp;ldquo;Before I Go&amp;rdquo; list. A recording can be found at https://archive.org/details/Blueroomkauai. The raw recording has nothing added but was trimmed at the beginning and end of the file.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our Bodhi Tree</title>
      <link>/posts/our-bodhi-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/our-bodhi-tree/</guid>
      <description>There is a Bodhi Tree on our property and we sometimes do a vandana (chanting) in front of this tree rather than at the gazebo. We did one tonight until a passing rain cloud sprinkled on us.&#xA;From Wikipedia: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bodhi_Tree The Bodhi Tree, also known as Bo (from Sinhalese: Bo) and &amp;ldquo;peepal tree&amp;rdquo; in Nepal and Bhutan, was a large and very old sacred fig tree (Ficus religiosa[1])[2] located in Bodh Gaya, India, under which Siddhartha Gautama, the spiritual teacher later known as Gautama Buddha, is said to have attained enlightenment, or Bodhi.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
