<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>teaching on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/teaching/</link>
    <description>Recent content in teaching on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/teaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why Do Monasteries Have Skeletons?</title>
      <link>/posts/why-do-monasteries-have-skeletons/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/why-do-monasteries-have-skeletons/</guid>
      <description>If you go to a Theravada Buddhist forest monastery in Asia, you are likely to find a full skeleton or parts of a skeleton somewhere where it can be viewed easily. Some monasteries also have cemeteries inside the boundary like Pa-Auk Forest Monastery in Mawlamyine. Some other monasteries have a place were dead bodies are burned (with open wood fires), right on the premises, like Pa-Auk Mawlamyine and also Wat Pa Nanachat in Thailand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18th Anniversary and Update</title>
      <link>/posts/18th-anniversary-and-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/18th-anniversary-and-update/</guid>
      <description>This is where I live&#xA;Wow! Today is February 7th and another year has passed. I have now completed 18 years total as a monk and I am working on my 19th year. Of course, my monk age is 12 rainy seasons because I changed Nikayas after my 6th year. I have been living my monk life in Kauai, Hawaii for about 10 months now and things have been moving along.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Secret Teachings of Theravāda</title>
      <link>/posts/the-secret-teachings-of-theravada/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/the-secret-teachings-of-theravada/</guid>
      <description>If there was a book that had all of the Secret Teachings of Theravāda, The Path of Purification (The Visuddhimagga) would be that book. It explains all the good stuff, like how to attain samādhi concentration; how to attain psychic powers including knowing and seeing the past lives. Lastly, it includes the stages of insight and wisdom that one needs to reach Nibbāna. Books do not get more complete than this.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vegetarianism and Theravada Buddhism</title>
      <link>/posts/vegetarianism-theravada-buddhism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/vegetarianism-theravada-buddhism/</guid>
      <description>Vegetarianism and Theravada Buddhism I have been asked to write a little something on vegetarianism and Theravāda Buddhism. I am qualified to be quite objective, and to see both sides of the issue because I was a vegetarian for a total of ten years as a lay person and I had vegetarian eyes. That meant that when I looked at meat, cooked or not, I saw a dead animal in front of me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inspire Means To Leave Facebook</title>
      <link>/posts/inspire-means-leave-facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/inspire-means-leave-facebook/</guid>
      <description>Inspire Means To Leave Facebook Much of what I write about is related to stories that happen to me that would charge me up and make me feel inspired. I would then write down what happened and share it with others. Often my stories are related to vinaya – the monks’ rules and living without money. These days it is special for a monk to live without money and I can inspire people simply by following the rules.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are You A Buddhist</title>
      <link>/posts/are-you-a-buddhist/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/are-you-a-buddhist/</guid>
      <description>Are You A Buddhist?&#xA;Introduction&#xA;Being a Buddhist is quite open because if you believe in certain aspects it is better than not believing in anything. We take what we can get. However, here are the more traditional aspects of being Buddhist. One should believe in The Triple Gem – ie**: The Buddha, The Dhamma and The Sangha).** This can be expanded to include The 4 Noble Truths. This can be expanded to include the Eightfold Noble Path as well.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Dark Side of Ajahn Mun&#39;s Biography</title>
      <link>/posts/dark-side-ajahn-mun/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/dark-side-ajahn-mun/</guid>
      <description>Ajahn Mun dark&#xA;Did Ajahn Mun say the Buddha congratulated him on the night he attained arahant? His biography books says it for sure.&#xA;Venerable Ācariya Mun Būridatta Thera is one of the most revered forest masters of the 20th century. He is the root guru of both the Dhammayut and Ajahn Chah monasteries. He popularized the monastic practice of living under an umbrella in the forest and his relentless energy is fascinating and inspiring.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does The Buddha live in Nibbana</title>
      <link>/posts/buddha-live-nibbana/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/buddha-live-nibbana/</guid>
      <description>The Buddha in the clouds&#xA;Does the Buddha Live in Nibbāna? Many people believe that the Buddha is alive and living in some sort of transcendental realm called Nibbāna where he can hear your prayers and eat and drink the food and water that you offer to Him. We Buddhist monks smile when we hear that people have such beliefs because nobody lives in Nibbāna, not even a Buddha.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
