<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>pa-auk-meditation-center on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/pa-auk-meditation-center/</link>
    <description>Recent content in pa-auk-meditation-center on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/pa-auk-meditation-center/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Living as a Monk in Myanmar During Covid and Government Change</title>
      <link>/posts/living-as-a-monk-in-myanmar-during-covid-and-government-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/living-as-a-monk-in-myanmar-during-covid-and-government-change/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Foreigner monk gets a COVID vaccine jab during the times of the new Myanmar government&#xA;In this article, I want to share with you some of my experiences of living as a monk in Myanmar during the covid pandemic and the government change that happened recently. I also want to explain why I left Myanmar at the end of 2022 and what I am doing now.&#xA;I am an American Buddhist monk who has been living in Myanmar for many years.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Water Purification</title>
      <link>/posts/water-purification/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/water-purification/</guid>
      <description>Water Purification Diagram&#xA;While the first step of meditation is called Sīlavisuddhi (Purification of morality), another important part of our monastery is the water purification system. We basically have our own industrial Reverse Osmosis water purification plant with enough capacity to supply a whole village with drinking water. However, since we normally have 500+ residents, we only supply our own monastery instead of going into business.&#xA;Ven Kāruṇika is one of the worker monks who keeps our water filtration machine in tip top condition, or shall we say &amp;ldquo;purerr-ing&amp;rdquo; ?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ajahn Brahmavamso&#39;s Dark Jhāna</title>
      <link>/posts/ajahn-brahmavamsos-dark-jhana/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/ajahn-brahmavamsos-dark-jhana/</guid>
      <description>Does Ajahn Brahmavamso Jhāna Have a Nimitta? Ajahn Brahmavamso (&amp;ldquo;Ajahn Brahm&amp;rdquo;) teaches about a samādhi nimitta. However, during jhāna, he says that there is no perception of light. He says that &amp;ldquo;The nimitta is the gateway to jhāna, but not the object of jhāna itself. Pīti or sukha are the objects of jhāna&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;If you follow Ajahn Brahm, this article will help you follow his teachings better. If you follow another method, this article will help you distinguish the difference.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>500&#43; monks at Pa-Auk Main. Some slippers go missing, but not these.</title>
      <link>/posts/500-monks-at-paauk-main/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/500-monks-at-paauk-main/</guid>
      <description>500+ monks at paauk main. Some slippers go missing so people mark them with different patterns as a passive way to prevent loss. However, the slippers in the center were not as passive. (Reposted and fixed lost picture from 2013)&#xA;Look at the writing on the slippers &amp;ldquo;No for Your&amp;rdquo; (Not for you).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I Ordained Twice</title>
      <link>/posts/why-i-ordained-twice/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/why-i-ordained-twice/</guid>
      <description>Many people who have learned that I have re-ordained and actually know what that means have asked me why I did it. It is a long story, but I will try to be brief. During my first ordination in 2001, at Pa-Auk Main Branch with Venerable Pa-Auk Sayadaw as my preceptor, I was asked 13 questions. According to tradition, every monk is asked these 13 qualifying questions in the ordination ceremony twice.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Back in Myanmar Headed to Pa-Auk Meditation Center</title>
      <link>/posts/back-in-myanmar-headed-to-paauk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/back-in-myanmar-headed-to-paauk/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_697&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignleft&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;1920&amp;rdquo;] From the pamc lookout[/caption]&#xA;I am back in Myanmar from Kauai, Hawaii. I will begin the Bus trip to Pa-Auk Meditation Center this morning. What a long transit back that was. Here is a picture taken from Pa-Auk Lookout point that friends and I had fun taking a while back. I will begin the Bus trip to Pa-Auk Meditation Center this morning.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
