<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>anger on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/anger/</link>
    <description>Recent content in anger on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/anger/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Three Stories Of Loving-kindness</title>
      <link>/posts/three-stories-of-loving-kindness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/three-stories-of-loving-kindness/</guid>
      <description>There are three stories of loving-kindness told in the video posted below. The first story is from Kaua&amp;rsquo;i, Hawai&amp;rsquo;i, when a person did not want me on &amp;ldquo;his&amp;rdquo; street. Through the power of loving-kindness, things changed. Another story was also from the island in 2015. There were children on bicycles who were yelling at us to go away on multiple days. Through the power of loving-kindness, things changed. The last story is from 2011 during a trip to India.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fighting Anger With Loving-Kindness and No Money</title>
      <link>/posts/fighting-anger-with-loving-kindness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/fighting-anger-with-loving-kindness/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I ran into a very angry man who came out of his house yelling at me and coming closer and closer. Eventually, I won the fight with my two big weapons, loving-kindness and my commitment of being free from money for all these years. I have been going for alms in this neighborhood for a little over a year now, and while I did have two girls yell at me, they did not leave their property boundary.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
