<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sri-lanka on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/sri-lanka/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sri-lanka on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/sri-lanka/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Brief Stay At Spring Hill Forest Monastery</title>
      <link>/posts/a-brief-stay-at-spring-hill-forest-monastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/a-brief-stay-at-spring-hill-forest-monastery/</guid>
      <description>The Wootens One of the few places I have been to in Sri Lanka besides Na-Uyana and The International Institute of Theravāda (IIT) is Spring Hill Forest Monastery located in the Hantanna Mountains above Kandy. My two donors from Kaua&amp;rsquo;i, John and Nandini Wooten were visiting Kandy and I decided it would be good to take a break from the IIT scenery and climate with a great inspirational place for the Wootens to visit me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Percentage of Monks Who Do Not Use Money</title>
      <link>/posts/percentage-of-monks-who-do-not-use-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/percentage-of-monks-who-do-not-use-money/</guid>
      <description>Monk walking towards the world of the 5%&#xA;If you are a Westerner and new to Buddhism, you might be surprised to learn that most monks use and handle money. I have calculated that around 95% use money while 5% do not use money. The general consensus of those I have consulted say that about 2 or 3 percent do not use money but I used a 5% number to be safe.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Piṇḍapāta:  Why Do Monks Go For Alms in a Village?</title>
      <link>/posts/why-go-for-alms-in-a-village-while-they-are-still-recovering-economic-crisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/why-go-for-alms-in-a-village-while-they-are-still-recovering-economic-crisis/</guid>
      <description>Alms Tray and Cambodia Monk&amp;rsquo;s Full Bowl&#xA;Introduction: This article explains the essence of piṇḍapāta (alms) and why we go for alms, even in poor villages. On the weekends, I have some time to go for alms in the nearby village. However, you might ask yourself, &amp;ldquo;Why would a monk collect food from a very poor village during an economic crisis when the monastery is mostly supported by wealthy people?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On The Way Back Home</title>
      <link>/posts/on-the-way-back-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/on-the-way-back-home/</guid>
      <description>Swedagon Pagoda, Myanmar&#xA;On November 4th, I left The States for Sri Lanka, Thailand and of course Myanmar which I now consider a home for myself. Shortly after the Buddhist Rainy Season had begun in Kaua’i, the support for inviting a second monk fell through and I was tired of being alone which meant I needed to leave.&#xA;Around the same time, in late July or early August, my Lao/American supporter named Thongvanh, sent me brochure with a monk who was leading a “Spiritual Sri Lanka Trip” which included the Sri Maha Bodhi Tree in Anuradhapura.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
