<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>samadhi on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/samadhi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in samadhi on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/samadhi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How To Be Human and Higher</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-be-human-and-higher/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/how-to-be-human-and-higher/</guid>
      <description>Sunrise behind clouds, free public domain CC0 image.&#xA;Many people want to go to Heaven or at least be born in human worlds but most people do not know what is needed to go there, let alone how to achieve enlightenment. Previously, in a previous article, I explained what happens after death according to the Theravāda teachings. If you have not read it, you really should. It explains the five causes for the five effects to arise (rebirth).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview: Monk Meditates for 24 Hours</title>
      <link>/posts/interview-monk-meditates-for-24-hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/interview-monk-meditates-for-24-hours/</guid>
      <description>Downloaded from https://www.needpix.com&#xA;Interview 1 of 2 Note: Some edits have been made afterwards to make things clear or to protect the anonymity of people.&#xA;I am sitting here now with one anonymous monk. He has sat for more than 24 hours in 4th jhāna and I wanted to interview him anonymously to inspire others. So we are here with Bhante (Note: All monks can be called “Bhante”).&#xA;I want to ask a few questions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When To Look At The Light</title>
      <link>/posts/when-to-look-at-the-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/when-to-look-at-the-light/</guid>
      <description>Is the light a Nimitta and when should one look at it?&#xA;When one practices meditation based on the breath, it is possible for the light to come and when that happens and it is stable one can use that light to enter samadhi absorption concentration. However, one should know when to look at the light and when not to look at the light. It is very important to know this difference because progress can stop.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acapella Inertia MP3 Audio</title>
      <link>/posts/acapella-inertia-mp3-audio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/acapella-inertia-mp3-audio/</guid>
      <description>A’capella Inertia Audio Story (free MP3 download)&#xA;[archiveorg id=acapellainertia]&#xA;I have decided to make an audio version of this story. I started off by having a computer read this for the purpose of proofreading. Then I started reading it out loud. As I read it out loud with my own natural expressions, I thought that it might be better if an audio version were available.&#xA;I happen to have access to a good quality microphone and some professional Linux software running on Elementary OS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Tale of Love and Samādhi Explained:  A&#39;capella Inertia</title>
      <link>/posts/tale-love-acapella-inertia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/tale-love-acapella-inertia/</guid>
      <description>A Tale of Love and Samādhi Explained: A’capella Inertia A little Valentines story for all of you. The topside title is just a description of what the story is generally about. However, the real title of the story is called, “A’capella Inertia.” This is not a short one, but I think you will like this one very much. It has received high marks and it will take about 30 minutes to read.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
