<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mawlamyine on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/mawlamyine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mawlamyine on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/mawlamyine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Video:  Knowing And Seeing Pa-Auk Forest Monastery</title>
      <link>/posts/video-knowing-seeing-pa-auk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/video-knowing-seeing-pa-auk/</guid>
      <description>From Knowing and Seeing Pa-Auk Forest Monastery video&#xA;In 2005 I made a video called, &amp;ldquo;Knowing and Seeing Pa-Auk Forest Monastery.&amp;rdquo; This is about the Pa-Auk Main Branch in Mawlamyine. Sayadawgyi was young back then and used to climb the stairs to his mountain kuti twice per day. I will miss that.&#xA;The title was meant to play with the name of Sayadawgyi&amp;rsquo;s famous book called, &amp;ldquo;Knowing and Seeing.&amp;rdquo; The book is referring to knowing and seeing the detailed Dhammas which were once thought impossible to know and literally &amp;ldquo;see&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pa-Auk Forest Monastery and Pa-Auk Sayadaw Shared Names</title>
      <link>/posts/pa-auk-monastery-and-sayadaw-shared-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/pa-auk-monastery-and-sayadaw-shared-names/</guid>
      <description>Pa-Auk Main Gate (cc-by-sa)&#xA;Pa-Auk Forest Monastery and Pa-Auk Sayadaw share the same names. Why is that?&#xA;Some people might question why Pa-Auk Forest Monastery and Venerable Pa-Auk Sayadaw have the same names. Did the Pa-Auk Sayadaw name his monastery after himself to immortalize his name? Is this an ego trip? What is the who, what, were, when, why, and how of this story?&#xA;Who? Venerable Pa-Auk Sayadawgyi (cc-by-sa)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Having Fun At The Pa-Auk Dentist Clinic</title>
      <link>/posts/having-fun-at-the-pa-auk-dentist-clinic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/having-fun-at-the-pa-auk-dentist-clinic/</guid>
      <description>Having Fun At The Pa-Auk Dentist Clinic (Repost/refurbish from June, 2015*)&#xA;Because dentists are very expensive in America and the Pa-Auk dental clinic has pretty good sanitary conditions (for Myanmar), I went for a checkup before my trip to Hawai&amp;rsquo;i. Usually in Asia, you only go to a dentist when there is pain but I had some sensitivity I wanted to get checked and I waited for the Saturday dentist who is known on the street as &amp;ldquo;the old retired dentist who takes his time and does a good job.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>500&#43; monks at Pa-Auk Main. Some slippers go missing, but not these.</title>
      <link>/posts/500-monks-at-paauk-main/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/500-monks-at-paauk-main/</guid>
      <description>500+ monks at paauk main. Some slippers go missing so people mark them with different patterns as a passive way to prevent loss. However, the slippers in the center were not as passive. (Reposted and fixed lost picture from 2013)&#xA;Look at the writing on the slippers &amp;ldquo;No for Your&amp;rdquo; (Not for you).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pa-Auk Monastery Alms Line in Myanmar</title>
      <link>/posts/pa-auk-monastery-alms-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/pa-auk-monastery-alms-line/</guid>
      <description>I recently found this video in my Google Drive. I had a layperson (probably UKZ) follow me around in the line to show what it was like for a monk to go through the alms food line at Pa-Auk Main Center, Mawlamyine, Myanmar. It is not easy to manage so many donors with big hearts to give. Most of the time, I am giving hand signals to get less food. You might want to play this at double speed.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
