<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>morality on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/categories/morality/</link>
    <description>Recent content in morality on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/categories/morality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Changing The Cloth: The Process To Become A Monk In Sri Lanka</title>
      <link>/posts/changing-the-cloth-the-process-to-become-a-monk-in-sri-lanka/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/changing-the-cloth-the-process-to-become-a-monk-in-sri-lanka/</guid>
      <description>A lay person named Chathuranga came to the International Institute of Theravāda looking to ordain in November, 2022. He is now a sāmaṇera (novice monk) and not yet a fully ordained bhikkhu. I thought that it would be interesting to show his path to monkhood to you.&#xA;Stage 1: Regular Person First he was a regular lay person working as a construction assistant engineer in the Maldives and then made the transition to a devoted layperson.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Buddhist Monk&#39;s Bowl</title>
      <link>/posts/the-buddhist-monks-bowl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/the-buddhist-monks-bowl/</guid>
      <description>Bowl with bowl stand (maybe Pa-Auk)&#xA;There are certain characteristics of the Theravada Buddhist monk&amp;rsquo;s bowl that might be interesting to know, even though the information is quite dry. Enjoy!&#xA;Material: The Buddha has allowed two different types of materials for bowls: iron and clay. When we say iron in Asia, we mean steel. Stainless steel is called steel. Is stainless steel allowed? This metal was not invented yet, but The Buddha left us with the great standards to judge if something should be allowable that was not mentioned during the time of the Buddha.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How To Be Human and Higher</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-be-human-and-higher/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/how-to-be-human-and-higher/</guid>
      <description>Sunrise behind clouds, free public domain CC0 image.&#xA;Many people want to go to Heaven or at least be born in human worlds but most people do not know what is needed to go there, let alone how to achieve enlightenment. Previously, in a previous article, I explained what happens after death according to the Theravāda teachings. If you have not read it, you really should. It explains the five causes for the five effects to arise (rebirth).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stay Away From the Fools and Associate with the Wise</title>
      <link>/posts/stay-away-from-the-fools-and-associate-with-the-wise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/stay-away-from-the-fools-and-associate-with-the-wise/</guid>
      <description>Sattigumba and Pupphaka&#xA;Asevanā ca bālānaṃ, paṇḍitānañca sevanā;&#xA;Pūjā ca pūjaneyyānaṃ etaṃ maṅgalamuttamaṃ.&#xA;Avoid the Fools and&#xA;Associate with the wise.&#xA;Give respect to the respectable.&#xA;This is the highest blessing.&#xA;Maṅgala Sutta&#xA;This small quote is from the first verse spoken by the Buddha when he was asked, &amp;ldquo;What is the highest blessing?&amp;rdquo; There are thirty-eight blessings listed and you can find them here. However, the first verse is the most important and we will only discuss the fools and the wise.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conversations With Christians</title>
      <link>/posts/conversations-with-christians/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/conversations-with-christians/</guid>
      <description>Every so often on my alms rounds, or here and there, I encounter Christians who approach me. Usually within the first sentence, they announce themselves as Christians to me as if they were holding a cross near to my face. However, I listen to their questions and give them answers. Many times they are trying to convince me my path is wrong and since it is a predictable pattern for them, I can anticipate what they will say, and put logic into their own path.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buddhist Monks&#39; Robes Information</title>
      <link>/posts/buddhist-monks-robes-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/buddhist-monks-robes-information/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1367&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;708&amp;rdquo;] Sewing pattern from BMC 1 (creative-commons, Thanissaro Bhikkhu)[/caption]&#xA;Robe Information Few people realize that the Theravāda monk’s robes are actually a piece of rectangular cloth with no sleeves.[mfn]While some monks use shirts with sleeves underneath their robes, it is not actually allowed [/mfn] If you see a Theravāda monk wearing his robes in different styles, then rest assured it is due to the art of “tying the robes” or “rolling the robes” or what I call “robe origami.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Collecting Alms (Piṇḍapāta) Legal?</title>
      <link>/posts/is-collecting-alms-pindapata-legal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/is-collecting-alms-pindapata-legal/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1264&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;708&amp;rdquo;] That is me going for alms on Aalona Street Kilauea.[/caption]&#xA;Collecting alms, also known as piṇḍapāta by Theravāda Buddhists, is a legal activity in the USA. There are some restrictions though. I spoke with a lawyer who seemed to know civil liberties quite well, but there are no guarantees with what I say. However, this information should make sense and seem legal to you. It is legal to ring the doorbell of any house and preach to them or talk to them about politics under the freedom of speech rights.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Are Most Monasteries Not Allowable?</title>
      <link>/posts/why-monasteries-not-allowable/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/why-monasteries-not-allowable/</guid>
      <description>Why are most monasteries not allowable for vinaya monks? Today, I was Skyping my parents which is something we do once or twice a month now. I feel it is good for them to &amp;ldquo;see&amp;rdquo; me as a monk, rather than having them talk to me and visualizing their son from 1999. That was when I left home and things changed for me. We had a nice discussion. We spoke about possibilities for a visit, but I told them that finding a place was difficult, because the monks all use money and whatever they buy with that money becomes unallowable.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inspiration, move me brightly</title>
      <link>/posts/inspiration-move-brightly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/inspiration-move-brightly/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_966&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;2048&amp;rdquo;] Alms[/caption]&#xA;Inspiration is like a bright star that shines among the dim. In Monastic life, there are few monasteries or monks that really inspire people. Following the vinaya (or rules) inspires people. It is tried and tested.&#xA;This was an old picture when I was in a vinaya monastery that follows all of the rules including the &amp;ldquo;basic ten rules&amp;rdquo; that a 7 year old beginner monk is supposed to follow.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5, 8 and 10 Precepts</title>
      <link>/posts/5-8-10-precepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/5-8-10-precepts/</guid>
      <description>Here is a comparison of 5, 8 and 10 precepts. The Buddhist who follows five precepts is known as a regular lay Buddhist. The person who follows 8 precepts is known as a serious Buddhist yogi. The person who follows the 10 precepts is known as a novice monk. A bhikkhu follows 227 rules.&#xA;It is important to know these classes to know which rules are more important to follow. It also can explain, what class of rules a monk is following.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buddhism and Abortion</title>
      <link>/posts/buddhism-and-abortion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/buddhism-and-abortion/</guid>
      <description>What do Theravada Buddhists believe in terms of abortion? Much of what has been written are liberal beliefs and overturning what is written down in the texts. They claim “Modern Buddhism” as a section heading, but there is no such thing as “Modern Buddhism” since there is no such thing as “Modern Kamma.” The rules of kamma do not change over time, and abortion has been around since the time of the Buddha.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
