<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>monk-life on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/monk-life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in monk-life on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/monk-life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Water Purification</title>
      <link>/posts/water-purification/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/water-purification/</guid>
      <description>Water Purification Diagram&#xA;While the first step of meditation is called Sīlavisuddhi (Purification of morality), another important part of our monastery is the water purification system. We basically have our own industrial Reverse Osmosis water purification plant with enough capacity to supply a whole village with drinking water. However, since we normally have 500+ residents, we only supply our own monastery instead of going into business.&#xA;Ven Kāruṇika is one of the worker monks who keeps our water filtration machine in tip top condition, or shall we say &amp;ldquo;purerr-ing&amp;rdquo; ?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Buddhist Monks Allowed To Use Money?</title>
      <link>/posts/are-buddhist-monks-allowed-to-use-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/are-buddhist-monks-allowed-to-use-money/</guid>
      <description>A Money tree in Laos cc-by-attrib-sa https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Buddhist_money_tree_with_toilet_paper.jpg&#xA;Are Buddhist monks allowed to use money? The short answer is that monks are definitely not allowed to even touch money for all traditions; Theravāda, Mahayāna, and Tibetan. However, it is very common for monks to not only accept money from lay people without shame, but they even encourage lay people to offer the money. Nevertheless, it is still a rule and there are heavy consequences if this becomes a lifetime habit and a wrong mode of livelihood.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Have You Eaten Yet?</title>
      <link>/posts/have-you-eaten-yet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/have-you-eaten-yet/</guid>
      <description>In 1993, I visited China with five lucky School of Technology students at my University. Before going, I asked around for some cool things to say and &amp;ldquo;Chī le ma?&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Have you eaten yet?&amp;rdquo; was the phrase I learned besides asking for the toilet. It does not mean what it literally says. Instead, it means a little bit like &amp;ldquo;How are you?&amp;rdquo;, but more casual like, &amp;ldquo;How&amp;rsquo;s it going?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Having Fun At The Pa-Auk Dentist Clinic</title>
      <link>/posts/having-fun-at-the-pa-auk-dentist-clinic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/having-fun-at-the-pa-auk-dentist-clinic/</guid>
      <description>Having Fun At The Pa-Auk Dentist Clinic (Repost/refurbish from June, 2015*)&#xA;Because dentists are very expensive in America and the Pa-Auk dental clinic has pretty good sanitary conditions (for Myanmar), I went for a checkup before my trip to Hawai&amp;rsquo;i. Usually in Asia, you only go to a dentist when there is pain but I had some sensitivity I wanted to get checked and I waited for the Saturday dentist who is known on the street as &amp;ldquo;the old retired dentist who takes his time and does a good job.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Most Important Buddhist Lesson Learned and Taught</title>
      <link>/posts/most-important-buddhist-lesson-learned/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/most-important-buddhist-lesson-learned/</guid>
      <description>A little while ago, I was asked what was the most important lesson learned and what was the most important thing that I taught. The answer spans two different videos and they are listed below:&#xA;The first video gives a very technical answer, yet in very simple English that everyone can understand. However those who are into the deepest Dhamma and Abhidhamma will still appreciate what is said and how it is said.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>September 11 and Jeremy Glick</title>
      <link>/posts/september-11-and-jeremy-glick/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/september-11-and-jeremy-glick/</guid>
      <description>September 11th and Jeremy Glick&#xA;I have a personal story I want to tell you about Jeremy Glick and September 11, 2001. The short story is that my name is Jeremy Glick and I was a computer programmer. However, I had left my regular world in 1999 and people who have lost track of me remembered me when 9/11 happened. About seven months after I ordained as a Buddhist Monk in 2001, the famous 9/11 or September 11th event happened.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kauai Update Part 2</title>
      <link>/posts/kauai-update-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/kauai-update-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Aloha!&#xA;It has been a little over a month since I have been on the island of Kauai. Things have been going well although my situation is still the same. I am still in a tent at Anini, but I have a new tent in Anini with a better view of the pristine Kauai shore! Things are dryer than the record rains we had last month.. and I guess if it were wetter than before a new record would be set.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kauai Update</title>
      <link>/posts/kauai-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/kauai-update/</guid>
      <description>Kauai Update April 22 Aloha! I have been in Kauai since April 9th. It has been a rough start but things are getting better everyday. If you have paid attention to the news, you may have noticed an unheard of 30&amp;quot; of rain in 24 hours. Actually, there were several days of incredible amounts of rain, but only the third day broke the records. See https:www.washingtonpost.com&#xA;I was in a tent in Anini Park during that time and I am still in Anini Park.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Tale of Love and Samādhi Explained:  A&#39;capella Inertia</title>
      <link>/posts/tale-love-acapella-inertia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/tale-love-acapella-inertia/</guid>
      <description>A Tale of Love and Samādhi Explained: A’capella Inertia A little Valentines story for all of you. The topside title is just a description of what the story is generally about. However, the real title of the story is called, “A’capella Inertia.” This is not a short one, but I think you will like this one very much. It has received high marks and it will take about 30 minutes to read.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Traveling Without a Helper</title>
      <link>/posts/traveling-without-helper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/traveling-without-helper/</guid>
      <description>When Ven. Devananda and I traveled to Kauai in 2015, we did not have a Kappiya (helper) to buy us food or even pay for our luggage. One can live without helpers, but it does take some pre-planning.&#xA;We had a ticket from Yangon to Honolulu that was dirt cheap at only $854 for a round trip fare. However, it came with 12 hour and 6 hour layovers in China.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Possessed!  A Halloween Special</title>
      <link>/posts/possessed-halloween-special/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/possessed-halloween-special/</guid>
      <description>There were a few times when I have seen some yogis and or monks go crazy. One time I saw a possession case when I went to a Kandy forest monastery called, Ulpathkandha. It means Sprint Hill Monastery.&#xA;I think it was 2010 when I went there. I wanted to use the Internet for the first time in a few years. I wanted to see what this Facebook thing was.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Finally Did It!</title>
      <link>/posts/i-finally-did-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/i-finally-did-it/</guid>
      <description>I Finally Did It! This Rainy Season (Vassa) I was able to learn the Pātimokkha (227 Rules) by heart. It is the first round and it takes me a long time to do it, and there are mistakes. Never the less, it is considered “learned” and “memorized” at this stage. I will hopefully recite the Pātimokkha for the full moon November 3rd if all goes well. I need to get my 2+ hours of recitation down to at least 1:15 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Do Monks Say Grace Before Eating?</title>
      <link>/posts/monks-say-grace-eating/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/monks-say-grace-eating/</guid>
      <description>How Do Monks Say Grace Before Eating? Do Theravāda monks say anything before they eat? Do they give thanks? Who do they say thanks to? Or is it something else?&#xA;Buddhist monks generally do a reflection and chant something before eating. In fact it is said that the monks incurs debt if they doe not reflect before eating. Actually, there are 4 reflections concerning the Four Requisites:&#xA;1. Robes</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Are Most Monasteries Not Allowable?</title>
      <link>/posts/why-monasteries-not-allowable/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/why-monasteries-not-allowable/</guid>
      <description>Why are most monasteries not allowable for vinaya monks? Today, I was Skyping my parents which is something we do once or twice a month now. I feel it is good for them to &amp;ldquo;see&amp;rdquo; me as a monk, rather than having them talk to me and visualizing their son from 1999. That was when I left home and things changed for me. We had a nice discussion. We spoke about possibilities for a visit, but I told them that finding a place was difficult, because the monks all use money and whatever they buy with that money becomes unallowable.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
