<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>vinaya on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/categories/vinaya/</link>
    <description>Recent content in vinaya on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/categories/vinaya/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Memorizing The Bhikkhunī Pātimokkha</title>
      <link>/posts/memorizing-the-bhikkhuni-patimokkha/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/memorizing-the-bhikkhuni-patimokkha/</guid>
      <description>Palm leaf photo link wellcomecollection:[mfn]CC 4.0 iiif.wellcomecollection.org/image/L0031774/full/760%2C/0/default.jpg[/mfn]&#xA;Today I finished memorizing the Bhikkhunī Pātimokkha in Pāḷi (the 311 Theravāda nun&amp;rsquo;s rules). While I did not recite the whole lot in a single session, I did memorize in chunks until the total was completely memorized at one time or another. That means, I would recite a chunk of rules in front of a teacher by memory and then work on a separate adjacent succeeding chunk for memory.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theravāda Buddhist Monk Head Shaving: Traditions, Stories, and Techniques</title>
      <link>/posts/monks-shaving-techniques-traditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/monks-shaving-techniques-traditions/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to shaving heads, Theravāda Buddhist Monks might be the authority on this issue. It is second nature for monks to shave but perhaps unknown to the rest of the world. In this article, we will discuss the motivation, Buddhist culture and methods for shaving the head and how it is done.&#xA;Simplicity Inspires But Also Saves Money: For those of you in the layperson world (man or woman) who aspire to become monks but cannot plunge into a monastery just yet, you might want to try cutting your hair very short before shaving it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Monks Allowed To Perform Marriage Ceremonies?</title>
      <link>/posts/are-monks-allowed-to-perform-marriages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/are-monks-allowed-to-perform-marriages/</guid>
      <description>Although Buddhist lay people might be interested in having a monk perform their marriage ceremony, it is not allowed and doing so is classed as a heavy rule (Saṅghādisesa). Such heavy rules have penalties and require the monk to lose his full status for a minimum of 6 nights[mfn]mānatta[/mfn] and additional probation time if concealing the offense occurs.&#xA;Image was created by AI DALL-E by openai. All participants do not exist in real life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Is The Bhikkhu Patimokkha or Buddhist Monk Rules?</title>
      <link>/posts/what-is-the-bhikkhu-patimokkha-or-buddhist-monk-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/what-is-the-bhikkhu-patimokkha-or-buddhist-monk-rules/</guid>
      <description>Pa Auk Monastery in 2014, Photo by Klaus&#xA;The Pātimokkha is a set of 227 rules for the bhikkhus belonging to the Theravāda sect which is based on the Pāḷi language texts. The 227 rules are grouped into seven classes with the first two, Pārājikā and Saṅghādisesā considered as &amp;ldquo;heavy&amp;rdquo;. The first heavy group is also considered irrecoverable while the second requires official transactions to restore the full bhikkhu status to the offender.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Buddhist Monk&#39;s Bowl</title>
      <link>/posts/the-buddhist-monks-bowl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/the-buddhist-monks-bowl/</guid>
      <description>Bowl with bowl stand (maybe Pa-Auk)&#xA;There are certain characteristics of the Theravada Buddhist monk&amp;rsquo;s bowl that might be interesting to know, even though the information is quite dry. Enjoy!&#xA;Material: The Buddha has allowed two different types of materials for bowls: iron and clay. When we say iron in Asia, we mean steel. Stainless steel is called steel. Is stainless steel allowed? This metal was not invented yet, but The Buddha left us with the great standards to judge if something should be allowable that was not mentioned during the time of the Buddha.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Buddhist Monks Allowed To Use Money?</title>
      <link>/posts/are-buddhist-monks-allowed-to-use-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/are-buddhist-monks-allowed-to-use-money/</guid>
      <description>A Money tree in Laos cc-by-attrib-sa https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Buddhist_money_tree_with_toilet_paper.jpg&#xA;Are Buddhist monks allowed to use money? The short answer is that monks are definitely not allowed to even touch money for all traditions; Theravāda, Mahayāna, and Tibetan. However, it is very common for monks to not only accept money from lay people without shame, but they even encourage lay people to offer the money. Nevertheless, it is still a rule and there are heavy consequences if this becomes a lifetime habit and a wrong mode of livelihood.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stay Away From the Fools and Associate with the Wise</title>
      <link>/posts/stay-away-from-the-fools-and-associate-with-the-wise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/stay-away-from-the-fools-and-associate-with-the-wise/</guid>
      <description>Sattigumba and Pupphaka&#xA;Asevanā ca bālānaṃ, paṇḍitānañca sevanā;&#xA;Pūjā ca pūjaneyyānaṃ etaṃ maṅgalamuttamaṃ.&#xA;Avoid the Fools and&#xA;Associate with the wise.&#xA;Give respect to the respectable.&#xA;This is the highest blessing.&#xA;Maṅgala Sutta&#xA;This small quote is from the first verse spoken by the Buddha when he was asked, &amp;ldquo;What is the highest blessing?&amp;rdquo; There are thirty-eight blessings listed and you can find them here. However, the first verse is the most important and we will only discuss the fools and the wise.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patheos Interview On Robes</title>
      <link>/posts/patheos-interview-on-robes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/patheos-interview-on-robes/</guid>
      <description>A couple of months ago, I was contacted by a professor of World Religions in the College of Religious Education at BYU named, Alonzo Gaskill. He had read my previous article on Buddhist Monk&amp;rsquo;s Robes Information and wanted to interview me for another Buddhist robes article for Patheos.com. We talked for quite a long time about Buddhism, my past, and why I ordained, and then the time was up. So we scheduled another call to talk about robes the next day to actually talk about the robes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patimokkha Chant Feb 15, 2022</title>
      <link>/posts/patimokkha-chant-feb-15-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/patimokkha-chant-feb-15-2022/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, I recited the 227 rules of the Pātimokkha for 110 bhikkhus at Pa-Auk Meditation Center in Pyin Oo Lwin. When a monk recites the Pātimokkha, traditionally he does so by memory and not by reading. My recitation was not the best quality, but it was not so bad considering I only started when I was 47, and I have only done this 5 times now. However, the recitations get better and better each time I do it and I hope improvement continues until perfection.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should Bhikkhunis Be Sent To Probation Monasteries?</title>
      <link>/posts/should-bhikkhunis-be-sent-to-probation-monasteries/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/should-bhikkhunis-be-sent-to-probation-monasteries/</guid>
      <description>Copyright notice.. picture by Kim Traynor cc-by-sa&#xA;Note: This post is not for everyone. Those who claim to be bhikkhunis and supporters of the movement, and monks and nuns in general will find this interesting.&#xA;Did you know that bhikkhunis (nuns) are not allowed to sleep alone or travel alone and if they do, they are sentenced to 2 weeks of rehabilitation and lose their full status as bhikkhunis during this period?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monk Towels and Soap</title>
      <link>/posts/soap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/soap/</guid>
      <description>Very few people from the West know about what the monks use for their bath towels and their bathing soap. Monks use items that are much different than those found in the West, although commonly known in Myanmar and other Buddhist countries. Furthermore, the monks use these items because of the monk rules associated with them in addition to the abundance and low cost.&#xA;Monks at Pa-Auk usually use small hand towels instead of normal &amp;ldquo;wrap-around&amp;rdquo; sized towels.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is an Overturned Bowl?</title>
      <link>/posts/what-is-an-overturned-bowl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/what-is-an-overturned-bowl/</guid>
      <description>Pa-Auk Bowl Blackening Foundry (not a political picture)&#xA;We have seen many Facebook selfies of politically active monks with their bowls turned upside down. What does this mean and is that proper?&#xA;The answer is: What you see on Facebook is not proper for monks or nuns. What you see on the news with monks and nuns as protesters is not proper. Overturning a bowl is an official Buddhist act, but what you have seen on Facebook and on the news are not official acts of overturning a bowl.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Long Do Monk&#39;s Robes Last?</title>
      <link>/posts/how-long-do-monks-robes-last/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/how-long-do-monks-robes-last/</guid>
      <description>Various items for Kaṭhina&#xA;It is quite common in Myanmar to offer robes at the end of the Rainy Season (vassa) in a ceremony called Kaṭhina. How long do monk&amp;rsquo;s robes last?&#xA;A monk normally has a set of three robes; a lower robe, an upper robe and a double robe sometimes referred to as the outer robe. During Kaṭhina, a set of robes are offered, but usually just the lower and upper robes since the double robe or outer robe lasts a long time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Monastery Murder Massacre</title>
      <link>/posts/monastery-murder-massacre/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/monastery-murder-massacre/</guid>
      <description>Artistic digital recreation of Migalaṇḍika (an ascetic who looked like a monk)&#xA;The Monastery Murder Massacre that happened in Vesālī during the time of The Buddha is not well known among lay people. It was because of this massacre that The Buddha made a rule about killing humans. For the first 20 years, there were no rules and this was the third rule that was ever created. Before this, the monks intuitively knew what was proper and there was no need for rules.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Theravada Bhikkhuni Ordinations Valid?</title>
      <link>/posts/are-theravada-bhikkhuni-ordinations-valid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/are-theravada-bhikkhuni-ordinations-valid/</guid>
      <description>cc0 picture https://pxhere.com/en/photo/489726&#xA;There is not much written in English explaining why bhikkhuni ordinations are rejected by the Theravāda Community of Monks. The English writings are a poor representation of the vast majority of Buddhist Scholarship and that is why there is &amp;ldquo;controversy&amp;rdquo; regarding the revival of the extinct Theravāda Bhikkhuni order. There is really no controversy to speak about once you know the full story.&#xA;Many Westerners believe that women are not able to become nuns without such a revival, but that is not true.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Does Rainy Season Start?</title>
      <link>/posts/when-does-rainy-season-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/when-does-rainy-season-start/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I got a nice message from a monk friend telling me he was taking vassa (3 month Rainy Season Retreat) on July 23rd (the Full Moon Day) and wishing me a happy vassa before he goes offline for three months. However, we at Pa-Auk are taking the vassa today on July 24 (the day after the Full Moon Day). The calendars often say it starts on the Full Moon Day, but we don&amp;rsquo;t do that at Pa-Auk.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Buddha&#39;s Intermittent Fasting</title>
      <link>/posts/the-buddhas-intermittent-fasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/the-buddhas-intermittent-fasting/</guid>
      <description>Did the Buddha do intermittent fasting? The answer is: Yes.&#xA;When I first became a monk, people were shocked about how I gave up eating after Solar Noon and I have not eaten dinner in over 20 years. Sometimes I switch to one meal per day, but I often find a light breakfast, mostly liquid foods or rice soup, with a full lunch works best for me. These days, many people are using intermittent fasting as a form of weight loss and when I describe my Buddhist monk diet, they give a nod and say &amp;ldquo;Intermittent Fasting&amp;hellip; It&amp;rsquo;s Healthy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Monks Get Married?</title>
      <link>/posts/can-monks-marry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/can-monks-marry/</guid>
      <description>cc0 picture&#xA;Recently, there have been some instances in the news of monks who have been accused of rape or consensual sex. One monk appears to have supported a child with his money. While we won&amp;rsquo;t know the true outcome until an admission of guilt is made, we should investigate what is a rule and what is not a rule. Although it is appalling that the Catholic church allows its priests to continue in the order even after such admissions of guilt for sexual acts, the Buddhist rules across all Buddhist schools have a different approach.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thanks and Giving</title>
      <link>/posts/thanks-and-giving/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/thanks-and-giving/</guid>
      <description>Of course I&amp;rsquo;m happy!&#xA;On November 24, I helped make a nice breakfast and lunch for Pa-Auk Forest Monastery, Pyin Oo Lwin. I organized 28 monks including myself to be the donors for the whole day meals + fresh squeezed apple juice, for a full value of 1,250,000 Myanmar Kyat. It fed approximately 530 yogis across four sections in Pa-Auk Forest Monastery. But how is that possible for monks to donate money?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Is Vassa (Rainy Season) Late Sometimes?</title>
      <link>/posts/why-is-vassa-rainy-season-late-sometimes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/why-is-vassa-rainy-season-late-sometimes/</guid>
      <description>Please note: this was written in 2020 but also applies to 2023. Vassa starts on August 1, 2023.&#xA;There seems to be confusion about when vassa is this year. This year is a special year and Vassa starts the day after the full moon day in August. The full moon day is August 3rd and Vassa starts on August 4th.&#xA;However, there are some traditions that believe that Vassa has already started with the full moon day of July 4th and Vassa on July 5th.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chicago Lao Monastery</title>
      <link>/posts/chicago-lao-monastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/chicago-lao-monastery/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I had a chance to go to a Lao Monastery in Elgin, Chicago, IL, USA for 12 days. I usually avoid American Theravada Temples like the plague because most of these places have monks who use money and much of the monk life is centered around collecting money. This is a typical standard not only in America but in most countries. This monastery however, is different.&#xA;In 2015, the committee decided to stop being a useless, unwholesome temple that teaches wrong dhammavinaya (teaching and training &amp;mdash; on wrong ways to give donation and wrong ways to make merit, and obviously wrong kamma and results).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I Ordained Twice</title>
      <link>/posts/why-i-ordained-twice/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/why-i-ordained-twice/</guid>
      <description>Many people who have learned that I have re-ordained and actually know what that means have asked me why I did it. It is a long story, but I will try to be brief. During my first ordination in 2001, at Pa-Auk Main Branch with Venerable Pa-Auk Sayadaw as my preceptor, I was asked 13 questions. According to tradition, every monk is asked these 13 qualifying questions in the ordination ceremony twice.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fighting Anger With Loving-Kindness and No Money</title>
      <link>/posts/fighting-anger-with-loving-kindness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/fighting-anger-with-loving-kindness/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I ran into a very angry man who came out of his house yelling at me and coming closer and closer. Eventually, I won the fight with my two big weapons, loving-kindness and my commitment of being free from money for all these years. I have been going for alms in this neighborhood for a little over a year now, and while I did have two girls yell at me, they did not leave their property boundary.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vinaya Comparison of Monastery Allowances</title>
      <link>/posts/vinaya-comparison-of-monastery-allowances/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/vinaya-comparison-of-monastery-allowances/</guid>
      <description>Below is a chart comparing special allowances by tradition which is useful for making a decision on where to ordain. If you need an explanation, read further..&#xA;There are some allowances and differences among traditions. I have included four traditions to the best of my knowledge about certain “allowances” that are allowed in some places and not allowed in other places. Who is right? Well, I believe that the two monasteries on the right (especially Wat Khao Sanamachai) are correct while other monks will believe that the monasteries on the left are correct.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Are Monk Bowls Black?</title>
      <link>/posts/why-are-monk-bowls-black/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/why-are-monk-bowls-black/</guid>
      <description>Monk bowls are black because they are fired with sesame oil 5 times to protect it from rusting. There are two types of bowls allowed; Iron and Clay. Iron bowls need to be fired 5 times and clay bowls only need firing twice. Obviously, the clay bowls do not need to be black in color but are rare to find because they are fragile and very very heavy. Iron bowls are black from the baked-on sesame oil.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why do monks have one shoulder exposed sometimes and both shoulders covered other times?</title>
      <link>/posts/why-do-monks-have-one-shoulder-exposed-sometimes-and-both-shoulders-covered-other-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/why-do-monks-have-one-shoulder-exposed-sometimes-and-both-shoulders-covered-other-times/</guid>
      <description>Why do monks have one shoulder exposed sometimes and both shoulders covered other times?&#xA;There is a very small rule about having the robes fully covered when we are in a populated areas (sekhiyā 3). Although it is a very small rule, it can say a great deal about the monk and his respect for the monastic code, especially in the afternoons or evenings.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Populated areas&amp;rdquo; refers to when we are outside of the monastery and outside of the forest.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buddhist Monks&#39; Robes Information</title>
      <link>/posts/buddhist-monks-robes-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/buddhist-monks-robes-information/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1367&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;708&amp;rdquo;] Sewing pattern from BMC 1 (creative-commons, Thanissaro Bhikkhu)[/caption]&#xA;Robe Information Few people realize that the Theravāda monk’s robes are actually a piece of rectangular cloth with no sleeves.[mfn]While some monks use shirts with sleeves underneath their robes, it is not actually allowed [/mfn] If you see a Theravāda monk wearing his robes in different styles, then rest assured it is due to the art of “tying the robes” or “rolling the robes” or what I call “robe origami.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Collecting Alms (Piṇḍapāta) Legal?</title>
      <link>/posts/is-collecting-alms-pindapata-legal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/is-collecting-alms-pindapata-legal/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1264&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;708&amp;rdquo;] That is me going for alms on Aalona Street Kilauea.[/caption]&#xA;Collecting alms, also known as piṇḍapāta by Theravāda Buddhists, is a legal activity in the USA. There are some restrictions though. I spoke with a lawyer who seemed to know civil liberties quite well, but there are no guarantees with what I say. However, this information should make sense and seem legal to you. It is legal to ring the doorbell of any house and preach to them or talk to them about politics under the freedom of speech rights.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should We Be Nice To Muslims?</title>
      <link>/posts/should-we-be-nice-to-muslims/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/should-we-be-nice-to-muslims/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1211&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;400&amp;rdquo;] Muslim Imam giving dana[/caption]&#xA;The short answer is, &amp;ldquo;Yes.&amp;rdquo; Of course we should be nice to Muslims, Christians, Atheist, animals, snakes and all beings. Sabbe Satta means all beings. In this long winded article, I speak about how the Muslims will win a majority in Myanmar and how Buddhism is already falling down in quality and quantity. Any &amp;ldquo;evil&amp;rdquo; actions like parochial schools, or large families were actually practiced in Myanmar by Buddhists only 20 or 30 years ago.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vegetarianism and Theravada Buddhism</title>
      <link>/posts/vegetarianism-theravada-buddhism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/vegetarianism-theravada-buddhism/</guid>
      <description>Vegetarianism and Theravada Buddhism I have been asked to write a little something on vegetarianism and Theravāda Buddhism. I am qualified to be quite objective, and to see both sides of the issue because I was a vegetarian for a total of ten years as a lay person and I had vegetarian eyes. That meant that when I looked at meat, cooked or not, I saw a dead animal in front of me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inspire Means To Leave Facebook</title>
      <link>/posts/inspire-means-leave-facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/inspire-means-leave-facebook/</guid>
      <description>Inspire Means To Leave Facebook Much of what I write about is related to stories that happen to me that would charge me up and make me feel inspired. I would then write down what happened and share it with others. Often my stories are related to vinaya – the monks’ rules and living without money. These days it is special for a monk to live without money and I can inspire people simply by following the rules.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Traveling Without a Helper</title>
      <link>/posts/traveling-without-helper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/traveling-without-helper/</guid>
      <description>When Ven. Devananda and I traveled to Kauai in 2015, we did not have a Kappiya (helper) to buy us food or even pay for our luggage. One can live without helpers, but it does take some pre-planning.&#xA;We had a ticket from Yangon to Honolulu that was dirt cheap at only $854 for a round trip fare. However, it came with 12 hour and 6 hour layovers in China.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Make a Monk Filter in 3 Minutes</title>
      <link>/posts/make-monk-filter-3-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/make-monk-filter-3-minutes/</guid>
      <description>Here is a quick tip on how to make a filter in just a few minutes. Maybe as fast as one minute. This is useful for monks who want to put filters on their water taps. It is my own invention as far as I know, but I am sure other monks somewhere else also do the same. The Buddha did mention that if we did not have a filter, we could use the corner of our robes (that we are wearing).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Finally Did It!</title>
      <link>/posts/i-finally-did-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/i-finally-did-it/</guid>
      <description>I Finally Did It! This Rainy Season (Vassa) I was able to learn the Pātimokkha (227 Rules) by heart. It is the first round and it takes me a long time to do it, and there are mistakes. Never the less, it is considered “learned” and “memorized” at this stage. I will hopefully recite the Pātimokkha for the full moon November 3rd if all goes well. I need to get my 2+ hours of recitation down to at least 1:15 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donation to Sangha or Individuals?</title>
      <link>/posts/donation-sangha-individuals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/donation-sangha-individuals/</guid>
      <description>When should you give to Saṅgha?&#xA;When should you give to individual monks?&#xA;This is a question that is not addressed very often and it can cause lots of trouble for monks knowingly and unknowingly. Quite often, many monks blindly prompt donors to recite a line of pāḷi before they offer anything to them. “Bhikkhu Saṅghassa demi.” There are some variations, but that is the generic formula. It means, “I give to the community of monks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making A Foot-Rug From Old Robes</title>
      <link>/posts/making-foot-rug-old-robes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/making-foot-rug-old-robes/</guid>
      <description>Here is an instructional video on how to make a foot-rug from old and discarded monk&amp;rsquo;s robes. If you are a monk, perhaps you will be very interested in this. I made the video as I was making my very first rug. Ven. Khemavamsa is the one who helped in the end. It was his idea and I have never seen this before. The story from the texts is below:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Are Most Monasteries Not Allowable?</title>
      <link>/posts/why-monasteries-not-allowable/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/why-monasteries-not-allowable/</guid>
      <description>Why are most monasteries not allowable for vinaya monks? Today, I was Skyping my parents which is something we do once or twice a month now. I feel it is good for them to &amp;ldquo;see&amp;rdquo; me as a monk, rather than having them talk to me and visualizing their son from 1999. That was when I left home and things changed for me. We had a nice discussion. We spoke about possibilities for a visit, but I told them that finding a place was difficult, because the monks all use money and whatever they buy with that money becomes unallowable.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Singing With My Bowl</title>
      <link>/posts/singwithbowl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/singwithbowl/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Singing With My Bowl&amp;rdquo; Today, after I Skyped my parents to say hello, I was doing my usual weekend schedule after: Go walking for alms, and then meditate at Swedo Paya (Tooth Relic Pagoda down the street from me). It is my favorite part of the week. It is where I can stop being a college student and be more like the monk I prefer to be. Near the end of my meditation in the Pagoda, a large Vietnam group came and did a chanting procession circumnavigating the inside of the pagoda.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shining The Inner Core</title>
      <link>/posts/shining-the-inner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/shining-the-inner/</guid>
      <description>To receive this by email, sign up at https://subhuti.withmetta.net/subscribe/&#xA;Last year, this picture (without the writing) went viral. The viral post seems to makes its rounds from time to time and every so often, someone tells me they saw my picture. It started when I was in Bagan for an 8 day trip with my friend Ashin Pannyagavesaka. We did a slow and thorough excursion and walked a good chunk of Bagan when rides were not provided.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inspiration, move me brightly</title>
      <link>/posts/inspiration-move-brightly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/inspiration-move-brightly/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_966&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;2048&amp;rdquo;] Alms[/caption]&#xA;Inspiration is like a bright star that shines among the dim. In Monastic life, there are few monasteries or monks that really inspire people. Following the vinaya (or rules) inspires people. It is tried and tested.&#xA;This was an old picture when I was in a vinaya monastery that follows all of the rules including the &amp;ldquo;basic ten rules&amp;rdquo; that a 7 year old beginner monk is supposed to follow.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5, 8 and 10 Precepts</title>
      <link>/posts/5-8-10-precepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/5-8-10-precepts/</guid>
      <description>Here is a comparison of 5, 8 and 10 precepts. The Buddhist who follows five precepts is known as a regular lay Buddhist. The person who follows 8 precepts is known as a serious Buddhist yogi. The person who follows the 10 precepts is known as a novice monk. A bhikkhu follows 227 rules.&#xA;It is important to know these classes to know which rules are more important to follow. It also can explain, what class of rules a monk is following.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buddhism and Abortion</title>
      <link>/posts/buddhism-and-abortion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/buddhism-and-abortion/</guid>
      <description>What do Theravada Buddhists believe in terms of abortion? Much of what has been written are liberal beliefs and overturning what is written down in the texts. They claim “Modern Buddhism” as a section heading, but there is no such thing as “Modern Buddhism” since there is no such thing as “Modern Kamma.” The rules of kamma do not change over time, and abortion has been around since the time of the Buddha.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lucky-Draw and Devas</title>
      <link>/posts/lucky-draw-devas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/lucky-draw-devas/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_902&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;948&amp;rdquo;] Calculation of odds.[/caption]&#xA;Do you believe in devas?&#xA;Devas are the Buddhist equivalent to angels. Ok .. Here is the story. I was on alms round two weeks ago and a regular supporter invited us to ask for anything for our studies at school. I needed some pens, so I asked for some pens. He told me to wait and showed up with a huge pen gift-box.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
