<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>5-precepts on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/5-precepts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 5-precepts on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/5-precepts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Buddhist Monk&#39;s Prayers For The Old And Sick</title>
      <link>/posts/buddhist-prayers-for-old-and-sick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/buddhist-prayers-for-old-and-sick/</guid>
      <description>India 2011&#xA;Can Buddhist Monks Pray For The Old And Sick?&#xA;Recently, a life long friend of the family has been diagnosed with lung cancer, a tough break because she is not a smoker. My mother asked me if I could say a prayer for her. I can, and have, but there was more to say about what I could do for her.&#xA;When I chant the Loving-kindness sutta for someone in person as a “blessing”, I usually explain what it means beforehand and then I chant it for them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theravada Buddhism and Sex: The Third Precept on Sexual Misconduct</title>
      <link>/posts/theravada-buddhism-and-sex-sexual-misconduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/theravada-buddhism-and-sex-sexual-misconduct/</guid>
      <description>NOTE: This is a very brief version of the 25 page PDF on the subject. The free 25 page pdf download on the third precept is here. Theravada Buddhism and Sex (extended)&#xA;Summary: The third precept is defined as not having sex without the protector&amp;rsquo;s permission. It is that simple! However, the protector can be the parents, husband, guardian, brother, government, religious order, etc. You need the protector&amp;rsquo;s permission and often that is the parents in most cases.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
