<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rules on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/rules/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rules on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/rules/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Memorizing The Bhikkhunī Pātimokkha</title>
      <link>/posts/memorizing-the-bhikkhuni-patimokkha/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/memorizing-the-bhikkhuni-patimokkha/</guid>
      <description>Palm leaf photo link wellcomecollection:[mfn]CC 4.0 iiif.wellcomecollection.org/image/L0031774/full/760%2C/0/default.jpg[/mfn]&#xA;Today I finished memorizing the Bhikkhunī Pātimokkha in Pāḷi (the 311 Theravāda nun&amp;rsquo;s rules). While I did not recite the whole lot in a single session, I did memorize in chunks until the total was completely memorized at one time or another. That means, I would recite a chunk of rules in front of a teacher by memory and then work on a separate adjacent succeeding chunk for memory.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Buddhist Monks Allowed To Use Money?</title>
      <link>/posts/are-buddhist-monks-allowed-to-use-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/are-buddhist-monks-allowed-to-use-money/</guid>
      <description>A Money tree in Laos cc-by-attrib-sa https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Buddhist_money_tree_with_toilet_paper.jpg&#xA;Are Buddhist monks allowed to use money? The short answer is that monks are definitely not allowed to even touch money for all traditions; Theravāda, Mahayāna, and Tibetan. However, it is very common for monks to not only accept money from lay people without shame, but they even encourage lay people to offer the money. Nevertheless, it is still a rule and there are heavy consequences if this becomes a lifetime habit and a wrong mode of livelihood.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should Bhikkhunis Be Sent To Probation Monasteries?</title>
      <link>/posts/should-bhikkhunis-be-sent-to-probation-monasteries/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/should-bhikkhunis-be-sent-to-probation-monasteries/</guid>
      <description>Copyright notice.. picture by Kim Traynor cc-by-sa&#xA;Note: This post is not for everyone. Those who claim to be bhikkhunis and supporters of the movement, and monks and nuns in general will find this interesting.&#xA;Did you know that bhikkhunis (nuns) are not allowed to sleep alone or travel alone and if they do, they are sentenced to 2 weeks of rehabilitation and lose their full status as bhikkhunis during this period?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buddhist Monks&#39; Robes Information</title>
      <link>/posts/buddhist-monks-robes-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/buddhist-monks-robes-information/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1367&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;708&amp;rdquo;] Sewing pattern from BMC 1 (creative-commons, Thanissaro Bhikkhu)[/caption]&#xA;Robe Information Few people realize that the Theravāda monk’s robes are actually a piece of rectangular cloth with no sleeves.[mfn]While some monks use shirts with sleeves underneath their robes, it is not actually allowed [/mfn] If you see a Theravāda monk wearing his robes in different styles, then rest assured it is due to the art of “tying the robes” or “rolling the robes” or what I call “robe origami.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buddhism and Abortion</title>
      <link>/posts/buddhism-and-abortion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/buddhism-and-abortion/</guid>
      <description>What do Theravada Buddhists believe in terms of abortion? Much of what has been written are liberal beliefs and overturning what is written down in the texts. They claim “Modern Buddhism” as a section heading, but there is no such thing as “Modern Buddhism” since there is no such thing as “Modern Kamma.” The rules of kamma do not change over time, and abortion has been around since the time of the Buddha.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
