<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>buddhism on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/buddhism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in buddhism on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/buddhism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Buddhism and Lists</title>
      <link>/posts/buddhism-and-lists/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/buddhism-and-lists/</guid>
      <description>Buddha by Numbers&#xA;Introduction The Buddhist teachings are often organized by various lists. Various matrices of interlinked lists to organize the teachings are one of the distinctive features of Buddhism. In my studies, I find myself learning many different types of lists for memory. By doing so, I can see the benefit and how they can be expanded and interlinked. While it may seem like dry minutia and uninteresting at first glance, the lists run very deep when you start to understand how the whole system works.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Is Halloween Bad According To Theravada Buddhism?</title>
      <link>/posts/why-is-halloween-bad-according-to-theravada-buddhism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/why-is-halloween-bad-according-to-theravada-buddhism/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: While I&amp;rsquo;m sure most religions do not particularly like the tradition of Halloween, I thought it would be good to explain why Halloween is not good according to Theravāda Buddhism.&#xA;Celebrating Halloween in modern times, regardless of the reasons why it was started in the first place, consists of dressing up in costumes. In celebration, you either dress up or you praise other people&amp;rsquo;s costumes. It is mostly bad karma for the one dressing up and if you praise that, it is not good either.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buddhism:  What Happens After Death?</title>
      <link>/posts/buddhism-what-happens-after-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/buddhism-what-happens-after-death/</guid>
      <description>https://unsplash.com/photos/j3R9C-Xqe1w&#xA;Warning: This is a long but clear and interesting religious post on what happens after death according to Classical Theravāda Buddhism.&#xA;Key Points: The Fully Enlightened do not take a rebirth after death. Immediate rebirth takes place after the death moment for all other beings. Kamma is what determines your next birth Lifetime and Momentary suffering Be careful what you wish for There is no such thing as a guaranteed intermediate stage (Bardo Plane).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Abhidhamma Lessons: A Top-Down Approach Using Computer Science</title>
      <link>/posts/abhidhamma-lessons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/abhidhamma-lessons/</guid>
      <description>Free Book: Abhidhamma Lessons PDF Download Abhidhamma Lessons PDF Here is a book I wrote long ago that relates the Abhidhamma to Computer Science. As a programmer from the nineties, I &amp;ldquo;clicked&amp;rdquo; with the abhidhamma after reading just a small amount. When I learned that the mind does only one thing at a time, it instantly clicked with a graduate class I had taken on digital circuits. It gave me the faith in the Abhidhamma early on which is very rare among Western Monks and Western Theravada Buddhist lay people.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>September 11 and Jeremy Glick</title>
      <link>/posts/september-11-and-jeremy-glick/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/september-11-and-jeremy-glick/</guid>
      <description>September 11th and Jeremy Glick&#xA;I have a personal story I want to tell you about Jeremy Glick and September 11, 2001. The short story is that my name is Jeremy Glick and I was a computer programmer. However, I had left my regular world in 1999 and people who have lost track of me remembered me when 9/11 happened. About seven months after I ordained as a Buddhist Monk in 2001, the famous 9/11 or September 11th event happened.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Collecting Alms (Piṇḍapāta) Legal?</title>
      <link>/posts/is-collecting-alms-pindapata-legal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/is-collecting-alms-pindapata-legal/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1264&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;708&amp;rdquo;] That is me going for alms on Aalona Street Kilauea.[/caption]&#xA;Collecting alms, also known as piṇḍapāta by Theravāda Buddhists, is a legal activity in the USA. There are some restrictions though. I spoke with a lawyer who seemed to know civil liberties quite well, but there are no guarantees with what I say. However, this information should make sense and seem legal to you. It is legal to ring the doorbell of any house and preach to them or talk to them about politics under the freedom of speech rights.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vegetarianism and Theravada Buddhism</title>
      <link>/posts/vegetarianism-theravada-buddhism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/vegetarianism-theravada-buddhism/</guid>
      <description>Vegetarianism and Theravada Buddhism I have been asked to write a little something on vegetarianism and Theravāda Buddhism. I am qualified to be quite objective, and to see both sides of the issue because I was a vegetarian for a total of ten years as a lay person and I had vegetarian eyes. That meant that when I looked at meat, cooked or not, I saw a dead animal in front of me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are You A Buddhist</title>
      <link>/posts/are-you-a-buddhist/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/are-you-a-buddhist/</guid>
      <description>Are You A Buddhist?&#xA;Introduction&#xA;Being a Buddhist is quite open because if you believe in certain aspects it is better than not believing in anything. We take what we can get. However, here are the more traditional aspects of being Buddhist. One should believe in The Triple Gem – ie**: The Buddha, The Dhamma and The Sangha).** This can be expanded to include The 4 Noble Truths. This can be expanded to include the Eightfold Noble Path as well.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does The Buddha live in Nibbana</title>
      <link>/posts/buddha-live-nibbana/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/buddha-live-nibbana/</guid>
      <description>The Buddha in the clouds&#xA;Does the Buddha Live in Nibbāna? Many people believe that the Buddha is alive and living in some sort of transcendental realm called Nibbāna where he can hear your prayers and eat and drink the food and water that you offer to Him. We Buddhist monks smile when we hear that people have such beliefs because nobody lives in Nibbāna, not even a Buddha.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spoken Metta Mix by One Voice</title>
      <link>/posts/spoken-metta-mix-one-voice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/spoken-metta-mix-one-voice/</guid>
      <description>This is a spoken English version of the Discourse on Loving-Kindness (Metta Sutta), mixed with the Pāi chanting of One Voice (EkaSara). I like it and I think you will too. Enjoy! If you get a chance, It is best listened with headphones. There is quite a bit of stereophonic separation included. Feedback welcome. The audio is uploaded here.&#xA;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aMpSVv2ZdvI</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buddhism and Abortion</title>
      <link>/posts/buddhism-and-abortion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/buddhism-and-abortion/</guid>
      <description>What do Theravada Buddhists believe in terms of abortion? Much of what has been written are liberal beliefs and overturning what is written down in the texts. They claim “Modern Buddhism” as a section heading, but there is no such thing as “Modern Buddhism” since there is no such thing as “Modern Kamma.” The rules of kamma do not change over time, and abortion has been around since the time of the Buddha.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
