<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dhammapada on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/dhammapada/</link>
    <description>Recent content in dhammapada on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/dhammapada/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How The Buddha&#39;s Teachings Saved Japan</title>
      <link>/posts/how-the-buddhas-teachings-saved-japan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/how-the-buddhas-teachings-saved-japan/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: There was a moment in world history where the Buddha&amp;rsquo;s teachings greatly affected world diplomacy during the Peace Treaty of 1951. We can learn from this type of history and apply the solution in our daily lives. In short, we can stop hatred with loving-kindness.&#xA;President J.R. Jayewardene of Sri Lanka exits from a helicopter and walks to his airplane for departure after a state visit.&#xA;If you look at the history of the San Francisco Treaty of 1951, you will see that it officially negotiated the end of the war crimes with Japan from WWII.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Most Common Dhammapāda Chants</title>
      <link>/posts/the-most-common-dhammapada-chants/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/the-most-common-dhammapada-chants/</guid>
      <description>CC BY-SA 2.5, https://commons.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?curid=190448&#xA;The most popular Buddhist book is the Dhammapada which contains 423 poetic verses in the Pāḷi language. What are the most popular verses? While there are some classic chants and everyone has favorites, nothing compares to what the monks chant and what is found in most chanting books. Here are the chants that are integrated into many different traditions and usually chanted after the pātimokkha.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
