<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>metta on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/metta/</link>
    <description>Recent content in metta on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/metta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Today I Saved A Cockroach</title>
      <link>/posts/today-i-saved-a-cockroach/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/today-i-saved-a-cockroach/</guid>
      <description>https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Amerikanische_Gro%C3%9Fschabe_1.JPG&#xA;Today I saved an upside down cockroach in my bathroom. I thought he was dead but then saw that he was still alive and moving. I was late for breakfast and decided I would save him after I came back, but I became very overwhelmed with guilt 10 seconds later and could not go further. So I grabbed a tissue and picked him up with care knowing not to squeeze too hard.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sabbe Satta -All Beings</title>
      <link>/posts/sabbe-satta-all-beings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/sabbe-satta-all-beings/</guid>
      <description>reposted from https://withmetta.net (2016) . When a Buddhist monk says “sabbe satta,” that is a shorthand for metta practice. “Sabbe satta” means “all beings.”&#xA;One of my friend’s collects the leftover food and cakes and says or acts on this everyday after each meal at the Mudon Pa-Auk monastery. But in reality, even though he says “sabbe satta,” he really just seems to feed the birds with the leftover food and cakes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making Helmut Schmidt’s Day</title>
      <link>/posts/making-helmut-schmidts-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/making-helmut-schmidts-day/</guid>
      <description>A Story from 1993 from my college days, before the Internet was around.&#xA;I remember all the way back in &amp;lsquo;93, when I was in college and I had just spent a few weeks in China for an academic scholarship. Because I was now some type of &amp;ldquo;International&amp;rdquo; student, I was asked to attend a &amp;ldquo;lunch hour&amp;rdquo; question and answer session with Helmut Schmitt. Although I had international travel experience, I was hardly experienced in “international issues,” and I did not even know who or what he was.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Blue Room Session and Update</title>
      <link>/posts/688/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/688/</guid>
      <description>I went to the sacred Blue Room cave today with a friend named Narayandass. Its waters are known for their healing powers. I made a recording of some chanting before we meditated there. It was a special time and extremely high on my &amp;ldquo;Before I Go&amp;rdquo; list. A recording can be found at https://archive.org/details/Blueroomkauai. The raw recording has nothing added but was trimmed at the beginning and end of the file.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
