<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dhamma-talk on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/dhamma-talk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in dhamma-talk on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/dhamma-talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Planting Wisdom: Reflections on the Cūḷakammavibhaṅga Sutta and a Meditation Journey</title>
      <link>/posts/planting-wisdom-reflections-on-the-cu%E1%B8%B7akammavibha%E1%B9%85ga-sutta-and-a-meditation-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/planting-wisdom-reflections-on-the-cu%E1%B8%B7akammavibha%E1%B9%85ga-sutta-and-a-meditation-journey/</guid>
      <description>In this talk, I explore the Cūḷakammavibhaṅga Sutta and share the story of reconnecting with my first meditation teacher after nearly two decades. The focus is on the seeds of kamma that we plant continuously through our actions. What kind of seeds are we planting right now?&#xA;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Iq7LED3zIJo&#xA;The Seeds From Long Ago The Seeds From Long Ago I remember when I first learned how to meditate on my breath some time in 1990, during my university years.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dhamma Talk Princeville August 19 2018</title>
      <link>/posts/dhamma-talk-princeville-august-19-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/dhamma-talk-princeville-august-19-2018/</guid>
      <description>With only 5 minutes left before we were supposed to start, the security guard told us that someone else had the room booked and we would need to move to a smaller amd inferior room. It was a mistake on their part, and while I did ask to see the schedule book, I opted out because we were running out of time and needed to setup the room again. It was disturbing and noisy, but we had to make the best of it.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
