<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>video on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/video/</link>
    <description>Recent content in video on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/video/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Video:  Knowing And Seeing Pa-Auk Forest Monastery</title>
      <link>/posts/video-knowing-seeing-pa-auk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/video-knowing-seeing-pa-auk/</guid>
      <description>From Knowing and Seeing Pa-Auk Forest Monastery video&#xA;In 2005 I made a video called, &amp;ldquo;Knowing and Seeing Pa-Auk Forest Monastery.&amp;rdquo; This is about the Pa-Auk Main Branch in Mawlamyine. Sayadawgyi was young back then and used to climb the stairs to his mountain kuti twice per day. I will miss that.&#xA;The title was meant to play with the name of Sayadawgyi&amp;rsquo;s famous book called, &amp;ldquo;Knowing and Seeing.&amp;rdquo; The book is referring to knowing and seeing the detailed Dhammas which were once thought impossible to know and literally &amp;ldquo;see&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Memorizing The Noble Eightfold Path</title>
      <link>/posts/memorizing-the-noble-eightfold-path/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/memorizing-the-noble-eightfold-path/</guid>
      <description>I took a small poll among seasoned Buddhists to see who could list all eight factors of The Noble Eightfold Path in English from memory and not many did so well. How can one follow a Path that one does not know? These factors should be said to oneself daily if one truly wishes to walk on the Path. To help with Buddhist literacy, I made a basic video that helps people memorize The Noble Eightfold Path in English.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pa-Auk Forest Monastery HD</title>
      <link>/posts/paaukhd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/paaukhd/</guid>
      <description>I made this video from 55 minutes of nearly silent footage. I cut it us and added a script to it. The titles in English are from the original and are misspelled in some areas. The monastery is more or less the same except a new health clinic which i had posted pictures of earlier. I finally got a higher resolution copy uploaded (in full) to YouTube, thanks to a wonderful Bhante who helped me upload it from the DVD Version.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
