<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>morality on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/morality/</link>
    <description>Recent content in morality on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/morality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Conversations With Christians</title>
      <link>/posts/conversations-with-christians/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/conversations-with-christians/</guid>
      <description>Every so often on my alms rounds, or here and there, I encounter Christians who approach me. Usually within the first sentence, they announce themselves as Christians to me as if they were holding a cross near to my face. However, I listen to their questions and give them answers. Many times they are trying to convince me my path is wrong and since it is a predictable pattern for them, I can anticipate what they will say, and put logic into their own path.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theravada Buddhism and Sex: The Third Precept on Sexual Misconduct</title>
      <link>/posts/theravada-buddhism-and-sex-sexual-misconduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/theravada-buddhism-and-sex-sexual-misconduct/</guid>
      <description>NOTE: This is a very brief version of the 25 page PDF on the subject. The free 25 page pdf download on the third precept is here. Theravada Buddhism and Sex (extended)&#xA;Summary: The third precept is defined as not having sex without the protector&amp;rsquo;s permission. It is that simple! However, the protector can be the parents, husband, guardian, brother, government, religious order, etc. You need the protector&amp;rsquo;s permission and often that is the parents in most cases.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5, 8 and 10 Precepts</title>
      <link>/posts/5-8-10-precepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/5-8-10-precepts/</guid>
      <description>Here is a comparison of 5, 8 and 10 precepts. The Buddhist who follows five precepts is known as a regular lay Buddhist. The person who follows 8 precepts is known as a serious Buddhist yogi. The person who follows the 10 precepts is known as a novice monk. A bhikkhu follows 227 rules.&#xA;It is important to know these classes to know which rules are more important to follow. It also can explain, what class of rules a monk is following.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
