<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>myanmar on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/myanmar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in myanmar on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/myanmar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Percentage of Monks Who Do Not Use Money</title>
      <link>/posts/percentage-of-monks-who-do-not-use-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/percentage-of-monks-who-do-not-use-money/</guid>
      <description>Monk walking towards the world of the 5%&#xA;If you are a Westerner and new to Buddhism, you might be surprised to learn that most monks use and handle money. I have calculated that around 95% use money while 5% do not use money. The general consensus of those I have consulted say that about 2 or 3 percent do not use money but I used a 5% number to be safe.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making Natural Brooms</title>
      <link>/posts/making-natural-brooms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/making-natural-brooms/</guid>
      <description>Sayadaw holding one of his finished brooms&#xA;Natural fiber brooms are quite common in Theravadan countries such as Myanmar, Thailand, Sri Lanka, Cambodia, and Laos. Since the plants that are used to make brooms grow in our monastery, one of our very senior monks takes pleasure in making brooms when he needs to stretch his legs after a long meditation. It is strange, but since our main job is to meditate, working can be a leisure activity!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monk Towels and Soap</title>
      <link>/posts/soap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/soap/</guid>
      <description>Very few people from the West know about what the monks use for their bath towels and their bathing soap. Monks use items that are much different than those found in the West, although commonly known in Myanmar and other Buddhist countries. Furthermore, the monks use these items because of the monk rules associated with them in addition to the abundance and low cost.&#xA;Monks at Pa-Auk usually use small hand towels instead of normal &amp;ldquo;wrap-around&amp;rdquo; sized towels.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Covid-19 Lockdown @ Pa-Auk</title>
      <link>/posts/covid-19-lockdown-pa-auk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/covid-19-lockdown-pa-auk/</guid>
      <description>Going for Alms at Pa-Auk&#xA;The world has has begun to know about Covid-19 and unfortunately, some countries know it better than others. As a monk, I try to stay away from basic web internet except one day per week, but I still hear what goes on and as of today, April 6th, 2020, Myanmar has 21 cases and one death. The number grows slowly in the beginning as you all might know and it is uncertain what will become of the virus in weeks to come.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pa-Auk Monastery Alms Line in Myanmar</title>
      <link>/posts/pa-auk-monastery-alms-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/pa-auk-monastery-alms-line/</guid>
      <description>I recently found this video in my Google Drive. I had a layperson (probably UKZ) follow me around in the line to show what it was like for a monk to go through the alms food line at Pa-Auk Main Center, Mawlamyine, Myanmar. It is not easy to manage so many donors with big hearts to give. Most of the time, I am giving hand signals to get less food. You might want to play this at double speed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Koral Inspires Me</title>
      <link>/posts/koral-inspires-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/koral-inspires-me/</guid>
      <description>Koral&amp;rsquo;s Family&#xA;Just about every Wednesday, I still find the time to continue with my Kilauea alms round[mfn]map is here[/mfn] (which used to include Tuesdays too). I take a one hour bus ride from Lihue, and then set out on my alms round, wishing loving-kindness to the houses one by one as I walk along the road.&#xA;In the beginning people thought I was some weird homeless person who might be crazy, but after some time, some fearless people spoke to me and then word started spreading.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kauai Update: Lihue</title>
      <link>/posts/kauai-update-lihue/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/kauai-update-lihue/</guid>
      <description>All-focus&#xA;Things have recently changed&#xA;Things have recently changed in my life. I have now moved to Lihue. Things were going well at the place where I was at before in Kilauea. The owner was happy with what I was doing for the community and I was happy and fulfilled with what I was doing for the community as well. Unfortunately, the owner&amp;rsquo;s son came for a visit. In short, he said, &amp;ldquo;I want to visit a monk.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should We Be Nice To Muslims?</title>
      <link>/posts/should-we-be-nice-to-muslims/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/should-we-be-nice-to-muslims/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1211&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;400&amp;rdquo;] Muslim Imam giving dana[/caption]&#xA;The short answer is, &amp;ldquo;Yes.&amp;rdquo; Of course we should be nice to Muslims, Christians, Atheist, animals, snakes and all beings. Sabbe Satta means all beings. In this long winded article, I speak about how the Muslims will win a majority in Myanmar and how Buddhism is already falling down in quality and quantity. Any &amp;ldquo;evil&amp;rdquo; actions like parochial schools, or large families were actually practiced in Myanmar by Buddhists only 20 or 30 years ago.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shining The Inner Core</title>
      <link>/posts/shining-the-inner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/shining-the-inner/</guid>
      <description>To receive this by email, sign up at https://subhuti.withmetta.net/subscribe/&#xA;Last year, this picture (without the writing) went viral. The viral post seems to makes its rounds from time to time and every so often, someone tells me they saw my picture. It started when I was in Bagan for an 8 day trip with my friend Ashin Pannyagavesaka. We did a slow and thorough excursion and walked a good chunk of Bagan when rides were not provided.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lucky-Draw and Devas</title>
      <link>/posts/lucky-draw-devas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/lucky-draw-devas/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_902&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;948&amp;rdquo;] Calculation of odds.[/caption]&#xA;Do you believe in devas?&#xA;Devas are the Buddhist equivalent to angels. Ok .. Here is the story. I was on alms round two weeks ago and a regular supporter invited us to ask for anything for our studies at school. I needed some pens, so I asked for some pens. He told me to wait and showed up with a huge pen gift-box.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Different Love Trumps Hate</title>
      <link>/posts/different-love-trumps-hate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/different-love-trumps-hate/</guid>
      <description>This video clip below came my way and I would hate to say that not only is this guy is correct right near the end of his talk, but he is expressing the same thoughts as the Buddha and myself&amp;hellip;well, at least the last part. This link will skip over to 3 minutes 38 seconds. Remainder running time is about 2 minutes. NOTE: There is more I say below after this video: https://www.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Open Letter to Ma Ba Tha</title>
      <link>/posts/open-letter-ma-ba-tha/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/open-letter-ma-ba-tha/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_793&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;1200&amp;rdquo;] Top: Ma Ba Tha conference Bottom: Reaching out to Muslims to show loving-kindness[/caption]&#xA;Recently, I was convinced to go to a “seminar on peace” this past Saturday. Some of you may have seen my picture on Facebook in regards to a Ma Ba Tha conference I attended. I was told that I should not pay attention to the negative press and that they are a peaceful organization and the gathering was about peace.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visit to Varanasi Monastery, Mingaladon</title>
      <link>/posts/visit-varanasi-monastery-mingaladon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/visit-varanasi-monastery-mingaladon/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_786&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;764&amp;rdquo;] Sima of Varanasi Monastery[/caption]&#xA;A Brief Visit to Varanasi Monastery, Mingaladon&#xA;I had a few more days before I was allowed to arrive at ITBM University (I am there now). Very close by is one of my favorite monasteries in the Yangon District. Actually, there are very few choices for monks who follow the monk’s rules (Vinaya) if you want to live with like minded vinaya monks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>License to Spill   (Myanmar Thingyan, New Year)</title>
      <link>/posts/license-to-spill/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/license-to-spill/</guid>
      <description>In the eight plus years that I have lived in Myanmar, I have never seen the Thingyan Water Festival festivities happening in the street. I normally spend my time in the monastery and normally, if I went on alms, it would be early in the morning. However, our Kyownpine monastery goes out on alms round a little later so we can collect real food to actually eat a little bit easier (so the donors have time to cook).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pa-Auk Monastery in Mudon</title>
      <link>/posts/pa-auk-monastery-mudon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/pa-auk-monastery-mudon/</guid>
      <description>Kyownpine Pa-Auk Branch Monastery in Mudon, Myanmar. I have moved to Yorgo Sayadaw &amp;rsquo;s new monastery called Kyownpine. The Yorgo Sayadaw read my first ordination transaction 15 years ago and invited me to come. He speaks no English, but we have fun together. Such a lovely place, lots of Metta here. Good views, cool at night (75 degrees), nice kuti. This place is suitable for foreigners to live at complete with proper vinaya (monks&amp;rsquo; rules).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
