<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>anguttara-nikaya on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/anguttara-nikaya/</link>
    <description>Recent content in anguttara-nikaya on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/anguttara-nikaya/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Buddhism and Lists</title>
      <link>/posts/buddhism-and-lists/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/buddhism-and-lists/</guid>
      <description>Buddha by Numbers&#xA;Introduction The Buddhist teachings are often organized by various lists. Various matrices of interlinked lists to organize the teachings are one of the distinctive features of Buddhism. In my studies, I find myself learning many different types of lists for memory. By doing so, I can see the benefit and how they can be expanded and interlinked. While it may seem like dry minutia and uninteresting at first glance, the lists run very deep when you start to understand how the whole system works.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Free PTS Sutta eBooks</title>
      <link>/posts/free-pts-sutta-ebooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/free-pts-sutta-ebooks/</guid>
      <description>The Pali Text Society has made its Vinaya, Sutta and Abhidhamma books available for non-commercial use since 2013. The Sutta books have been extracted from the Buddhadust Website which is still considered as &amp;ldquo;work in progress.&amp;rdquo; However, the work was good enough to reformat as eBooks in its current state.&#xA;Stephen Torrence and myself did most of the work to reformat the web pages into eBook versions. There were thousands of webpages which required many scripts to remove the web content.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
