<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>money on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/money/</link>
    <description>Recent content in money on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/money/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Percentage of Monks Who Do Not Use Money</title>
      <link>/posts/percentage-of-monks-who-do-not-use-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/percentage-of-monks-who-do-not-use-money/</guid>
      <description>Monk walking towards the world of the 5%&#xA;If you are a Westerner and new to Buddhism, you might be surprised to learn that most monks use and handle money. I have calculated that around 95% use money while 5% do not use money. The general consensus of those I have consulted say that about 2 or 3 percent do not use money but I used a 5% number to be safe.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Buddhist Monks Allowed To Use Money?</title>
      <link>/posts/are-buddhist-monks-allowed-to-use-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/are-buddhist-monks-allowed-to-use-money/</guid>
      <description>A Money tree in Laos cc-by-attrib-sa https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Buddhist_money_tree_with_toilet_paper.jpg&#xA;Are Buddhist monks allowed to use money? The short answer is that monks are definitely not allowed to even touch money for all traditions; Theravāda, Mahayāna, and Tibetan. However, it is very common for monks to not only accept money from lay people without shame, but they even encourage lay people to offer the money. Nevertheless, it is still a rule and there are heavy consequences if this becomes a lifetime habit and a wrong mode of livelihood.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chicago Lao Monastery</title>
      <link>/posts/chicago-lao-monastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/chicago-lao-monastery/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I had a chance to go to a Lao Monastery in Elgin, Chicago, IL, USA for 12 days. I usually avoid American Theravada Temples like the plague because most of these places have monks who use money and much of the monk life is centered around collecting money. This is a typical standard not only in America but in most countries. This monastery however, is different.&#xA;In 2015, the committee decided to stop being a useless, unwholesome temple that teaches wrong dhammavinaya (teaching and training &amp;mdash; on wrong ways to give donation and wrong ways to make merit, and obviously wrong kamma and results).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Are Most Monasteries Not Allowable?</title>
      <link>/posts/why-monasteries-not-allowable/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/why-monasteries-not-allowable/</guid>
      <description>Why are most monasteries not allowable for vinaya monks? Today, I was Skyping my parents which is something we do once or twice a month now. I feel it is good for them to &amp;ldquo;see&amp;rdquo; me as a monk, rather than having them talk to me and visualizing their son from 1999. That was when I left home and things changed for me. We had a nice discussion. We spoke about possibilities for a visit, but I told them that finding a place was difficult, because the monks all use money and whatever they buy with that money becomes unallowable.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5, 8 and 10 Precepts</title>
      <link>/posts/5-8-10-precepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/5-8-10-precepts/</guid>
      <description>Here is a comparison of 5, 8 and 10 precepts. The Buddhist who follows five precepts is known as a regular lay Buddhist. The person who follows 8 precepts is known as a serious Buddhist yogi. The person who follows the 10 precepts is known as a novice monk. A bhikkhu follows 227 rules.&#xA;It is important to know these classes to know which rules are more important to follow. It also can explain, what class of rules a monk is following.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
