<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>memory on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/memory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in memory on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/memory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Patimokkha Chant Feb 15, 2022</title>
      <link>/posts/patimokkha-chant-feb-15-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/patimokkha-chant-feb-15-2022/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, I recited the 227 rules of the Pātimokkha for 110 bhikkhus at Pa-Auk Meditation Center in Pyin Oo Lwin. When a monk recites the Pātimokkha, traditionally he does so by memory and not by reading. My recitation was not the best quality, but it was not so bad considering I only started when I was 47, and I have only done this 5 times now. However, the recitations get better and better each time I do it and I hope improvement continues until perfection.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How To Memorize Pāḷi by Rote Method</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-memorize-pa%E1%B8%B7i-by-rote-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/how-to-memorize-pa%E1%B8%B7i-by-rote-method/</guid>
      <description>Title Page&#xA;In America, the Rote Method of learning is belittled as &amp;ldquo;learning like a parrot&amp;rdquo; and rarely or never taught in the Western school systems. However, it is a useful brute force method for memorizing Pali texts and the only way to memorize longer word for word Pāḷi texts such as the Pātimokkha. This system is used extensively in Myanmar schools and Myanmar study monasteries. If you hear lots of noise in the classrooms, rote learning is what they are doing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Memorizing The Noble Eightfold Path</title>
      <link>/posts/memorizing-the-noble-eightfold-path/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/memorizing-the-noble-eightfold-path/</guid>
      <description>I took a small poll among seasoned Buddhists to see who could list all eight factors of The Noble Eightfold Path in English from memory and not many did so well. How can one follow a Path that one does not know? These factors should be said to oneself daily if one truly wishes to walk on the Path. To help with Buddhist literacy, I made a basic video that helps people memorize The Noble Eightfold Path in English.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
