<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>buddha on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/buddha/</link>
    <description>Recent content in buddha on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/buddha/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What Does Namo Tassa Bhagavato Arahato Sammāsambuddhassa Mean?</title>
      <link>/posts/what-does-namo-tassa-bhagavato-arahato-sammasambuddhassa-mean/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/what-does-namo-tassa-bhagavato-arahato-sammasambuddhassa-mean/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: Today we will have a short and brief introduction into the meaning of &amp;ldquo;Namo Tassa Bhagavato Arahato Sammāsambuddhassa&amp;rdquo;. We could easily say it is the most frequently chanted stanza of all Buddhist Pāḷi because this is said before any other type of chant. It is also chanted before every proper Theravāda dhamma talk. We will discuss the word by word meaning and the basic grammar. In short, the phrase means &amp;ldquo;Reverence to the Buddha.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Real Buddha Statues</title>
      <link>/posts/the-real-buddha-statues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/the-real-buddha-statues/</guid>
      <description>What qualities make up the real Buddha Statues? There are certain qualities of a Buddha that makes one instantly recognizable from afar. There are many features that make the Buddha a Buddha besides the iconic drooping earlobes. From time to time, I see statues of the Buddha that are just not right. When you know the correct signs of The Buddha, you immediately know that something is wrong. While you cannot fool a Sri Lankan, you can fool others from all parts of the world.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
