<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>paauk on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/paauk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in paauk on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/paauk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pa-Auk Vaccination 2021</title>
      <link>/posts/pa-auk-vaccination-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/pa-auk-vaccination-2021/</guid>
      <description>Injection on Western resident monk&#xA;Pa-Auk finally vaccinated 2000 of its residents across its branch monasteries with a privately sponsored SinoPharm vaccine. Pa-Auk Pyin Oo Lwin branch had its vaccines delivered on September 18th, 2021 with about half of the total population signed up. Vaccination was voluntary and provided by donors.&#xA;While it did take a long time for us to get the vaccine, the government did invite us for the vaccine back in April or May 2021.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ajahn Brahmavamso&#39;s Dark Jhāna</title>
      <link>/posts/ajahn-brahmavamsos-dark-jhana/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/ajahn-brahmavamsos-dark-jhana/</guid>
      <description>Does Ajahn Brahmavamso Jhāna Have a Nimitta? Ajahn Brahmavamso (&amp;ldquo;Ajahn Brahm&amp;rdquo;) teaches about a samādhi nimitta. However, during jhāna, he says that there is no perception of light. He says that &amp;ldquo;The nimitta is the gateway to jhāna, but not the object of jhāna itself. Pīti or sukha are the objects of jhāna&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;If you follow Ajahn Brahm, this article will help you follow his teachings better. If you follow another method, this article will help you distinguish the difference.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Back in Myanmar Headed to Pa-Auk Meditation Center</title>
      <link>/posts/back-in-myanmar-headed-to-paauk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/back-in-myanmar-headed-to-paauk/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_697&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignleft&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;1920&amp;rdquo;] From the pamc lookout[/caption]&#xA;I am back in Myanmar from Kauai, Hawaii. I will begin the Bus trip to Pa-Auk Meditation Center this morning. What a long transit back that was. Here is a picture taken from Pa-Auk Lookout point that friends and I had fun taking a while back. I will begin the Bus trip to Pa-Auk Meditation Center this morning.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
