<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>love on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/love/</link>
    <description>Recent content in love on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/love/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sabbe Satta -All Beings</title>
      <link>/posts/sabbe-satta-all-beings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/sabbe-satta-all-beings/</guid>
      <description>reposted from https://withmetta.net (2016) . When a Buddhist monk says “sabbe satta,” that is a shorthand for metta practice. “Sabbe satta” means “all beings.”&#xA;One of my friend’s collects the leftover food and cakes and says or acts on this everyday after each meal at the Mudon Pa-Auk monastery. But in reality, even though he says “sabbe satta,” he really just seems to feed the birds with the leftover food and cakes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acapella Inertia MP3 Audio</title>
      <link>/posts/acapella-inertia-mp3-audio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/acapella-inertia-mp3-audio/</guid>
      <description>A’capella Inertia Audio Story (free MP3 download)&#xA;[archiveorg id=acapellainertia]&#xA;I have decided to make an audio version of this story. I started off by having a computer read this for the purpose of proofreading. Then I started reading it out loud. As I read it out loud with my own natural expressions, I thought that it might be better if an audio version were available.&#xA;I happen to have access to a good quality microphone and some professional Linux software running on Elementary OS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Tale of Love and Samādhi Explained:  A&#39;capella Inertia</title>
      <link>/posts/tale-love-acapella-inertia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/tale-love-acapella-inertia/</guid>
      <description>A Tale of Love and Samādhi Explained: A’capella Inertia A little Valentines story for all of you. The topside title is just a description of what the story is generally about. However, the real title of the story is called, “A’capella Inertia.” This is not a short one, but I think you will like this one very much. It has received high marks and it will take about 30 minutes to read.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
