<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>bowl on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</title>
    <link>/tags/bowl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in bowl on American Monk:  Life with Buddha, Dhamma and Saṅgha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/bowl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Buddhist Monk&#39;s Bowl</title>
      <link>/posts/the-buddhist-monks-bowl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/the-buddhist-monks-bowl/</guid>
      <description>Bowl with bowl stand (maybe Pa-Auk)&#xA;There are certain characteristics of the Theravada Buddhist monk&amp;rsquo;s bowl that might be interesting to know, even though the information is quite dry. Enjoy!&#xA;Material: The Buddha has allowed two different types of materials for bowls: iron and clay. When we say iron in Asia, we mean steel. Stainless steel is called steel. Is stainless steel allowed? This metal was not invented yet, but The Buddha left us with the great standards to judge if something should be allowable that was not mentioned during the time of the Buddha.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Blackjack Anniversary</title>
      <link>/posts/my-blackjack-anniversary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/my-blackjack-anniversary/</guid>
      <description>Eating Hall Feb 7 2022&#xA;Today is my 21rst anniversary for when I first got ordained as a monk on February 7th, 2001. As you know there was a hiccup and I ordained twice (back to back) leaving me with an official age of 15 years. However, the total years is 21 and this is my blackjack year when I first got my name.&#xA;There were many reasons why I wanted to ordain as a Buddhist Monk.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is an Overturned Bowl?</title>
      <link>/posts/what-is-an-overturned-bowl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/what-is-an-overturned-bowl/</guid>
      <description>Pa-Auk Bowl Blackening Foundry (not a political picture)&#xA;We have seen many Facebook selfies of politically active monks with their bowls turned upside down. What does this mean and is that proper?&#xA;The answer is: What you see on Facebook is not proper for monks or nuns. What you see on the news with monks and nuns as protesters is not proper. Overturning a bowl is an official Buddhist act, but what you have seen on Facebook and on the news are not official acts of overturning a bowl.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Koral Inspires Me</title>
      <link>/posts/koral-inspires-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/koral-inspires-me/</guid>
      <description>Koral&amp;rsquo;s Family&#xA;Just about every Wednesday, I still find the time to continue with my Kilauea alms round[mfn]map is here[/mfn] (which used to include Tuesdays too). I take a one hour bus ride from Lihue, and then set out on my alms round, wishing loving-kindness to the houses one by one as I walk along the road.&#xA;In the beginning people thought I was some weird homeless person who might be crazy, but after some time, some fearless people spoke to me and then word started spreading.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should Monks Use Mixing Bowls as Monk Bowls?</title>
      <link>/posts/should-monks-use-mixing-bowls-as-monk-bowls/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/should-monks-use-mixing-bowls-as-monk-bowls/</guid>
      <description>On a warm Hawaiian Christmas day in 2018, I was off to collect my alms in the village. I was in a rush and worried that I would not be able to find a ride to the village where I go for alms because so few cars would be on the roads. Luckily, I got a ride and as I stepped out of the the car, I did my usual baggage check.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donation to Sangha or Individuals?</title>
      <link>/posts/donation-sangha-individuals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/donation-sangha-individuals/</guid>
      <description>When should you give to Saṅgha?&#xA;When should you give to individual monks?&#xA;This is a question that is not addressed very often and it can cause lots of trouble for monks knowingly and unknowingly. Quite often, many monks blindly prompt donors to recite a line of pāḷi before they offer anything to them. “Bhikkhu Saṅghassa demi.” There are some variations, but that is the generic formula. It means, “I give to the community of monks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Benefits of Faith Alms</title>
      <link>/posts/faith-alms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/faith-alms/</guid>
      <description>The benefits of “Faith piṇḍapata”. This is a term that I learned either in Abhayagiri, Ca, or Wat Pah Nanachat or both. Probably brought to the West from Ajahn Pasanno who is/was the abbot of both. This means that when you go on alms, you make a determination to only eat the alms food you collect. When you do something like this (and I am not sooo perfect when I follow these things), you can learn a lot about yourself and the real Buddhist teachings.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
